<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TextList>
<TextTemplate>
<name/>
<content/>
<bookmark/>
</TextTemplate>
<TextBean UUID="703b409e51794f038e9c33c27f9891a0">
<name>第一课时</name>
<content>Introduction
ⅰ、Why take BEC exams? 
　　　strong growth
　　　rigorous quality control
　　　wide suitability
　　　wide business context
　　　value for study and business career
　　　international recognition for work and study

ⅱ、What is International Business English? 什么是国际商务英语？
　　国际商务英语，指的是人们从事国际商务活动中所使用的具有行业特征的英语，这些行业包括：国际贸易、国际金融、国际会计、国际运输、国际商法、保险、银行、经济、营销、物流、企业管理、商业服务等。由此看来，商务英语不是一种独立的语言，它仍然是英语，是在国际商务背景下使用的英语。

ⅲ、How to learn International Business English? 怎样学习国际商务英语？
   掌握一定的商务英语词汇、短语和句型。
　　(1) 词汇方面
　　commercial 
　　e.g. The TV show was interrupted by too many commercials.
　　prospect
　　e.g. He called on some prospects but failed to make a sale.
　　make
　　e.g. These products are of Chinese make.
　　The factory manufactured five makes of tractors. 
　　(2) 短语方面
　　soft selling　　 hard selling
　　Some sales people adopt a direct ‘hard sell’ approach, while others use a more indirect ‘soft sell’ approach. 
　　have a bad year
　　The corporation is having a bad year and it will probably be necessary to dismiss a few office staff. 
　　break into/penetrate the market
　　There is chance that we’ll manage to break into the UK market 
　　(3) 句型方面
　　I am writing to you concerning… You can’t miss it. I can’t agree more. It may have slipped your mind, but… You can always reach me at the number… We would very much appreciate it if you could… I noted with interest your advertisement for… Yes, that’s true, but on the other hand… That’s exactly what I think. Maybe, but don’t you think…? You are wanted on the phone. As requested, we enclose for your attention… 
(4) 旧词“新义“
　　honour
　　e.g, All credit cards honoured here. The bank honoured this cheque.
cover
　　e.g. I have got myself covered against fire. 
　　royalty
　　e.g. Besides copyright, the writer got a 10 percent royalty on sales. The technology transfer fee shall be paid in royalties. 
　　(5) 同义词、近义词、相似词的辨析。
　　1) chairman, president, CEO, Managing Director, General Manager.
　　2) dealer, merchant, trader, businessman, distributor. 
　　3) deputy, vice-, associate, assistant. 
　　4) discharge, unload, land
　　5) discount, reduction, rebate, allowance. 
　　* 熟悉世界贸易组织。
　　* 熟悉国际商务英语有关行业的基本术语及其内涵意义。
　　* 学习国际商务常识，略知相关专业知识。
　　* 密切了解国际商务最新动态。

ⅳ、BEC2 Content
    BEC2考试主要是考学生的语言能力，包括听、说、读、写四个方面。试卷所设计的语言文字基本山都与商务有关。另外，还考学生的英语语法、结构等内容。
　　BEC2考试分笔试和口试两大部分。笔试包括阅读、写作和听力。

ⅴ、BEC2 Time
.	Preliminary 	Vantage	Advanced
Reading	1 hr 30 mins ﹡	1 hr	1 hr
Writing		45 mins	1 hr 10 mins
Listening	40 mins	40 mins	40 mins
Speaking
( 2 candidates)	12 mins ﹡﹡	14 mins ﹡﹡ 	16 mins ﹡﹡

ⅵ、BEC2 Grades
　　* one overall grade 
　　* each skill counts for 25% 
　　* candidates also receive profile of performance
　　* Preliminary: two pass grades
　　* Vantage and Advance: three pass grades

ⅶ、Introduction to BP Preparation Resource
　　* vocabulary 
　　* textbook 
《Pass Cambridge Vantage》
Teamwork, Entertaining a client, Brand power, New premises, Health and safety, Business travel, Marketing disasters, Going global是BV常考的商务专题。下面以Brand power举例说明：
1．	掌握商务词汇短语
E.g. to buy/develop/launch/sell/test/own/stretch/damage a brand
E.g. brand image/leader/loyalty/name/power/stretching
2．	掌握相关商务知识
E.g. Explain why you brought one of the products. 
strong sense of brand loyalty 
reasonable price 
good after-sales service 
reliability of the product 
good and consistent quality 
user-friendly design 
good value for money 
in style 
3．	掌握相关背景知识
Tesco, J Sainsbury, Asda
《Working in English》
　　       * mock exam papers: 9 sets

ⅷ、Register for BV   www.neea.edu.cn

ⅸ、Business Research
Answering business studies question 
Business Studies is a skills based subject which tests students’ ability to use their knowledge. There are four basic skills: 
Level One         Description/Identification
Level Two　　     Explanation
Level Three 　  　Analysis
Level Four 　   　Evaluation
To gain the highest grades, candidates must show evidence of the higher skills 

Key types of questions 　　 　　 　　 　　 　　  Responses should:
Identify/state/describe.. 　　 　　 　　 　　 　　  make a point
Explain/outline… 　　 　　 　 　　 　　 　　   make a point and develop it
Discuss… 　　 　　 　 　　 　　 　　 　　 　　present two sides of the debate
Examine/assess/analyse.. 　　 　　 　　 　　 　　 make a point and develop fully with some question of it
Critically assess/to what extent… 　　 　　 　　    explain both sides and evaluate

How to answer questions
Example question: 
What determines the price of a product? 
Example answer:
● The price of a product is influenced by the costs. 1 
● This is because firms have to charge a price which is greater than costs to make a profit. 2 
● However in the short run a firm may sell a product at a loss. This may be to gain market share or because the product is still at the introduction phase and has high research and launch costs. 3
● Overall it depends on whether we are considering a short or long term pricing policy. Firms may be willing to make a loss in the short run. It will also depend on the objectives of the firm. Some public sector organisations, e.g. may simply try to cover costs.
 
　　Example 
　　Question: Should firms train their employees?
　　Answer:
　　By training their employees firms may be able to increase their profits BECAUSE trained staff are likely to be more productive and make les mistakes. Employees might also be more motivated BECAUSE they might be able to undertake more interesting work and BECAUSE managers are showing that they value their staff (which can satisfy their esteem needs). HOWEVER training costs money and is not always successful. It can also lead to a loss of production while staff are being trained. OVERALL, management will have to weigh up the potential benefits against the costs. If, for example, the firm has the necessary resources, the training is relatively cheap and is likely to lead to significant increases in productivity and profitability the firm likely to invest in it. If, ON THE OTHER HAND, the firm lacks the necessary finance and staff already have the skills required then training is LESS LIKELY.
</content>
<bookmark>186</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="465c813a7706492693b92617a48da610">
<name>第二课时</name>
<content>第一讲
Ⅰ Introduction to BV Speaking
   format       conversation       presentation       discussion
   criteria    pronunciation    vocabulary &amp; grammar    discourse management     interactive communication
   examiner      interlocutor       assessor       Cambridge examiner

Ⅱ Presentation Example
PART 2: Mini-presentation
A: WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
   Selecting applicants for a job
	Working experience
	Personal qualities
   
Sample 1
   I choose topic A-what is important when selecting applicants for a job. As to this topic, as far as I am concerned, there are 3 things to consider.
   First, I think working experience is very important when selecting applicants. Applicants who have already had the work experience in the relevant fields will learn the new job easier and quicker. And it will also save the company a lot of training fees if the applicant has related experience.
   Second, we must consider the personal qualities of the applicants, such as personality and health. Companies tend to employ people whose character fits a special job. For example, consulting company tends to employ applicant who is analytical and knowledgeable, but advertising agents like their employees to be energetic and creative.
   Third, I believe language is of great importance when selecting applicants. Nowadays, we do business with people from all over the world. Always we buy goods from Africa, and sell our electronic product to Europe; a foreign language especially English is needed if the company wants to expand to the world. Applicants who can speak one or more foreign languages will have a better chance to get the job.

Sample 2
As we all know, the criteria used by HR professionals in screening and selecting applicants normally include such factors as working experience, personal qualities and communicative skills.
Firstly, we pay a lot of attention to working experience of the applicant. A person with a solid record of related experience is more likely to fit in with a new company. Therefore he or she can be trusted to fulfill the tasks and solve the problems in a more professional and competent way.
    In addition to this, we also look at the personal qualities of the applicant. Does he or she has integrity, perseverance or ‘can do’ spirit? Surely any organization can benefit from the reliability, devotion and enthusiam of its employees.
Finally, good communicative skills such as interpersonal skills and team spirit are also becoming an important precondition in selecting qualified employees.

B: WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
   Preparing for a job interview
	Studying the job advertisement
	Finding out about the company
Before you go for an interview, you must make preparations so as to face the interviewer with more confidence. They include studying the job advertisement, finding out about the company, preparing yourself psychologically, etc.
Firstly, you should study the job advertisement carefully so that you can match your knowledge, skills and abilities with the specifications required for the post. You must assure the interviewer that you have all the qualifications required, so you are the right sort of person they are looking for.
Secondly, you should know more about the company, such as its profile, structure, existing problems, requirements, campaigns and future plans. As a Chinese saying goes: “know the opponent and know yourself, and you can fight a hundred battles without defeat.”
Finally, you should also prepare yourself psychologically and this will help you combat stress. Rehearsing the interview with your friends, for example, is a good relaxation exercise that can install confidence in you.

Ⅲ Presentation Discourse Management
1.	Opening Sentence
Well, I’d like to make a short/brief/mini/one-minute presentation on the topic…
2.	Body （一般讲2-3个要点，根据语速和知识点调整）
First,…Second….Third,…
3.	Closing Sentence
Anyway, that’s why I think so.              Thank you very much.
Thank you for taking your time.             Thank you for listening.
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="b6c4db8f55ae45c58623be267439b98a">
<name>第三课时</name>
<content>第二讲
Ⅰ Conversation
PART 1: Exchange personal information
This part aims to prepare the candidate for phase 1 of the speaking test, which takes the form of an interview, with each candidate talking in turn to the examiner. This involves the candidate answering questions, responding to a comment or participating in an exchange or greeting.

Activity 1:
Asking each other’s name (including spelling), hometown, occupation, hobbies
Further probing: describe your hometown (location, city, town, village) climate, population, etc.
Further probing: describe your occupation/ or major (if student), likes and dislikes about your occupation.
Further probing: asking each other about marital status/ with or without boy friend/girlfriend.
Asking for opinion on married/single life, which is better?
Further probing: asking each other about hobbies.
Possible Questions	Suggested Answers and Note
1)	What’s your registration number?		My registration number is…
2)	What’s your name?
How do you spell your name?
How do you spell your family name / surname / last name?		My last name is…
	My given name is…, but my friends always call me…, my English name.
	You can call me…, if you like / wish.
	nickname
3)	Where are you from?
Would you say it’s a good place to live in?
(Why?)

Do you like living in…?
Where would you like rather live…or…?
(Why?)
Do you think it would be better to live in…or…? (Why?)
		Weather
	Transportation
	Environment
	Housing
Houses are pricey in this area.
	Night life (exciting, dynamic)
	Local people
	Local government
	Job opportunities
	Resorts (skiing)
	Atmosphere
	selling points

Possible Questions	Suggested Answers and Note
4)	Do you come from a large family or a small family?
Can you tell me a bit about…in your family?		Extended family 
	Nuclear family
5)	Do you work or are you a student in…?
What do you do?
What do you study?
What’s your major?
What do you like most about your job?
(Why?)
What do you like most about your studies?
(Why?)		Major v.
I majored in… , and minored in…
	Ever since I was a child, I was interested in…
	Job Satisfaction
	Interesting &amp; challenging
Traveling opportunity
Training (career development)
Financial benefits
Free Time

Do you have much free time?

How do you spend your free time?

What do you do in your free time?

What’s your hobby?

Why do you like…?

Is there any particular reason why you enjoy…?

When did you first take up / start…
(Why did you start then?)
		Particular reason
	Cultivate a hobby 
	It’s never too late to take a hobby.  ---Churchill
	Outdoor activities:
Sports: tennis / golf / baseball / attend the gym / fitness center
	Work out=exercise
	Recharge the battery: 
Attend a training course
Read various books, for example…
	Chat online 
Watch TV
(passive viewer) TV=one-eyed monster
ads (advertisement advert)
	Commercial 
	Teleplay 
	Educational programs
	Amusement programs
	Music: classical / light/ pop / jazz / blues folk
	Fine arts  Abstract painting / oil painting
	I am fond of traveling. Traveling is a good way of learning and a good way of communicating with other people.
	No, I don’t have much free time, because so many wonderful courses are fixed.
	I prefer doing exercises, (most of time) I’d like to attend the gym or go to the fitness centers. If time is enough, I’ll read various books.
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="7ad2b1fe227647d88a703f169cb115e2">
<name>第四课时</name>
<content>第三讲
Ⅰ Tongue Twister
1.	Good cookies could be cooked by good cook if a good cook could cook good cookies.
2.	If you understand, say understand.
   If you don’t understand, say don’t understand. 
   If you understand say you don’t understand. 
   How can I understand you understand.
   Understand?
3.	Peter Pipe picked a peck of pickled peppers prepared by his parents and put them on a large paper plate.

Ⅱ Conversation
Possible Topics &amp; Questions	Suggested Answers and Note
Transport
How did you come here today?
How did you travel to the test?
Did you come here by bus?

If you could travel by any form of transport you want, what would you choose? (Why?)
Which form of transport would you like to travel by?

How do you think you will travel to work in 15 years’ time?
How do you think you will travel to work 15 years from now?	
	Bus / taxi / cab / private car / subway / 
Tube underground / tram


time / safety / money



	light way / subway / airport
	It would be fast developing in 15 years time and will cover everywhere in Beijing. It will be really convenient.
Hotels
What kind of accommodation do you usually stay in when you go on holiday?

Do you stay in a hotel or an apartment you are on holiday?



What kinds of facilities do you think hotels ought to provide for business people? (Why?)





Do you think companies should pay for their staff to stay in expensive hotels on business trips? (Why? / Why not?)


Should people stay in expensive hotels on business trips? (Why? / Why not?)	
	hotel/motel/villa/apartment/flat(BrE)/dorm
	city breaks, beach holidays
sun-tanned / fast-tanned center
	camping  camp or tent
	Hitchhiking, hitchhiker (take a gap year)
	Domestic travel
	Sight seeing 
	Hi-tech, Local Area Net, internet, database system, fax
	Well equipped conference room,
sound-proof
multi-function hall 
video-conferencing, tele-conferencing

	It depends (on the different circumstances).
If you fix a deal which is worth $1000000, in that case, your company will pay for you to live…
If you go there for only $2, it’s impossible.

Possible Topics &amp; Questions	Suggested Answers and Note
Job
What kind of job would you like to do most?
(Why?)
What would your ideal job be?
What kind of job do you like?
Should companies offer training to staff?
(Why? / Why not?)
Do you think companies should provide training for staff?

Would you like to work abroad?
(Why? / Why not?)
Is the opportunity to work in another country important to you?	
Job title
Job responsibility
Job satisfaction

	trainingproductivityprofitmotivation
But: trainingcost money, time, staff
opportunity cost
internal conflict
	broaden one’s horizon, experience
	…is quite an experience to me. 
	…is a real eye-opener
	culture messenger
Training Course
What kind of training course have you ever taken?
Have you ever taken any training course?

What do you think is most important when you choose a training course? (Why?)







What do you usually expect from a training course?	
NewOriental School BEC online training course

Computer skill training course

Location
Transportation
Duration of course
Cost
Flexibility of trainer
Topics covered
Materials
Follow up advice

High expectancy
Life expectancy

Possible Topics &amp; Questions	Suggested Answers and Note
Future Plan
What would you like to do after you finish your studies? (Why?)

What are you doing now for the preparation of your future plan?

What if you failed to find a job as a…?

What would you do if you couldn’t find a job as a…?	
	go abroad, look for a job, hunt for a job, study further, post graduate
	knowledge preparation: attend training course
	psychological preparation: be mature
improve interpersonal skills

	It is not quite possible.
	If you don’t want me, there are several other companies waiting for me, actually I’ve got several offers.

	Can you do it?
AmE: Yes, definitely is a piece of cake.
BrE: I’m sure I can do it.
Teamwork
What kind of people do you most like working /studying with? (Why?)

What do you think makes a good team?
What is a good team?

Do you think you work in a good team?
(Why? / Why not?)	
	Honest and have good interpersonal skills


	Cooperation and friendly atmosphere
	Mutual trust


Ⅲ Conversation Topics
Asking about personal views.
1.	Why do you study English?
2.	Why do you want to study business?
3.	What do you think of some modern methods of payment (credit cards, cheques, bank transfers)?
4.	What role does the computer play in modern business?
5.	What are some necessary steps for preparing a business trip overseas?
6.	Which kind of office would you prefer to work in, cellular or an open-plan office?
7.	What do you think of international trade?
8.	How to deal with customer enquires on the phone?
9.	Transportation: (What is your usual means of transportation? Compare the various means of transportation)
10.	Health and safety in the workplace (How to ensure a healthy working environment for employees? What are some health hazards in the office/factory shop? What safety measures should be adopted in the workplace?)
11.	How to keep a balance between growth and environment protection?
12.	Radio and TV (What are your favorite/TV programs? Why?)
13.	What kind of role does advertising play in promoting your products/services? Which form of advertising is most effective in your opinion?
14.	What are the required qualities of a modern manager?
15.	What do you know about flexible time?
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="56333428fd8546abb6e8e9a810ee255d">
<name>第五课时</name>
<content>第四讲
Ⅰ Life English   Talking about money
 
1．
If you have money, you can easily make money.
Money makes money.
Money begets money.
If you are in debt, you lose your self-respect.
You lose your motivation.
Your debt continues to grow.
You start to worry.
You need to borrow more money.
You get even deeper in debt.
2.
Money comes. 
Money goes.
But the memory is always there.

Money talks.
Money rules.
Money is power.
3.
Money burns a hole in your pocket.
It goes out as fast as it comes in.
You’re a spendthrift.
Don’t squander your hard-earned money.
Put your savings in the bank.
Never live beyond your means.
Be a good consumer.
Be a smart shopper.
Be a clever buyer. 
 
Ⅱ Presentation Topics
Team Work  

WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
MANAGING A PROJECT
	ENCOURAGING TEAMWORK 
	KEEPING TO SCHEDULE 

WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
CHOOSING PEOPLE TO WORK IN TEAMS
	VARIETY OF EXPERIENCE
	PERSONAL QUALITIES

Key point: improve working efficiency. This plays a crucial role in the commercial practice in Western world.

Explain the importance of team work:
a.	Teamwork reflects the combined experiences, knowledge, intelligence and views of a group of people, so it will definitely improve the quality and efficiency of the work.
b.	If the participants worked together, it would be easy for them to come up with creative ideas. This is particularly valuable for a relatively complex work, for the people working in a team, if one of them gets stuck on a matter, others/the rest could chip in their ideas and get the problem sorted. But if you work on your own, for instance, you are the sole manager in the department.
c.	If people did not work as a team, everyone would have to wait for the decisions made by the manager and it was not easy to get people to take on responsibility for anything.
d.	A huge and complicated project is not possible to be completed/done by merely one person. For instance, 3 Gorges project-a huge amount of money, 30 million people have to emigrate to elsewhere, a lot of commercial contracts
e.	You will get bored quickly if you work on you own. But if you work in a team…
f.	Working in a team can increase personal awareness of abilities and complementary skills in colleague.

How to improve teamwork:
General ideas; friendly atmosphere; not bossy; patient; good manners; modest; leadership; good interpersonal skills; variety of experience

a.	Variety of experience and a broad horizon would help to tackle urgent matters and establish his or her personal prestige. Well-experienced staff are capable of overcoming storms and crises.
b.	On coming across problematic issues, new or inexperienced staff usually will feel depressed and even start to panic. One or a number of experienced staff will, in this kind of situation, automatically become the spiritual leaders of the team and can get the issues in question solved quickly. 
c.	A wide range of experiences are important to a team member, because you never know what kind of problems might suddenly come up to you. Experiences in different fields will enhance the chance of successfully sorting out the problem with your knowledge which is based on your past experience.

Personal qualities:
a.	The basis of the team work is mutual trust and friendly atmosphere
b.	Good manners, not too bossy, patient, modest, leadership, good interpersonal skills.


Project Management  
WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
MANAGING A PROJECT
	ENCOURAGING TEAMWORK 
	KEEPING TO SCHEDULE
Key points: Team work, time pressure (keeping to the schedule)
Team work: as explained in the teamwork section

Time pressure:
a.	A well-designed schedule can clarify yourself to the project. You should ensure that you would be running before the schedule rather than after it. 
b.	Time is always of essence for a project.
c.	Failure to keep to the schedule will result in/cause late completion.
d.	Late completion will lead to: civil litigation, injured party will become entitled to claim compensation/entitled to sue the breaching company.
e.	When the project is being processed/in the course of carrying out the project, there will be a lot of commercial activities involved. Such as investment banks advance cash; raw material supply, planning permission, sub-contract/outsource. Failure to stick to the schedule will affect above matters.

Competition 
WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
DEALING WITH COMPETITION
	PRICING POLICIES
	ADVERTISING STRATEGIES

WHAT IS IMORTANT WHEN…?
SETTING PRICES FOR NEW PRODUCTS
	PRODUCTION COSTS
	COMPETIORS’ PRICES

Key points: Pricing; Advertising; Production costs; Competitor’s price; Marketing; a wide range of services and products

Pricing:
a.	(For a consumer): all consumers would like to go for higher quality and less expensive products. It is a common sense.
b.	(For a manager): correct pricing policies can capture a large number of consumers in a short period of time.
c.	For a newly established company: correct pricing policies are particularly important for newly established businesses. The major task for them at the early stage is to draw the public attention and make their company and their brand known to the public. When a new product is put into market, there may be very few people knowing/who know about it…(e.g.Thai curry source)
Competitors’ price:
a.	Once a new product is put into market, it will immediately face the competition from rivals. The price war sometimes can be incredibly fierce and crude.
b.	Competitors’ price will mirror the consumers’ attitude about certain products and the satisfaction about their prices.
c.	If you fixed the price higher than your rivals without higher quality of service, you might soon find yourself in an unfavorable situation.
d.	Correct pricing policies could also defeat some competitors in a short period of time. For example: Safeway, Tesco price war against all small bread manufactures. In this case, Safeway and Tesco fixed their price for 7p per loaf, which is 23p cheaper than their competitors’ offer. As a result of this, in 35 days time, most of their competitors went into liquidation.

Advertising strategies:
a.	The fundamental task for a company is to make its products and itself known to the public. There are many ways to achieve this, advertising is the most important one. 
b.	Advertising through different media can cover nearly every corner in the world. The main channels are:
		-TV
		-Radio
		-Internet
		-Newspaper
		-Bill Board
		-Poster
		-Magazine
c.	The advantage/point of advertising is not only about propagandizing your company but also competing against/with your rivals. A company, through proper advertisements, can manage to introduce the advantages of their products comparing to their rivals’, and therefore convince the consumers that their products would be the right choice. For instance, Car manufactures can put in their new designs to the ads, e.g. ABS, double airbags to convince the prospective customers that their cars are safer than others.
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="65dc7ee1ef9b48b3bbf0cf6b278077ec">
<name>第六课时</name>
<content>第五讲
Ⅰ Life English
Talking about time
 
1.
How are we doing for time?
Do we have time for that?
How much time do we have left?
    Are we on schedule?
Do we have time?
Are we making good time?
2.
Times flies by too quickly.
Time passes by too swiftly.
Time waits for no man.

Enjoy life while you’re still young.
Don’t miss any opportunity.
Don’t pass up any good chances.
3.
Time is important.
Time is valuable.
Time is precious.
Do as much as you can every day.
Take every opportunity and chance given to you.
Don’t waste any time.
 

Ⅱ Presentation Topics
Motivating staff 
   WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
   MOTIVATING STAFF
	FINANCIAL BENEFITS
	CAREER DEVELOPMENT OPPORTUNITIES

WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…? 
INTRODUCING A REWARD SYSTEM FOR STAFF
	PURPOSE OF THE REWARD SYSTEM
	TYPES OF REWARD OFFERED
WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
AIMING TO REDUCE STAFF TURNOVER
	FINANCIAL INCENTIVES
	CAREER STRUCTURE

Key points: Financial benefits; Career development/structure; reduce staff turnover
Financial Benefits:
a.	Managers, company owners and supervisors have always been frustrated and bewildered by employees with little or no motivation.
b.	Staff always want reward for their contribution to the company and what they are worth. Such factors are just like market forces. The fundamental reason of looking for a job is to get pay. Staff do the job what they are paid for. However, quite often, the staff work overtime under their managers’ demand. If the company fails to give proper financial benefits staff might subsequently feel not being fairly treated, and therefore frustrate their enthusiasm for their work. 
c.	Staff want some sort of recognition for the job that they do. Correct financial benefits plan will arouse their enthusiasm; otherwise they would feel being ignored. 
d.	The job that the staff are doing is not always interesting, or the working environment may not be pleasant, or their colleagues might not be very helpful and cooperative. In this kind of situation/under the kind of circumstance, the staff would become stressful and uninterested in their job. Correct financial benefits can normally distract staff from their dissatisfaction with….

Career development/structure:
a.	Job-hunting is always a two-way process. On one hand, the employees look for their ideal jobs, on the other hand the employer, at the same time, look for competitive people. An employer has a number of methods to attract the best people into its business. Such as high pay, traveling opportunities, company cars and training/career development opportunities.
b.	Good educational background is not the only element that the future employers will take into account when they look for someone in the job market. Postgraduate qualifications and professional trainings are equally or even more important than the higher education degrees. When the HR managers only have 30 seconds to go through each applicant’s CV, the sector that will catch their eyes are normally your qualification and professional training experiences, which show whether you suit their vacant positions.
c.	Nowadays, very few people would like to go for that kind of job-for-life posts. They all wish to have their jobs better and better. If an employee is able to get the opportunities to obtain some sort of professional training during the course of employment, this experience will definitely enhance his value in the employment market and therefore benefits his future job-hunting.
d.	So in the two-way job-seeking process, while the employer is choosing its favorite people, the wise future employee will consider the training and career development opportunities with his/her future employer and try to make himself/herself more competitive in the employment market.

Ⅲ Business Dialogue
1) Negotiating a Job Offer 
Employer:		 would you consider an offer of $56,000 per year?
Ms. Wilson:	 What kind of benefits are talking about?
Employer:	Our standard package includes health insurance, two weeks vacation and a company car.	
Ms. Wilson:	Are these things negotiable?         Employer:	Uh…not normally. What do you have in mind ?
Ms. Wilson:	Vacation time is important to me. I would be willing to give up these other items in order to receive more vacation days. 
Employer:	What an interesting idea, Ms. Wilson. Would you also be willing to accept a cut in initial salary?
Ms. Wilson:	possibly. What do you have in mind ?
2)  Employee Pay Raise  
Boss:	You have done an excellent job this year and we are pleased with the results.
Employee:	I am glad that you have been happy with my performance. 
Boss:	As a result of your performance, we happy to offer you the position of manager.
Employee:	Does this title come with an increase in salary?
Boss: 	Yes, it does.
Employee:	Can you give me the specifics?
Boss:	Your monthly gross salary will increase by $500.
Employee:	That sounds fair.

3）  Asking for a Raise 
Mr. White:	So, tell me: what makes you think we should give you a raise?
Miss Small:	I’ve got several good reasons. I’ve been here several years, my work has proven to be good, and I’ve noticed that people in comparable jobs get paid more than I do.
Mr. White:	Salaries are confidential; how do you know how much money these “other people” make?
Miss Small:	Well, I’ve noticed all the new cars around here, for one thing.
Mr. White:	Those are company cars provided to the sales staff for their business trips. Also, some employees receive sales commissions. So good salesmen will naturally earn more.
Miss Small:	That’s understandable. Well, rather than comparing my salary with someone else’s, perhaps we could talk about my job performance. Surely you’ve noticed the extra hours I’ve put in recently? If I were being paid an hourly wage, with the standard time – and – a – half for overtime, I’d be earning much more.
Mr. White:	I see you point. However, it might be hard to get a raise approved. Profits were down last quarter, and the whole company is tightening its belt, so anything that affects the annual budget is hard to get approved. But I’ll tell you what I’ll do. I’ll give you a one – time bonus for your recent hard work. And I’ll try to arrange some sort of compensation for any future overtime.
Miss Small:	That would be very good of you, Mr. White.

4）	Asking for a Raise 
Martin:	Mr. Smith, I have been doing some industry research and was shocked to learn that the average salary for a position that is similar to mine pays, on average $2,000 more per year than I am currently making.
Mr. Smith:	What are you basing this information on?
Martin:	First and secondary research. I hope that you can address this concern immediately as I find it very disturbing.
Mr. Smith:	Yes, I will. We are very happy with performance and want to continue our good working relationship.
Martin:	I wish the same. As such, I hope you will seriously consider a pay increase.
Mr. Smith:	Let me take this up with the Director and get back to you immediately.

Ⅳ Conversation Notes
注意：
1．	考试中不要说 “Pardon?”
2．	Never say “sorry” in examination!
3．	没听清可用以下说法
I don’t quite understand you. Would you explain it a little bit for me?
I am not sure what you are getting at. Would you express it in another way?
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="d17ac5f146ac4b78a0239db1d7eb7952">
<name>第七课时</name>
<content>第六讲
Ⅰ Life English
   eating
 
1．
I am hungry.
I’m hungry as hell.
I’m hungry as a wolf.

I’m starving.
I’m starved.
I feel like I’m starving to death.
My stomach is empty.
My stomach is growling.
I could eat like a horse.
2.
I’m really hungry.
I’m feeling weaker by the moment.
I need to eat something nutritious.
3.
Let’s eat.
Let’s dig in.
Let’s pig out.
Let’s mounch out.
Let’s chow down.
Let’s indulge ourselves.
4.
It’s delicious.
It tastes great.
It’s out of this world.
This meal is fit for a king.
This meal was made in heaven.
I couldn’t ask for a better meal.
5.
I’m full.
I’m stuffed.
I can’t eat another bite.
I ate too much.
I need to take a rest.
I need to take it easy.
 

  Invite sb. to dinner
 
1.
It’s on me.
It’s my treat.
Be my guest.
Let me pay the bill.
Let me foot the bill.
Let me pick up the check.
2.
Pick your position.
Select what you like.
Choose whatever you wish.
It’s your choice.
It doesn’t really matter to me.
I don’t have any preference.
3.
Can I get you something?
Do you need anything?
What would you like?

Are you hungry now, or would you like to eat later?
I’d like to invite you out to dinner.
Do you have any preference?
4.
I’m easy to satisfy.				
I’m easy to please.
I have simple tastes.
I don’t need any fancy food.
I don’t need anything special.
McDonald’s would do me fine, if it’s OK with you.
5.
What do you recommend?
What do you suggest?
What do you think is best?
What’s good today?
What’s your most popular dish?
What’s this place famous for?
 

Ⅱ Presentation Topics
Business Premises 
WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
RELOCATION A BUSINESS
	LOCAL WORKFORCE AVAILABLE 
	LOCATION OF SITE

WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
CHOOSING RETAIL PREMISES TO RENT
	LOCATION
	LENGTH OF CONTRACT


Key points: location of the premises; local workforce; rent a premises
Local workforce:
a.	Might technology support and skilful workforce are the two crucial elements leading a modern enterprises to success. So when locating a business, the management people in the business got to consider local workforce.
b.	Skilful workers are just like the hands of a business, they are the direct creators of company’s profits. 
c.	The diversity of the workforce’s skills will diversify the quality of the products. (Swiss watch, Volkswagen cars)
d.	Skilful workforce is particularly important to hi-tech oriented companies. The hi-tech products require the company to maintain a strong research and development team, which are normally the more valuable assets of the company.
e.	When locating a business, the managers need to consider whether the local workforce is capable of producing such a strong R&amp;D team. 
f.	Moreover, cheap local force will certainly reduce the production costs. (Consider why many foreign companies choose China as their manufacturing base)

Location of the business site:
Consider the following issues:
a.	Whether it is convenient and easy for raw material supply and transporting out the products.
b.	Whether it is easy to get access to the electricity, water, gas and other supporting energy supplies.
c.	Whether it is convenient for most of staff to go to work
d.	The property price there
e.	Environmental issues
f.	Planning permission
g.	Tax liabilities

The length of the contract:
a. Longer contract would cover issues in more details. The contract should cover certain matter, which are likely to incur, such as assignment, service charges, and rent review clause.

Marketing

WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
AIMING TO REACH NEW MARKETS
	MARKET RESEARCH 
	ADVERTISING

WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
ADVERTISING A NEW PRODUCT
	TARGET MARKETS
	CHOICE OF MEDIA

Market research: 
a.	Marketing is the performance of business activities that direct the flow of goods and services from producer to consumer or user. 
b.	Marketing research is always the first step before the company gets into the market. 
c.	The fundamental goal of marketing is the satisfaction of consumer needs. No organization can survive for long without meeting consumer needs. People will simply not purchase a product or service that they do not need. 
d.	Thus, any organization, if it is to be successful, must proceed from the goal of customer satisfaction and adjust its programs to deliver an offering meeting consumers’ needs. 
e.	E.g. foreign medium and high range car manufacturers did not attempt to enter into the Chinese market until recent years, because following market researches, they discovered that Chinese consumers, in general, could not afford to buy and maintain expensive cars. … 
f.	E.g. Pizza, Pasta…
g.	Talking about Market Research
	The company has done a lot of market research for the product.
	Can you tell me how a company starts selling a new product?
	Do you often carry out/conduct market research?
	What’s objective of market research?
	One of the purpose of market research is to find out whether there’s a market for the product.
	We did a detailed market analysis.
	Market research is actually an analysis of a specific market for a particular product.
	We have to run the market test for two months.
	We have a wide product range.
	The stock market is uncertain at the moment because interest rates are falling.

Advertising:
a.	Advertising is the most useful way to propagandize a company’s products and make them known to the public. Advertising is also the way to get the products orientated. (E.g. whether the products are for female/male market, high earning people or low earning people. Sports shoes… perfume)
b.	When advertising a new product, it is essential to consider the target markets. Consumers’ needs in the target market.
c.	Choice of media: see Advertising Strategies.

Ⅲ Business Dialogue
1)	Market Potential  
Andy:  Thank you for your interest in representing our product.
Janet:   I have heard many excellent things about your company and have experienced first – hand the
capabilities of your computers. 
Andy:   What are your initial thoughts of our computers in China? Is there a market?
Janet:    I am very optimistic about the market opportunities in China.
Andy:   We agree. Based on our initial market research the findings are very positive.
Janet:   I am not surprised. Having been a player in the computer industry in China for the last decade, I have witnessed
firsthand its Phenomenal growth.

2)   Target Market 
Michael: Our target market is large corporations and government agencies. They have the most need for our computers.
Ann:    I have extensive government contacts and rich experience working for Fortune 500 companies.
Michael:  I see from your resume you tell us about your experiences with these companies in China?
Ann:     I have held numerous management positions and been responsible for nationwide sales for IBM.
Michael:  Can you elaborate on your sales experience?
Ann:     I was responsible for building a sales team from 10 to over 150. Sales during my tenure increased 150%.
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="b7d45a46705e4daa9698f26f9dbd067a">
<name>第八课时</name>
<content>第七讲
Ⅰ Life English
 
 1
I owe you.
I owe you one.
I owe you a big favor.


I appreciate it.
I’m much obliged.
I’m indebted to you.

2.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I can’t thank you enough.
I’m grateful.
I’m really grateful.
I’m more than grateful.
3.
I’m really sorry.
I’m extremely sorry.
I apologize from the bottom of my heart.


It’s my mistake.
It shouldn’t have happened.
I won’t let it happen again.
4.
Don’t take me seriously.
Don’t believe what I say.
I’m just talking nonsense.
I’m just making a joke.
I’m trying to be funny.
I only want to amuse you.
I’m kidding you.
I’m teasing you.
I’m just joking with you. 
Ⅱ Presentation Topics
Trade Fair

WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
EXHIBITING AT TRADE FAIR
	QUALITY OF DISPLAY
	STAFF SELECTED

Key issues: Quality of display in trade fairs; Staff selected for trade fairs; 
Quality of display in trade fairs:
a.	The quality of display will affect the public image of the company.
b.	Trade fairs are the irreplaceable means of propagandizing products. They provide the manufacturers with the formal stages to display their products. 
c.	A trade fair is an important link and activity in commercial sale. Before a trade fair takes place, there normal are a lot of propagandas about it, and the organizer always tries to attract as many customers as possible to attend the trade fair. 
d.	Consequently, a trade fair will have massive influence on the public and market. And most of visitors to a trade fair will be the genuine buyers or at least would like to take interests in the companies and the products on the trade fair. And therefore a high quality of display in a trade fair would be the best opportunity for an ambitious company to promote its newest products and built up its good image. 

Ⅲ Presentation Functional Sentences
（一）总起句
    The present talk aims to decide…
    The purpose of this talk is to answer the question of …
    In brief, this talk sets out to solve the problem of …
    There are currently three possible solutions to …

（二）分论点
    Firstly,…； Secondly,…； Thirdly，…
In addition, …
Furthermore, …
As … is concerned, … 
    As for …，… 
    On one hand, …；On the other hand，…
（三）小结句
    From the above information, it can be shown that …
    Based on the study, it is clear that …
    Before we close, let me just summarize the main points.
    Shall I just go over the main points?
    So, to sum up,…
In conclusion,…
In general, …
    On the whole,…
    Overall,…

（四）常用连词
1．解释性：
in other words，that/which means，namely，that is to say
2．进一步阐释性：
in particular，especially，notably，chiefly
3．对照、转折性：
but, though, even though, while, whereas
despite, in spite of
yet, however, nevertheless, still, but, even so
all the same，in contrast
4．原因、结果：
lead to, result in, bring about, give rise to, account for, be responsible for, followed by effect
rise, stem from, be attributable to, cause
because, as, since，because of, due to, owing to, on account of, as a result/consequence of
therefore, so, accordingly, consequently, hence, thus, that’s the reason why

（五）常用口头衔接语
Well, it seems to me that …
That’s true, but on the other hand …
I couldn’t have put it better myself.
That’s just what/all I was thinking.
There’s something in that, I suppose.
That’s exactly my opinion.
Well, the point I’m trying to make is that …
Well, what I am trying to say is that …
That’s how I feel.
That’s just how I see it.

（六）常用词汇
1．动词：to clarify, to explain, to interpret, to put sth. another way, to recap on sth.
2．名词：a summary, a decision, a report, an outcome, a write-up, a recommendation

Ⅳ Presentation Q&amp;A
WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…
DEVELOPING AN ADVERTISING PROGRAM?
	OBJECTIVE
	BUDGET
Outline
—three steps  carefully planned in advance

                   —inform
——objective       —persuade
                   —remind

                   —how much,  spend
——budget         —control cost
                  —within

                  —TV, radio, newspaper, magazine
——media         —scope, reach
                  —effectiveness

—finally       evaluating system

提问及应答 
（1）	细节扩展法：用特殊疑问句
Question 1
You mentioned three objectives of an advertising program.  How can you judge the very kind of the objective a specific advertising program serves?

Question 2
How many ways are there for you to control costs of advertisement?

Question 3
As for the products of your company, which media do you think is the best one for advertising?  And why?

（2）	个人意见法：用一般疑问句
Question 4
Do you think timely adjusting is just as important as preparation beforehand in the development of an advertisement program?

Question 5
I heard you talked about evaluation systems of advertisement, and found myself quite interested in it.  Has your company adopted/evolved such a system?  How does it work?

Question 6
Do you believe/agree/support that advertisement is the best way in promoting sales?

回答问题时简明扼要
    Answer to question 1
    There are two main aspects we must take into consideration when judging the objectives of a specific advertising program.  Firstly, we must decide what major category the product belongs to.  Secondly, the current sales situation of the product on the market should be considered.


    Answer to question 2
I think the advertisement costs can be controlled by two ways.  The first way is to choose the most economically-efficient media, such as newspaper or radio rather than TV slots, for the former two will reach the general public at a relatively low cost. The second way is to ensure that the quantity of advertisement is appropriate, with no space for waste.

    Answer to question 3
    Since my company’s manufacturing mainly focuses on food products, I believe TV may be the best media for advertisement.  Because TV reaches the most extensive mass and seems to serve a very strong influence on children and women, who compose the major consumers of our products.
  
    Answer to question 4
    Yes, I quite agree with you.  Because the market situation keeps changing almost without stop, timely adjusting is of key importance leading to a successful launch of an advertising program.  But it never reduces the significance of preparation.
  
    Answer to question 5
Thank you for your interest in our company.  Actually, our company adopted this evaluating system last year.  It has worked very well up till now, providing us with a set of quantified standards in evaluation, which are much more objective in comparison with previously man-made criteria.

    Answer to question 6
    It cannot be denied that advertisement is a very effective way of sales promotion, but I don’t think it is the only way to do this.  Cutting prices, for example, sometimes generates the same result as advertisement does.  And that’s a more direct way, and is money-saving.
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="c8e75e9f9c154a6e8968df7b6bb9009c">
<name>第九课时 </name>
<content>第八讲
Ⅰ Business Dialogue
Trade Show – Cell Phone 

Shop Owner:	Whew! The traffic at this trade show is so much heavier than it was last year!
Manufacturer:	Yes. There are more phone manufacturers than ever.
Shop Owner:	Yeah, I noticed Microsoft has started making cell phones.
Manufacturer:	Every booth has a different gimmick to try to catch your attention.
Shop Owner:	I noticed that you have Michael Jordan signing autographs in your booth.
Manufacturer:	I’ll admit it – it is a gimmick to pull you in. Now that you are here, let me show you some of the great features of our newest products.
Shop Owner:	There’s a big demand for cell phones with digital cameras.
Manufacturer: Of course we have several models with miniature cameras. We also have the basic simple phones that most of your customers need.
Shop Owner:	I’m kind of pressed for time. Why don’t you just give me a brochure and your business card, and I’ll contact you later?
Manufacturer:	Of course. Here you go.
Shop Owner:	Ok, and now I just have time to squeeze in a short conversation with Michael Jordan.


Ⅱ Discussion









Candidate A: It is the first time for our company to attend a trade fair in Paris. So we have to do a lot of preparations before we set off. Do you think so?
Candidate B: I’ m of exactly the same idea. Firstly, I think we must arrange an appropriate schedule. For example, we should arrive a day earlier to give us time to adjust and acclimatize.
Candidate A: I agree entirely. As we know, travel fatigue, climatic changes, jet lag, foreign food, etc. will all have great effect on us.
Candidate B: Yes. And then we should book air tickets and reserve accommodations in advance.
Candidate A: Yes. I think we should contact the travel agent because it can offer variety of choices and discount.
Candidate B: That’s just what I was thinking. Then, we must remind every participant that cultural differences can cause a lot of misunderstandings and even break a deal. So they should learn more about French culture.
Candidate A: Can you put things into the perspective?
Candidate B: For instance, shaking hands with everyone present, inviting your customers to lunch rather than dinner, avoiding talking business over the main course, etc. are all basic business customs that our participants should bear in mind.
Candidate A: I go along with you about that. I think we can invite French people to give every participant lecture to help them familiarize with French culture.
Candidate B: Ok, that’s agreed. I’ll present our ideas to the board of directors. Nice talking with you.








Candidate A: Our company is organizing a press conference to launch our latest model. We must make careful planning and considerate arrangements to ensure the most satisfying outcome.
Candidate B: True enough. I think the first thing we should take into consideration is the people we shall invite to the press conference. What are your views on this?
Candidate A: As I see it, we should target most important motoring magazines, national papers, major regional papers and freelance journalists, etc.
Candidate B: That’s a good point. When the public reads positive things in their favorite magazine or newspaper, they are the journalists’ own comments and therefore much more powerful than advertising because they aren’t influenced by the organization.
Candidate A: Yes. So, our goal is to communicate the quality and image of our cars to the motoring press.
Candidate B: Then, how about the information needed in the press conference. Would you comment on this point?
Candidate A: I think we should make sure that press information packs are accessible to everyone present.
Candidate B: I wonder if you could explain it in more detail.
Candidate A: sure. The information packs include, for example, brochures about specifications of our advanced cars, the most attractive pictures reflecting the modern image of our cars, etc.
Candidate B: I agree entirely. What’s more, I think welcome information and itineraries for guests should also be prepared in advance.
Candidate A: Oh, exactly.

Ⅲ Examination Strategies     1）看清问题、紧扣主题、合理分配时间     2）和搭档注意配合，切忌一边倒     3）如何合理的利用准备时间
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="94aad8ef775b432e9de664455cc450b4">
<name>第十课时</name>
<content>第九讲
Ⅰ Presentation Topics
Entertaining clients

WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
ENTERTAINING CLIENTS
	TYPES OF ACTIVITIES
	COST

 Types of Activities:
a.	Entertaining client is done by way of a series of activities. Such as a sightseeing tour, a football match, a ballroom party, an orchestra performance, a ballet show, a fashion show, playing tennis and a formal meal, etc. 
b.	The activities that you choose will constitute a part of the first impression that you will give to your clients. So you should be careful when choosing the type of activities. You need to consider the client’s age, educational and cultural backgrounds and do some research about your clients’ characters and hobbies.
c.	For well-educated clients, they may expect some high class-associated activities, such as ballet, ballroom parties, and orchestra performances. If you fulfill their expectation/standard, your efforts will put a lot of weight on your credibility.  
d.	For some young clients, you may wish to take them to some more fashionable activities, such as a music bar, a pop music show, a fashion show.
e.	For those sporty clients-football, tennis
f.	However, you should always end up all kind of activities with having a formal meal. You don’t want to talk about business with your clients in the tennis court or theatre; they are just the warming-up activities for the key matter-business. After a whole day or a few days’ entertainment, you may find the distance between the two sides are much narrower than the beginning, and there might be a lot of things that you both want to talk about.

The costs of entertainment  
a.	Not always the essential thing. Depending on the nature/characteristics of the transaction or the size of the deal.
b.	Should consider the profit issue. If the company is expecting to make big gain/profits out of a specific client, it should at least put in proportional investment to entertain/please its clients. E.g.….
c.	If the company foresees that the client is not very lucrative, then….
d.	The ideal plan would be spending as little money as possible to get the deal done. But you must not offend your clients. You should make them feel being welcomed. 



Complaint handling

WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…?
 DEALING WITH COMPLAINTS FROM CLIENTS
	OFFERING AN APOLOGY
	SUGGESTING A SOLUTION TO THE PROBLEM

a.	Offering an apology is the very basic level. 
b.	When the clients think that they have received unfair treatments, the first thing that the company should do is to calm them down and try to keep the client. 
c.	An apology is the first step and a useful method to maintain control of the situation.
d.	Offering an apology is an important gesture to show that the hosting company is fully aware of the situation and would like to take the potential responsibility for its mistakes. 
e.	The complaining clients would feel that their complaints are being paid attention and may therefore be happy to proceed to the transaction with the hosting company.
f.	It is necessary to suggest a solution to the problem as well.
g.	The clients want to enter into the transaction in a good mood and with a reliable and trustworthy business partner. Apart from an apology, the client would want to have the problems and misunderstanding solved before their communication moves to the next level. If the hosting company failed or refused to suggest a solution, its sincerity of entering into the transaction would be put into doubt. 

Ⅱ Discussion Topic
   Entertaining Foreign Clients

Your company is entertaining a group of foreign clients for three days, including one non-working day.
You have been asked to plan a programme for the visit.
Discuss the situation together, and decide:
	What kinds of activities would be suitable for the visit
	What information it would be useful to know about the clients before finalizing the programme

Interlocutor: [Select one or more of the following questions as appropriate, to redress any imbalance or to broaden the discussion.]
	What kinds of arrangements need to be made before foreign visitors arrive? (Why?)
	Are there any disadvantages for a company in having a visit from foreign clients? (Why / Why not?)
	Where would you take foreign visitors in your home town? (Why?)
	Would you enjoy looking after business visitors for a few days? (Why / Why not?)
	What problem might there be when socializing with foreign business people? (Why?)
	What are the long-term benefits of establishing personal contacts with foreign clients?

Thank you.  That is the end of the speaking test.
[Retrieve materials.]

Ⅲ Discussion Functional Sentences
 
（一）	开始某个话题
Let’s start with …
Shall we begin with …
So, the first item on the agenda is …
Linda, would you like to kick off?
（二）	结束某个话题
Right, I think that covers the first item.
Shall we leave that item?
If you don’t have anything else to add, …

（三）	转移话题
Let’s move on to the next item …
The next question on the agenda is …
Now let’s come to the question of …

（四）	打断对方
Excuse me, may I interrupt?
Just a moment, but …
Can I say something here?
Mark, sorry, …
Sorry to interrupt, but …

（五）	评价
1．	同意
That’s a good point.
I agree with you.  I can’t agree with you more.
I see what you mean.
Yes, …
That’s quite a good idea.
That’s absolutely true.
2．	反对
I totally disagree with you.
I couldn’t agree less.
You must be joking!

（六）	询问对方意见
What do you think about this?
What’s your opinion on this?
Have you considered …
I haven’t heard your opinion about …

（七）	表达自己观点
I think/feel/believe that …
You mentioned that …, but, in my view …
In my opinion, we should …
I’d like to point out …
Let me emphasize …
My view is that …
Just let me finish.

（八）	评论
That’s a good idea/an excellent idea.
That’s very interesting.
I’m sure we’d all agree with that.
That’s a very good point/an important point.

（九）	要求对方澄清观点
I don’t see what you’re getting at.
I’m not sure what you mean.
I’m not sure what you are saying.
It’s not clear what you mean.

（十）	避免跑题
We’re missing the point.
We’re getting off the point.
Let’s get back to the main point.
It’s not on the agenda, but …

（十一）	回应
That’s marvelous.
That’s great.
That’s fine.
OK. 
All right.
I see your point.
I understand your concern.
 

更加口语化的表达方式
 
1. 口语化表达简单同意
a.	Yeah!
b.	How true!
c.	Exactly!
d.	Absolutely!
e.	 Well said!
f.	You got it!
g.	You bet!
h.	That’s for sure.
i.	My opinion exactly!

2.  表同意
a.	I share your view on that!
b.	Oh, yes, I couldn’t agree with you more, you are genient!
c.	Okey, you are the doctor.
d.	I don’t think anyone would disagree.
e.	I have no problem with that.
f.	I couldn’t have said it better.
g.	I wish I had said that.
h.	I am with you there.
i.	I think I will go along with your proposal.

3.  部分同意
a.	Could be!
b.	Yes, you’ve point there.
c.	So it seems! （似乎有点道理）
d.	So to speak!
e.	In the manner of speaking.
f.	I agree with much of what you said.
g.	That’s one way of looking at it, I admit.

4.  口语化表达不同意
a.	Not really.
b.	Not at all.
c.	Of course not.
d.	No way.
e.	Not a chance. 

5.  不同意
a.	Do you really think so?
b.	I am not convinced.
c.	Don’t speak too soon.
d.	I will believe it when I see it.
e.	I’m afraid we don’t see eye to eye on this.
f.	That was not the case.

6.  强不同意
a.	No, I don’t agree. Don’t waste your breath.
b.	You must be joking. / kidding
c.	You can’t be serious.
d.	You are way off base. (棒不在垒上)
e.	You don’t know up from down.
f.	Over my dead body.
g.	I wasn’t born yesterday.
h.	That’s ridiculous.
i.	It’s pure fiction.
j.	Non-sense!
k.	Bullshit!
l.	That’s out of the question!
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="4469e094ed1840f29f82ab62f4f23a1a">
<name>第十一课时</name>
<content>第十讲
Ⅰ Mock Exam

1.	Conversation
Where do you live?
Do you like living in London?
What do you like about living there?
Where would you like to live?
If you couldn’t live in London, where would you like to live?
How do you travel to work?
Do you like traveling by tube?
In future, how do you think people will travel by work?

2.	Presentation
WHAT IS IMPORTANT WHEN…
RECRUITING NEW STAFF
	QUALIFICATIONS
	MOTIVATION

3.	Discussion
English Language Training
Your company is planning to offer an English language training to employees.
You have been asked to help with the planning and organization of the training.

Discuss the situation together, and decide:
	Who should be given the chance of having English classes
	How to encourage employees to take part in the training


Ⅱ Interview Question
1.	What do you consider your major strength?
A.	self-motivated
B.	hard working and honest 
C.	look for better ways of doing the work
D.	good interpersonal relationships
 
2.	What do you consider your major weakness?
I cannot leave a job half-done and usually find myself thinking of possible solutions to problems while I am driving to work or in the shower. I also know I spend too much time in my work. I can't get enough leisure time.

3.	Why do you want to leave your present job / previous job?
There is no room for my career growth and promotion I want in my previous job. So I'm looking for a company, which recognizes and rewards hard workers.
There is room for improvement in your work. It is not as good as it could be.
My reason for leaving my present employer is that I am desirous of getting broader experience in trading.
I am leaving my present job in order to improve my position and have more responsibility.

4.	What is it about this job that interests you? / Why do you want to join our company?
Your company enjoys a good reputation in this field. I've heard you take care of your employees and offer good salaries and benefits. 
Your company is well respected in this field. I have heard nothing but good things about your company. 
I've heard you take care of your employees and offer good salaries and benefits.

5.	Why do you think you are qualified for this position?
I graduated from Beijing University in 1993, and hold a Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science. Therefore, I have a firm knowledge background in this field.
I have spent the last 3 years working specially in this field. I think I can bring a lot of experience and knowledge with me.
Yes. Because I do believe that my qualifications and experience perfectly match what you are looking for.
Yes. Because I have the experience you are looking for，and think I will be one of the best in this field.
Yes. I know exactly what's involved. I am a hard worker and will perform to the best of my ability.

6.	What salary do you expect?
This will be my first job and I lack experience, so I hesitate to suggest a salary. 
I don't mind if I start with a low salary because it is my first time to hunt for a job and I lack experience. I'll leave it to you, because I'm not in the position to ask for a certain salary at present." 
I think we can reach an agreement on the salary if I can be sure that there is a good chance to advance in this company.  
I believe you must have a standard starting salary, which should be satisfactory.
I am making RMB2000 a month at my present work. I should expect not lower than RMB3000 a month.
One good qualified man is better than a score of men. I can handle this work quite easily by myself and you will end up saving money if you pay me RMB4000 a month.

7.	What type of people do you prefer working with? 
I like working with all types of people.  
I like working with people who work well under pressure.
I can work with anyone as long as they are honest. 

Occasionally I might run into a conflict with someone. When this happens, I usually focus on what the conflict is about rather than on personalities. I find that approach helps me to maintain a successful relationship with anyone and often leads to resolution and strengthened relationships.
If the solution is an easy one and not time consuming I will help my teammate. Otherwise I will tell him to wait till I finish my project and then I will help him. 

8.	Tell me about yourself?
Ever since I was a child…
to be fascinated with sth.
talent
to be heavily involved in sth.
elaborate on

9.	Where would you like to be in 5 years?
I would like to follow the management career path.
I would like to try the secretary career track
I'd like to be a senior manager of your company in five years.　　 
Although it's certainly difficult to predict things far into the future, I know what direction I want to develop toward. Within five years, I would like to become one of the best engineers in your company.
“I would like to become the expert that others rely upon. And in doing so, I feel I will be fully prepared to take on any greater responsibilities that might be presented in the long term." 
 
In five years I want to be a valuable part of this company and help it to reach its goal. I also want to manage a challenging project and bring in latest technology that will benefit the company.
In the next five years, I want to learn new things, gain more experience and increase my value to your company. I want to learn my job well and eventually to achieve a position of higher responsibility within your company.
In the next five years, I will not plan on moving or going back to school, I want to stay with this company for many years, and expect I would be very happy with this job.

10.	Tell me something about your educational background.
I've taken every class the college has to offer in the field and also completed an independent study project specifically in this area.

It seems as if organizations are more dependent than ever on the ability of employees to be articulate both orally and in writing. I am constantly taking advantage of opportunities to develop my oral and written communication skills.
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="e67593157e444e4b84ab4f4fc484891b">
<name>新东方讲义</name>
<content>Chapter 1

         * 地下室：basement  地下储藏用的屋子
                                cellar        地窖
                                underground room 地下室

一、	国内英语考试体系

1．Academic English ：CET-4   CET-6   PETS
                     Band-4   Band-8
2．Living English：TOEFL   IELTS
      * May I borrow your facilities？
3．Working English：BEC   TOEIC   

二、	BEC简介及概况

1．	BEC分为三个等级
（1）	Preliminary  
* Preliminary：基本的，初级的  e.g. Preliminary Market Research
（2）	Vantage
                * 我们所学是 BECV，是学习英语过程中的intermediate 水平。
（3）	Higher
        
2．	BEC对学生的重大影响

BEC is unique.
BEC sets me different from others / other human beings.
BEC raises my confidence.
BEC is the secret of my success.

此组句式可替换使用，可以形容对你意义深远的一件物品，一段经历或是一个特殊的人。
NOTES：如果用在某人身上，应把第一句改为：
You are special in my heart!
        
3．	BEC口语课堂风格与授课方式：
I love words. 
I love sentences.
I am just crazy about the beautiful sentence patterns.
They are all my wealth.

4．	BEC=Business English Certificate
* 谈成一笔交易：finalize a deal / cut a deal
* 在考试的时候不要苛求写出 earth shaking articles
* 注意英语中表达同一意思可有多种表达方法：
   e.g. yes, sure, why not, certainly
          diploma, degree, bachelor degree, master degree

三、	BEC口语考试形式

1．	基本形式如下页表。
2．	注意：
（1）	Mini-presentation 采取话题“三选一”形式。
（2）	2 Candidates 一起参加考试。
（3）	Criteria （评分标准）
①	Pronunciation (语音面貌) 包括：
a.	狭义的语音面貌：单词发音
b.	Intonation （音调）
c.	Stress and Rhythm (语调及节奏)  
②	Vocabulary and Grammar
* I reckon= I believe= I think= To my knowledge= …
在口试过程中，应至少运用一句虚拟语气，一句比较级，几个从句，并做到长短句交替使用。
③	Discourse Management
做到KISS原则：Keep it simple and stupid.
④	Interactive Communication (互动性)
（4）	注意BrE and AmE之间的区别
（5）	注意在口语考试中，Speed ≠ eloquence，communication的重点在于所说的话应该understandable。
（6）	平时应注意对Grammar的训练，以防考试时犯基础错误。例如，he /she 用错，被动语态用错的话很难使成绩提高。

	BECV (old) 	BECV (new)	BECH 	评分
PART Ⅰ	Conversation 3min	Conversation 3min	Conversation 3min	①②
PART Ⅱ	Question and Ask
6min	Mini-presentation
6min
1min prepare
2-3min presentation
1-2min partner ask
                       	Mini-presentation
                      6min	③
PART Ⅲ	Discussion   
5min	Discussion     5min	Discussion     7min	④
TOTLE TIME	14min	14min	16min	
 
3．	参加考试的考官：
（1）Interlocutor                    Chinese
（2） Assessor                     Chinese
（3）Cambridge Examiner            English           
所以，应该注意话题应该尽量选择东、西方文化融合较多的东西

四、	应该如何突破口语

1．	应该从几方面着手突破口语
（1）Listening          input 与 output之间可以互相转换
（2）Reading            可以上网看一些资料，如 Financial Times http://news.ft.com
（3）Reading aloud 半小时/天，注意培养Language Sense
（4）Confidence
       
2．	应该如何准备考试
（1）	认真听听力原文，充分利用Tape script，尤其是PART Ⅱ Monologue部分
（2）	利用Mirror练习发音及锻炼自信
（3）	用Repeater录音练习

五、	口语课总共七节，课程安排如下：

1．	Intro to BEC, sample test
2．	PartⅠ and business enrichment
3．	Teamwork, project management, competition
4．	Motivating staff, Entertaining clients, 
Business premises （不动产）=property
5．	Marketing trade fair, Promotion
6．	Starting a new job (job interview), Technology (BECH), Finance (BECH)
7．	Summary –exam (Demo), Business

六、	口语的境界

1．	考试口语：应注意自己expand question
e.g. My surname is Xie, my second name is Jiaoyue.
My friend always calls me Irene, my English name.
e.g. 在说自己的Hometown时也应该适当扩充
*词组 to be exact 准确的说

Presentation 之 取非式 （TC10A）
①	I’d like to make a short presentation on the topic about …
②	Talking about this, I have 2 things / aspects / views / opinions to cover.
③	Now, let me explain it to you one by one.
④	First, find out about the audience.
Second, researching the topic.
⑤	Without the audience that would be …
⑥	If you failed to research the topic, …
⑦	That’s why I think so.

2．	生活口语 slang (俚语) / idiomatic expression (地道的英语用法)
e.g. cost an arm and a leg 很贵
read someone like a book 非常了解某人

3．	职业用语 Terminology, 应该注意formal
e.g. not a chance= no way （不能用语考试中）
split the difference 平摊 （可以用于考试中）

七、	有关BEC的Vocabulary 

1．推荐书目 《BEC难词解释》作者：陈晓慰   经济科学出版社
2．考BEC应具有5000单词量，介于CET-4（4000）与CET-6（6000）之间
3．注意一些日常用语
e.g. 番茄酱 catch-up 
       make 做名词时表牌子，样式，制造，制法
          e.g. especially produced by a particular maker
       make 的常用短语
①	make a killing 
e.g. He made a killing on that deal, I wish I had bought some shares.
②	make my day 令人高兴，令人很爽
③	make ends meet 收支相当
e.g. I can’t make ends meet.
④	make waves 兴风作浪
⑤	make a scene 关手机
e.g. Don’t make yourself a scene.

* 绕口令：
   Good cookies could be cooked by a good cook if a good cook could cook good cookies.

八、	Speak Varied English   
说地道英语 (authentic)，说灵活英语 (flexible)，说生动英语（lively）
* lively 还可修饰 mind, description, song
* flexi-time 弹性工作制

Chapter 2

一、PartⅠ应试三大原则：Active、Creative、Informative
     
* DINK家庭=Double Income No Kids
    
1.注意非语言交际 （Non-verbal communication）包括：
Eye contact
Smile
Nod
Shake hands

2．注意口语中的连读
   （1）/n/+元音 
        e.g. an^apple                       an^employer                        an^hour
   （2）辅音+元音
         e.g. a pair^of shoes            all^of^us                              get^up
                            shut^up                        wait^a^moment                   how much is^it
                            first^of^all                   for^a^while                          some^of^it
                            hand^it^over                tell^us                                  sold^out
                            keep^it                         take^part^in                         she and^I
                            Would you like^a cup of tea?
   （3）辅音+辅音
         e.g. Please stop^pushing                      black^cat
                            I like^kidding                                 big^girl
                            They had a tough^fight                  take^care
   （4）爆破音+爆破音
         e.g. bad^boy          stop^talking             Does it make^difference?

二、团队 Teamwork (商务知识)
    1.分析教学team 
王令   big cheese / wheal               VIP / CEO
刘军      big man on campus              Financial manager
王湘鄂    chatterbox                          Marketing 
谢姣岳    small potato / nobody        R&amp;D (Research and Development)
2．Teamwork 补充讲义 （见讲义第一页）

三、Presentation 之重申式 （TC10B）
    1. How to … involves many aspects/sides/respects.
2. Each of them requires careful consideration.
3. Firstly, … is very important/vital/significant/crucial/essential/
helpful/imperative/indispensable
4.Secondly, … is the key to ….
5.Thirdly, in order to improve customer service, we should/ought to/must/need to ….
6.Shortly/In short, … are three main points.

四、Competition (商务知识)
    1．见补充讲义第二页
2．Economic (4c) ① Competition
                               ② Contradiction
                               ③ Cooperation
                                ④ Coordinating

五、常用俚语
    1．Dead end 死胡同
2．Doggy bag 打包袋 take away food
3．Pass away 去世的婉转的说法= kick the bucket
4．Killer=nerve-racking 难题
5．Mickey mouse=banana
6．The one wearing pants in the house 当家作主的人
7．Be yourself. 该怎么样就怎么样，做你自己。
8．Pipe 吸油管 straw 吸管

六、Attack speaking through listening 用听力突破口语
     * My recent experiences tell me the real aim of an interview is to obtain the very job I want.
          * An effective interview is like an exciting encounter with a seatmate on a flight.
          * When somebody tries to control us, we resented, when we try to control somebody, they resent us.
注意在做discussion时一定要feel free,在讨论过程中interrupt、agree、disagree enthusiastically.避免成为yes man/follower。应该注意open minded(do not to hesitate to change your mind),避免narrow minded和single-minded.

七、Presentation 定义式 （TC11C）
1. I like to make a small presentation and my topic is how to plan …
2. According to my knowledge/In my opinion/view), there are 3 key elements/factors.
3. First, selecting topics. Good topics are those that could make people think/ …
4. The second is selecting staff. Right staff are those who are diligent and obedient/ …
5. Third, selecting locations. In other words, we should choose a place that is very convenient.
6. In a word, that’s why I think so.

八、Presentation 举例式 （TC10B）
4．In the first place, we should pay enough attention to staff training. For example/instance, staff might attend the course on manners and speech making.
5. In the second place, we should conduct customer satisfaction surveys. For example, we can prepare some questionnaires or set up a hotline.
6.By the way/Last, but not the least, we should stress on product quality, for instance, …

九、	Motivating staff （商务知识）
1. Maslow’s hierarchy of needs
①	Self-actualization= take responsibility
②	Esteem/ego needs: 可用company car或者job title这种status symbol满足
③	Social needs: need to belong, teamwork
④	Security needs: job security
⑤	Physiological needs: shelter, food, transport, cloth, basic pay, canteen …

* 绕口令
  Peter Pipe picked a peck of pickled peppers prepared by his parents and put them in a large paper plate.
  If you understand say understand, if you don’t understand say don’t understand. If you understand say don’t understand. How can I understand you understand, understand?

Chapter 3

一、	日常用语

     ⅠGreetings
1．	Expressing surprise when meeting someone
a.	Long time no see! 
（Chinglish 转变过去的，就像有时外国人也说 horse horse tiger tiger ）
b.	Hi, there. What a coincidence!
c.	I haven’t seen you for ages.
d.	Fancy meeting you here.
(Fancy party 化妆舞会，fancy hotel/restaurant 极贵的饭店/饭馆)
2．	Ask someone how is he doing
a.	How are you doing? / How are you getting on? / How are you feeling on?
b.	Are you doing okey?
c.	How are things? /  How are things going with you?
d.	Hi, Mike, how’s business?
         3.    Greeting a familiar friend
                a.   Anything new? / Anything special?
                b.   What’s up? （带点贬义，通常指不太好的事情发生）
c.    What have you been up to? (近来在忙什么？) 
up to ones ears / neck…可表示很忙
d.    How’s life? / How is life been treating you?

Ⅱ Responding to greetings
  1.   Things just couldn’t be better. / Never better!
  2.    It’s nothing to complain about. / No complaints.
  3.    Same as usual. / Same as always.
  4.    Could be worse. （凑合吧）
  5.     Thins could be better. /  Been getting by. (凑合吧)

二、	有关Part Ⅲ Discussion
* 主要考 Teamwork, Cooperativeness
* 注意，对方说20秒后应该主动interrupt
        1．Preparation (40s)
              (1) 分清角色 role : a. Boss and subordinates
b. Colleagues
(2) 看清issues (items) : Activities, information
(3) 分清responsibility
2．	Discuss (Task 31)
(1) Opening （切入正题）
Activity：
A：Show me around the city / sight seeing
B：Disagree. Skiing resorts
A：Agree. Take them to dinner
B：Agree
Information：
B：Favorites and preferences, age, sex
A：Disagree, age, number of people.
B：Agree, cultural differences
A：Agree.

(2) Closing
       Okey, time is limited, from what we discuss above, to sum up, …
       * 注意，总结应该两个人一起说。
3．	常用用语
（1）	Interrupt
a.	Excuse me …
b.	Can I / May I just come in here?
c.	Can I / May I interrupt for a moment?
d.	Just a minute.
e.	One moment, please.
（2）	Give one’s opinion
                          Strongly:   a. I am convinced / sure / positive that …
b. I definitely / certainly think that …
c. I really do think that …
Neutrally:  a. In my opinion, …
         b. I think / feel / consider that …
         c. As I see it …/ According to my knowledge …
Weakly:    a. I am inclined to say that … / think that …
         b. I tend to think that …
          (3)     Disagree, agree and partial agree
                           Agree:      a. I totally / fully / wholly / completely agree with you.
b. I am in total agreement with you.
c.  I am all in favor of that.
                           Disagree:  a.  I am afraid (I don’t agree). / I don’t / I can’t agree with you.
Partial agree: a. Up to a point, I’d agree with you, but …
           b. To a certain extend, I’d agree with you, but …
           c.  You may be right. / You could be right, but …
                    (4)       Repeat 
a.	Do you really mean this?
b.	Do you really think so?
c.	I just want to make one thing clear.
d.	Could you explain it a little bit for me?
        
* 有关Premises的专业术语
   1．工业原区 Enterprise zone
    2．政府投资捐款 Investment grant
    3．政府援助 Government assistance
    4．Subsidised premises
    5．开发区 Development area 
    6．经济衰落区 Depressed area

三、	情人节专题 Valentine’s Day (亦纪念 Friendship )
1．	代表Love and Romance 
2．	礼物
（1）送Chocolate (1874) ，送Card 并在 card上写xxx ，送 Perfume 香水
（2）不同的情人送不同的礼物
           旧情人送旧照片，远方的情人电台点歌，住家情人烛光晚餐，office lover送花，分手的情人在网上送card ，现在的情人可送健身卡。

四、Presentation 具体式 （？） 
        * Presentation 一般采取“331”形式，即3句开头，3句观点，1句结尾。
       4． First, location. 注意结合讲义进行补充
5.	Second, the length of contract. (讲义P5 a )
6.	Third, workforce.
7.	That’s why I think so. / Thank you very much. / Thank you for taking your time.
Thank you for listening.

五、Presentation 理由式 （TC18A）
       4．Market research is important because through market research, the company could gather, record and analyze and present the relevant information, which serves the fundamental goal / basic goal of marketing.
        5.   Selecting appropriate media is important / crucial because different media aim at different customers, furthermore, the cost varies.
         6.   Advertising is the most important part because it could either make the products know to the public or waste a lot of money.

六、综合总结Presentation的6 versions
1.	取非式，重申式，定义式 。（较容易）
2.	举例式，具体式，理由式。 （较难）
3.	注意6个versions 可以混用。

Chapter 4

一、Romance and Love 之经典影片
1．	Gone with the wind (1939)
* Tomorrow is another day.
       2.    The Philadelphia Story (1940)
       3.     Casablanca  (1942)
4.	The Apartment (1960)
5.	It happened one night (1934)
6.	Brief Encounter (1945)
7.	Roman Holiday
                    * I’d like to be remembered as a decent human being.
8.	Harold and Maude (1971)
9.	The way we were   (1973)
10.	Romeo and Juliet  (1968)

二、Talking about Romantic Love
1.	When I met Susan, it was love at first sight.
2.	I fell my head over heels in love with her the moment I saw her.
3.	True love, crazy about someone, have a crush on someone, carry torch for someone
4.	Talking about sex
a.	Mike used to sleep around until he met Snoopy. (sleep around：很风流)
b.	Their relationship is said to be strictly platonic.
c.	We are just friends, okey?
d.	Everyone in the office knows she’s having an affair. (婚外恋)
e.	Love affairs (贬：桃色新闻)，December heartbeat 黄昏恋
5.	Approaching the opposite sex
(1)出现在电影中的经典搭讪语句
a.	Let me see your strap mark. (Beach)
b.	Do you really eat the junk? / snatch?  (Shopping)
c.	Your place or mine? (Bar)
(2) 可用语生活中的句式
a.	That’s a pretty outfit.
b.	Say, don’t I know you from somewhere?
c.	What do you think of the band?
d.	Would you care to dance?
e.	I feel a little embarrassed but I’d really like to meet you.
6.	Dating Appointment
(1) 种类：
a.	grouping dating (dates)
b.	double dating (dates)
c.	blind dating (dates) 相亲, match-maker 媒人，murder the line 照本宣科
               （2） 约人：
a.	What are you up to this weekend? 这个周末你在忙什么？
b.	I was wondering if you’d like to go out to dinner?
c.	I had a marvelous time, Jane. Can I call you?
(3)   Commenting on someone’s attractiveness
a.	She is a real dish. / doll / babe
b.	She’s as gorgeous as ever. (80%turn head) (Does she turn head? 她有回头率么？)
c.	He’s absolutely gorgeous.
d.	He’s absolutely cute.
e.	He’s a real hunk.
f.	Her new boyfriend is not much to look at. （没什么可看的）, but he seems to be pretty smart.
                 (4)    Express your romantic feeling
a.	I adore you.
b.	You mean the world to me.
c.	Be my sweetheart. (女对男说)
d.	Can’t you see I’m absolutely mad about you?
                  (5)     Turning someone down
a.	You are not my type.
b.	Sorry, I’m not interested.
c.	You must be kidding.
d.	I have to wash my hair. (找借口推脱约会，一般三次可以 turn down someone completely)
e.	No way! /  Not if you were the last person on earth.

三、有关面试的英语问答：
        1. What do you consider your major strength?
a.	self-motivated
b.	hard-working and honest
c.	I always look for better ways of doing things
表明自己非常quick minded并且creative, 避免说自己smart
d.	good interpersonal relationship / communication ( teamwork)
e.	I do believe I do present a lot of strength.
First, I can work under pressure and hard working.
Second, I am independent, but can team work.
Third, use my own method to solve problem.
Then, I am honest.
          2.  What do you consider your major weakness?
a.	too honest (但要说对relationship 不好，要努力改进)
b.	I cannot leave the work half done.
c.	I am so hard working and I don’t have much free time.
           3.  Why do you want to leave your present job?
a.	   表明自己想得到更大的发展空间
There is no room to career growth and the promotion.
b.	I am desirous of getting broader experience in trading.
c.	I am leaving my present job in order to improve my position and have more responsibility.
                4.  What is it about this job that interests you? Why do you want to join our company?
a.	In this field, your company has a good reputation to my knowledge.
b.	I’ve heard nothing but good things about your company.
c.	Your company is well respected in this field.
d.	I’ve heard your company take good care of your employees and offer good salaries and benefits.
                 5.  Why you feel you are qualified for this position?
a.	a firm knowledge background
b.	work experience  并应指出会将经验带给贵公司
I think I can bring a lot of experience and knowledge with you.
6.   Do you think you are the right person for the job?
          a.  Yes, because I do believe that my qualifications and experience can perfect match what you are looking for.
          b.  Because I have the experience you are looking for, and I think I am one of the best in this field.
 7.  Do you know what’s involved in a position like this?
a.  perform to the best of my ability
                  8.  What salary do you expect?
a.	It’s up to you, just acceptable and reasonable. (student)
b.	我可以接受底薪2000，但我会在3个月试用期中证明我的价值10倍于此。
c.	What is the best you can offer to me?
d.	There will be my first job, and I lack experience. So I hesitate to suggest a salary.
e.	I will leave it to you, because I am not in the position to ask for a certain salary at present.
f.	I think we can reach an agreement, if I can be sure there is a good chance to advance to me.
g.	A standard starting salary
h.	我现在2000，不能比这个少，大概2500
i.	One good qualified man is better than a group of man.

四、	面试中谈到的有关teamwork内容
           1. What type of people do you like to working with?
a.	见strength
b.	I like working with all types of people.
c.	I can work with anyone as long as they are honest.
d.	I like working with people who work well under pressure.
e.	I don’t like working with people with gossip. / who are lazy / crack under pressure.
2.  I generally get along well with the coworkers.
3.  focus on what the conflict is about rather than an personalities （对事不对人）
4.  take responsibility for the project
5. Tell me something about yourself.
a.	说一分钟，说自己最特别的地方，起到画龙点睛的作用。
b.	I am young but experienced.
            6.  Where would you like to be in five years?
a.	I would like to follow the management career passed.
b.	预测未来不容易，但是我清楚我的发展方向，在五年内做到one of the best in the field.
五、	面试中谈到的教育问题 Interview about education
             1.  I’ve gone above and beyond.
              2.  Which is better? Oral English or written English?
a.	从这个问题可看出贵公司很重视英语这两种skills, 而我恰巧是一个每抓住机会就能提高自己的人。
b.	Oral English比较好，但是我曾经在…发表…文章。
c.	Written English 比较好，但也常练习oral English
六、	Presentation 常用语
Opening sentence
1. The present talk aims to decide …
2. The purpose of the talk is to answer the question of …
3. In brief, this talk sets out to solve the problem of …
分层：
    1. first second third 
    2. firstly secondly thirdly
    3. one hand, in the other hand
    4. next, also, in addition, further more （至少运用一两个）
    5. as for;  as … is concerned
小结：
    1.   so, to sum up
    2.   in conclusion
    3.   in general
    4.   on the whole, overall
    5.    from the above information, it can be shown that …
7.	before we close, let me just summarize the main point. （presentation估计用不到，可用于discussion）
七、	Discussion常用语
1. 口语化表达简单同意
a.	Yeah!
b.	How true!
c.	Exactly!
d.	Absolutely!
e.	 Well said!
f.	You got it!
g.	You bet!
h.	That’s for sure.
i.	My opinion exactly!
         2.  表同意
a.	I share your view on that!
b.	Oh, yes, I couldn’t agree with you more, you are genient!
c.	Okey, you are the doctor.
d.	I don’t think anyone would disagree.
e.	I have no problem with that.
f.	I couldn’t have said it better.
g.	I wish I had said that.
h.	I am with you there.
i.	I think I will go along with your proposal.
         3.  部分同意
a.	Could be!
b.	Yes, you’ve point there.
c.	So it seems! （似乎有点道理）
d.	So to speak!
e.	In the manner of speaking.
f.	I agree with much of what you said.
g.	That’s one way of looking at it, I admit.
         4.  口语化表达不同意
a.	Not really.
b.	Not at all.
c.	Of course not.
d.	No way.
e.	Not a chance. 
         5.  不同意
a.	Do you really think so?
b.	I am not convinced.
c.	Don’t speak too soon.
d.	I will believe it when I see it.
e.	I’m afraid we don’t see eye to eye on this.
f.	That was not the case.
         6.  强不同意
a.	No, I don’t agree. Don’t waste your breath.
b.	You must be joking. / kidding
c.	You can’t be serious.
d.	You are way off base. (棒不在垒上)
e.	You don’t know up from down.
f.	Over my dead body.
g.	I wasn’t born yesterday.
h.	That’s ridiculous.
i.	It’s pure fiction.
j.	Non-sense!
k.	Bullshit!
l.	That’s out of the question!
          7.  骂人的话
a.	Shut up!
b.	Big mouth!
c.	Go to hell! Get out of here!
d.	You ask for it!
e.	Loss head
f.	Cheap skate! 小气鬼
g.	Banana! Nuts!
h.	Blast!
八、总结 内容见以前笔记。



</content>
<bookmark>350</bookmark>
</TextBean></TextList>