<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TextList>
<TextTemplate>
<name/>
<content/>
<bookmark/>
</TextTemplate>
<TextBean UUID="06e93567a71d428f93ebdba4f9ac0fbe">
<name>Senior C++ Engineer SAP</name>
<content>/ SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES
• MS in computer science or related majors
• Excellent OOA/OOD, design patterns, architectural knowledge
• Software infrastructure, middleware, technical platform and framework development
experience
• Familiar with at least one commercial DBMS with solid SQL programming skills
• Good communication skill with team member, can lead the team to match project
schedule and deadline
• Quick-learning, self-motivated and hard-working
• Good command of English (written &amp; oral) and communication skills
Beneficial Skills:
• Experience in statistic computing tools, such as MatLab, Project R, SPSS and SAS
• Experience in compiler/language runtime design
• Experience in .NET, Java, web application development
• Understanding of project management principles
• Global team working experience
WORK EXPERIENCE
• 5+ year's industry experience in software development and at least 1+ year as team
lead</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="214be954ef7b479482c32b879fe7774b">
<name>Senior Software Developer　DELL</name>
<content>Responsibility:
1.Systems software development
2.Understanding of business logics
3.Creating development documents
4.Developing and implementing business modules

Qualification:
- Computer science degree or an equivalent degree
- Strong ability to learn new technologies
- Good problem solving skills
- Excellent EN communicating skills
- Strong grasp of OOP programming
- Grasp of client server concepts and technologies
- Experience in project management
- Experience in J2EE and Web Service, JDBC, EJB, JSP, Servlet, Message Bean, Weblogic is a plus but not essential
- Experience in a high level programming language (e.g. ASP.NET /ADO.NET /Java/C#, etc.)
- Experience in database programming (e.g. SQL / Oracle, etc.)
- Experience on GUI design, JSF, MyEclipse
- Good understanding on software development processes</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="2776919c54884d5d91b4aefc56c15ef6">
<name>Senior Java Engineer</name>
<content>Job Description:

· To analyze requirements, write design or program specifications

· To code Java/J2EE applications to implement product features

· Communicate and work closely with peer developers

· Guide and support junior developers


Requirements:

· BS/MS degree in Computer Science or equivalent 

· At least 3 years experience of software development, experience in supervising a development team is an advantage

· Good command of speaking and writing English

· Be skilled at Core Java or J2EE technologies

· Be good at Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Design Patterns, familiar with UML

· Hands-on experience on J2EE frameworks like Spring, Hibernate, Struts and etc

· Be skilled at Oracle/Sybase DBMS development is required

· Be familiar with Unix environment and command

· Experience in Struts and Tiles is a plus

· Experience in software test is a plus

· Strong responsibility and flexibility under work pressure

· TOEIC - Certificate holders highly preferred
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="72bef5392b704709bcc120ef44045bd6">
<name>Database Support Engineer/Sr.engineer-urgent</name>
<content>RESPONSIBILITIES
1.Exercise strong technical expertise to respond to and solve customer issues;
2.Responds to incoming technical calls from both external and internal customers;
3.Constantly research, study, and keep in pace with Oracle Database new features and other related technologies;
4.Ensure the timely completion of planed proactive tasks and SRs.
5.Build and maintain strong relationships with customers;
6.Work collaboratively with team members
7.Create and maintain knowledge management content.

Qualifications
1.At least 5 years of Oracle Database experience (Candidate with lesser experience with be considered as support engineer)
2.A solid Database knowledge of Oracle RDBMS or other relational databases and a strong Database administration, tuning and trouble-shooting experience is required.
3.Experience with Linux, Unix or Windows as well as an exposure to SQL, PL/SQL and performance tuning is required.
3.A Computer Sciences, MIS, Science, IT or Engineering related degree is required.
4.Strong analytical skills and problem diagnostic experience, with the ability to consult customers on technical issues amongst technical and IT environmental ambiguity;
5.Strong communication skills and good English skill in both writing and speaking;
6.Self-motivated, able to work effectively with customers under pressure;
7.Ability to manage multiple priorities and ensure the timely completion of SRs and assigned tasks</content>
<bookmark>85</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="44b0117dbd0940c98e99bef2cf44b5e6">
<name>Senior Software Enginerr for Japan Project </name>
<content>Participates as a member of development team.


Completes development of units with designs prepared by more senior developers. 


Participates in code reviews. Prepares and executes unit tests. 


Applies growing technical knowledge to maintain a technology area (e.g. Web-site Development).  


May perform unit design. 


Applies HP and 3rd party technologies to software solutions of moderate complexity.


Configures end-user or enterprise systems designed by more senior technologists.


Performs work assigned by others.



Provides time / resource estimates for assigned tasks.







Education and Experience Required:
 

Typically a technical Bachelor's degree or equivalent experience and a minimum of 2 years of related experience or a Master's degree and up to two years of experience.

 


 

Knowledge and Skills:
 

2 or more years experience writing code using languages such as (and not limited to) COBOL, PL/1, Java, C, C++, C#, VB.Net. Basic Understanding of RDBMS databases such SQL Server and Oracle.  Basic understanding of modern software design and development methodologies (e.g., OO). Basic understanding of modern SCM (software configuration management).  
 
Basic understanding of testing tools and unit test scripting, and testing Methodologies. Experience using (or an understanding of the use of) an Integrated Development Environment (e.g., Eclipse, Visual Studio). Understanding of basic Database Administration. Understanding of quality and security standards. Good verbal and written communication skills.
</content>
<bookmark>137</bookmark>
</TextBean></TextList>