<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TextList>
<TextTemplate>
<name/>
<content/>
<bookmark/>
</TextTemplate>
<TextBean UUID="e349e8d397cb46fa88edd32afd6c4df8">
<name>0729 - Maradona</name>
<content>Buenos Aires, Argentina (CNN) -- Argentina's top soccer officials lied to and betrayed coach Diego Maradona in deciding not to renew his contract, he told reporters.

"Grondona lied to me; Bilardo betrayed me," said the 49-year-old former star player for Argentina's national team, referring to Argentine Football Association President Julio Grondona and AFA General Manager Carlos Bilardo.

Argentina's 4-0 loss to Germany in a quarterfinal match put the team out of the World Cup competition. After the team's elimination, according to Maradona, Grondona told him, "in the presence of witnesses and players, that he was very content with the work done and that he wanted it to continue."

But once the team returned to Argentina, "Grondona told me that he wanted me to continue as the coach, but that seven people from my coaching squad would have to go," Maradona said Wednesday. "That was impossible for me to agree to do."

He added, "I have different codes and morals than they do; my parents taught me that."

Maradona said that, "while we were in mourning, Bilardo was working in the shadows to throw me out."

I have different codes and morals than they do; my parents taught me that

--Diego Maradona, sacked Argentina national team coach
 
After reading from a prepared speech for 12 minutes, he left without taking questions as many of the assembled journalists applauded.

After meeting with officials at AFA headquarters in Buenos Aires, Grondona told reporters that he had not lied to Maradona. Though the two men had talked about change, "it was not my intention to open the exit door for him," he said.

He said he did not understand how Maradona could believe he was betrayed. "We were looking for some change, not to get rid of Maradona," he said.

Bilardo said he would respond next week to Maradona's accusations.
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="908715d8d0c0465f83fc9f23b1507003">
<name>0729 - Joint South Korea-U.S. drills enter fourth day</name>
<content>(CNN) -- The United States and South Korea on Wednesday plan to end their joint military exercises aimed at warning North Korea to stop acts of aggression.

The military exercises, dubbed Invincible Spirit, are in waters off South Korea. They include 8,000 personnel, 20 ships and submarines, and about 200 aircraft, officials said.

U.S. Defense Department officials said the drills are in response to the March sinking of the South Korean warship, Cheonan, which killed 46 South Korean sailors.

South Korea has said that an investigation concluded that a North Korean submarine fired a torpedo that sunk the South Korea warship, an assertion the North has denied.

The drills are intended to send a strong message to Pyongyang to stop "provocative and warlike acts," the U.S. Defense Department said.

The drills will include anti-sub infiltration exercises, said Cmdr. Jeff Davis of the U.S. 7th Fleet.

"The anti-sub-infiltration exercise works like this: if a sub is coming in to attack a ship, the military finds it and prosecutes it," he said.

Davis said there was a "renewed desire" and urgency to focus on the exercise after the Cheonan sinking. North Korea has criticized the exercises.

"The U.S. provocations amount to trespassing on the off-limits fixed by the DPRK and it, therefore, feels no need to remain bounded to the off-limits drawn by the U.S.," the state-run Korean Central News Agency quoted a North Korean foreign ministry spokesman as saying.

It continued, "It is the mode of the DPRK's counteraction to react to sword brandishing in kind. The DPRK is prepared for both dialogue and war. It will remain unfazed by military threat and sanctions."

Earlier, North Korea had heightened its threats against the military exercises.

North Korea "will legitimately counter with [its] powerful nuclear deterrence the largest-ever nuclear war exercises to be staged by the U.S. and the South Korean puppet forces," KCNA reported.

Democratic Sen. Carl Levin of Michigan downplayed the threats from North Korea. 

"I think North Korea is just too interested in their own survival to do anything that could end that regime," Levin said Sunday on C-SPAN's "Newsmakers" program. 

</content>
<bookmark>63</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="860868c0934c4227a3c19432a27f1121">
<name>0730 - This is not the end for Maradona</name>
<content>Much of Diego Maradona's life has seemed to play out at a different level to ordinary mortals, so it was no surprise that the announcement of his departure as Argentina coach was spiced with high drama.

Maradona raised the temperature by countering a bland statement from the Argentine football authorities that his contract had not been renewed (because of his refusal to countenance a change to some of his technical team,) with a visceral attack on his alleged enemies.

He accused national team director Carlos Bilardo of betrayal, and Julio Grondona, president of the Argentine Football Association, of being part of a conspiracy to unjustly oust him. 

Maradona: I was lied to and betrayed

There is nothing Diego likes more than to be placed in a situation where he can rally his believers round a claim of martyrdom by sinister powers. He did so when he was busted for drugs back in the early 1990s, and he did it again when he tested positive in the football World Cup in the U.S. in 1994.

He arrived at the World Cup in South Africa, already hitting back at all those journalists who had noted his apparent incompetence as a coach and predicting failure from the outset. Such antagonism fuels his popularity among the downtrodden and dispossessed. But I am not alone in believing his protests are actually an attempt to cover up his own professional and personal failings.

Maradona, in the end, badly let down his team of superstars

--Jimmy Burns
 

Video: Maradona sacked as coach 
RELATED TOPICS 
Diego Maradona 
Argentina 
World Cup Soccer 
If this were happening in another country, then the reason for Maradona's sacking should be plain. He may once have been a great player, and he brought us some entertainment in an otherwise rather dull World Cup in South Africa (La Roja's justified victory excluded,) but Argentina's thrashing by Germany exposed his shortcomings as a coach, and the lack of professionalism of some of his hand-picked advisers, which had been a subject of public debate for well over a year.

In the end, the myth of Diego's divinity -- the "hand of God" -- was brought crashing down by a German team that played better because they were coached better. The Argentinean team realized belatedly that Maradona's genius lay in personal instinct rather than in any system, and there was a limit to what that could achieve.

You may bring a smile to global TV audiences by kissing your players and dancing like a pogo stick each time your side scores a goal, but you need technique and strategy, not just inspiration, to win a championship, and Maradona, in the end, badly let down his team of superstars.

But then this is Argentina -- a country where politics and football make a potent mix. Maradona not only has a popular following among his country's more fanatical football fans, but continues to be looked at as a political vehicle by sectors of the populist government of Cristina Fernandes. Which is why I doubt this is the final chapter of the flawed genius's extraordinary life.

On the psychological front, there are testing times ahead for Maradona, and thus for the Argentine nation. His self-proclaimed dream was to coach his national team to World Cup victory. He failed in South Africa, but afterwards said he would do it, next time, when the tournament is played in neighboring Brazil.

Without the motivation that the coach's job provided, some of his fans fear he may return to the bad old days of depression, self abuse and intensifying paranoia.

The myth of Maradona's invincibility has been severely dented and may prove irrevocable. But he has been down before, and fought back. There will be more dramas ahead -- of that I am sure.

Comments:


1DesertEagle 
What a sad piece of journalism. When I look at your photo Jimmy Burns, I see a bitter face. You seem to be the kind of person who's shooting down others as a way of therapy for your own depression. Maradona is a very likable man - to link this trait to the longings of the downtrodden and dispossesse... more 
What a sad piece of journalism. When I look at your photo Jimmy Burns, I see a bitter face. You seem to be the kind of person who's shooting down others as a way of therapy for your own depression. Maradona is a very likable man - to link this trait to the longings of the downtrodden and dispossessed only shows your own. You are a disgrace to your profession. less 
2 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
scoob1e 
Brazil will win the 2014 World Cup in their own country. And they will do so with Maradona as their coach. And the final match? You guessed it. Brazil vs. Argentina, where Brazil will win in a historic 5-0 victory. Maradona will then run naked through the streets of Buenos Aires, holding his hairy b... more 
Brazil will win the 2014 World Cup in their own country. And they will do so with Maradona as their coach. And the final match? You guessed it. Brazil vs. Argentina, where Brazil will win in a historic 5-0 victory. Maradona will then run naked through the streets of Buenos Aires, holding his hairy balls and screaming loudly "Eat this! I told you so!" less 
7 hours ago | Like (8) | Report abuse 
 
SupermanEX Please no, not naked please. Maybe 10-15 years ago..sure, run naked, but not now, please no... 
4 hours ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
SZimmerman "This is not the end for Diego Maradona." Mr. Burns, for the good of the game, specially in Argentina, I hope your statement is incorrect.. 
9 hours ago | Like (10) | Report abuse 
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="cc19a91befb743ac9d6adb64ca912cff">
<name>0730 - Chinese prot burns for 15 hours ater pipeline blasts</name>
<content>A pair of oil pipeline blasts engulfed a Chinese port in flames for 15 hours before firefighters were able to extinguish the blaze, state-run media reported.

The fire was far from residential areas and no casualties were reported, government spokesman in the northeastern coastal city of Dalian told the Xinhua news agency.

More than 2,000 firefighters and 338 fire engines from 14 cities across Liaoning province worked through the night to put out the fire, Xinhua said.

Comments:

TheInsideMan 
dclayt1, again you aren't addressing my points you're just making a personal attack. Here's a little background for ya. I'm a veteran that has served our nation. I've also lived in China and have done business there for more than a decade. How about you? Ever made the trip or are you trying to argu... more 
dclayt1, again you aren't addressing my points you're just making a personal attack. Here's a little background for ya. I'm a veteran that has served our nation. I've also lived in China and have done business there for more than a decade. How about you? Ever made the trip or are you trying to argue that which you know nothing about? Chinese people are free to gather in groups and meditate whenever they like without fear of death or torture. In fact, if you go to just about any city park at 6am you'll find thousands of people doing just that. Chinese people have more rights than you know and are free to litigate legal disagreements and wrongs just like we are. They are also free to work hard, pay taxes and work toward public servant positions just like we are. It's the system that is different and your misunderstanding on how that system works that gives rise to your fears of it. As to the kicking down of doors thing you mentioned how about Ruby Ridge? It's OK you don't have to answer. I'm done arguing to try to help raise you up... All your bases are belong to me! less 
1 week ago | Like (23) | Report abuse  
TheInsideMan 
For the uninformed dclayt1,Your calling China a ruthless communist dictatorship just proves my point and takes focus away from the issue. And for my comparing it to a free and open society - I said no such thing. I would never be so naive as to believe ours is a free and open society (The Patriot Ac... more 
For the uninformed dclayt1,
Your calling China a ruthless communist dictatorship just proves my point and takes focus away from the issue. And for my comparing it to a free and open society - I said no such thing. I would never be so naive as to believe ours is a free and open society (The Patriot Act, Free Speech Zones, need I go on?). If you want to heckle me at least argue against my points with something that floats. I just sank your battleship. less 
1 week ago | Like (8) | Report abuse 
 
dclayt1 
The only thing you know less about China is about Western society. You have legal rights. You can vote. You can run for office. If the police smash down your door you can sue and defend yourself. If you don't like the Patriot Act you can vote for a party that will change it. For that matter yo... more 
The only thing you know less about China is about Western society. You have legal rights. You can vote. You can run for office. If the police smash down your door you can sue and defend yourself. If you don't like the Patriot Act you can vote for a party that will change it. For that matter you can run for office and change it yourself.

The Chinese have none of that. It is not even known how they select their PM. If the police smash down their door and steal their property they have no rights. If the try to get together in a group to meditate they are tortued to death.

You are a fool and lack any appreciation for the freedoms you have. less 
1 week ago | Like (6) | Report abuse 
 
Cenfl When will we be able to stop Bush from starting fires in China? The guy is out of control. Fortunately, Obama will stop it. It will be on CSPAN because he's transparent. He said so. 
1 week ago | Like (5) | Report abuse  
TheInsideMan 
What saddens me more than the worldwide ecological suffering we're going through these days is the sheer number of uninformed people sharing fear-mongering opinions. You can't apply one countries standards to another, that's apples and oranges. Surely it's naive to think our own governments report t... more 
What saddens me more than the worldwide ecological suffering we're going through these days is the sheer number of uninformed people sharing fear-mongering opinions. You can't apply one countries standards to another, that's apples and oranges. Surely it's naive to think our own governments report the truth,the whole truth and nothing but the truth. What's the difference between our governments using the media to fuel the desired public opinion and China choosing not to report the darker sides of some issues? Seems like the semantics of social engineering to me. China's policies regarding news media and it's control were put in place to help ensure a harmonious society. Chinese people are passionate and quick tempered. Showing blood and death doesn't always serve the best interests of the people, least of all those that have fallen. Rest assured those that died will be duly honored by their families privately. A public spectacle or a private memorial? Think about your own family and what you'd rather have. 
If people spent more time trying to find things to do to get people to look up to them rather than trying to find a reason to look down on others, imagine what the world could achieve. Sitting behind the illusion of anonymity that the internet provides is empowering. It seems such a shame that it's so often used to propagate misunderstanding and hate. We should celebrate and enjoy our differences now as the world would be so incredibly boring were we are all cookie-cutter clones battered in consumerism and deep-fried in a singular political dogma. less 
1 week ago | Like (8) | Report abuse 
 
dclayt1 
China's policies regarding news media and its control were put in place to ensure the Chinese government remains in power.Your attempt to compare a ruthless communist dictatorship to a free and open society is ridiculous. You have the choice to ignore the media and render your own decisions. The C... more 
China's policies regarding news media and its control were put in place to ensure the Chinese government remains in power.

Your attempt to compare a ruthless communist dictatorship to a free and open society is ridiculous. You have the choice to ignore the media and render your own decisions. The Chinese have no choice. less 
1 week ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
TouchingName Don't stand up high and ridicule someone who's taking effort heading toward the pinnacle! 
1 week ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
RichPhitswel Why are they using water and not the foam, that we use to fight oil and gas fires, that's made there? 
1 week ago | Like | Report abuse  
AshannaK China has a fire. America has an oil spill. I would ask, 'What next'? But i don't'
want to know. 
1 week ago | Like (4) | Report abuse  
guest06660 Well there goes China's aircraft carrier, the Varyag.

Maybe our seals from one of our subs had a successful mission? 
1 week ago | Like (3) | Report abuse 
 
dclayt1 Haha, like anyone had to take a shot at that old piece of crap. Even the Russians don't want that junk.

The pride of the Chinese navy! LOL 
1 week ago | Like (4) | Report abuse 
 
UmpireSamson read it to me again How many fire trucks are in this town ??

and this is at a port ? dont they have any fire boats ?? 
1 week ago | Like | Report abuse  
Larson1995 i wonder who is going down for this? 
1 week ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
zunedog if obama wasnt screwing around in maine, he could have stoppped this fire,oh no wait, that was the gulf oil well, bet he is glad thats over with, great ice cream cheif. 
1 week ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
LiberalNN Bush's fault. Totally Bush's fault. 
1 week ago | Like (10) | Report abuse  
TerrXL 
@ molarbandChina will catch up soon. Believe me, people are buying cars like candy. I see more people driving gas guzzling SUVs in China than I do in L.A. Not to mention the fact that nobody recycles and everyone has air conditioning units. When Beijing was bidding for the Olympics and the committee... more 
@ molarband

China will catch up soon. Believe me, people are buying cars like candy. I see more people driving gas guzzling SUVs in China than I do in L.A. Not to mention the fact that nobody recycles and everyone has air conditioning units. When Beijing was bidding for the Olympics and the committee visited, they had rolling power cuts throughout the city in order to clear the layer of smog that blocks out the blue sky. Trust me, the sky is not something you ever get to see in any Chinese city. 

This isn't a competition. It's not a larger or smaller disaster than the one in the Gulf. These two isolated incidents should only serve as a cautionary tale: that industry always comes at a price. I wonder how long and how much we're willing to pay before we come to our senses. less 
1 week ago | Like (17) | Report abuse  
Jephtastic Sabotage. 
1 week ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
em2onthemix I'm sure republicans are going to blame Obama for this one too. 
1 week ago | Like (11) | Report abuse 
 
Reality678 Lol yea 
1 week ago | Like | Report abuse  
acai And why shouldn't Republicans blame Obama? After all, it was Obama's ill-advised, failed amusement park policies that got us into this situation to begin with. The Spaniards must feel totally like pawns in the great game of life. 
1 week ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
clstevens It's great how both the Bush and Obama worshiping idiots make this same comment on just about every news story.
Get a life you losers. 
1 week ago | Like (15) | Report abuse  
misterMaker colowest, you forgot to mention farting after eating baked beans. I blame Obama for that too. 
1 week ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
colowest 
em2onthemix,of COURSE Obama's responsible! EVERYTHING is his fault! Extinction of the dinosaurs, the Ice Age, Global warming, WWI, WWII, the war in Iraq, Sputnik, the sinking of the Titanic, thunderstorms, tornadoes, hurricanes, droughts, heat waves, cold waves, the Deep Horizons disaster, plagues o... more 
em2onthemix,of COURSE Obama's responsible! EVERYTHING is his fault! Extinction of the dinosaurs, the Ice Age, Global warming, WWI, WWII, the war in Iraq, Sputnik, the sinking of the Titanic, thunderstorms, tornadoes, hurricanes, droughts, heat waves, cold waves, the Deep Horizons disaster, plagues of locusts, just plain plague, flat tires, the Great Recession, hell the Great Depression....

There might be something that isn't his fault but I sure can't think of what it might be!

Thank God for Barack Obama -- if it weren't for him something, although I can't imagine what, might actually be our fault! 

A proud Republican less 
1 week ago | Like (27) | Report abuse 
 
TimothyCrowe And this just happened to occur so soon after BP stats to make decent progress in the gulf. Or were both planned events to intimidate the people of super-nations. No one yells "TERROREST" when the Elitists authorize the fear-mongering. But no, my TSA-unauthorized 20 OZ coke is defiantly a weapon. 
1 week ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
molarband 
The United States just created one of the biggest oil disasters in the world and you are still trying to criticize China about pollution??? Seriously The USA has only 1/4 the population of China but still produces more pollution than China. Americans are too lazy to drive and rely on their fat gas... more 
The United States just created one of the biggest oil disasters in the world and you are still trying to criticize China about pollution??? Seriously The USA has only 1/4 the population of China but still produces more pollution than China. Americans are too lazy to drive and rely on their fat gas guzzling SUV to go down the block. Seriously get off your moral high ground and look at yourself in the mirror. less 
1 week ago | Like (54) | Report abuse 
</content>
<bookmark>207</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="2e150711764a4885b0a607f0326e6a77">
<name>0730 - When phones are too big for pockets</name>
<content>(CNN) -- Something weird is happening to mobile phones: After shrinking from enormous Zack Morris proportions in the '80s and '90s, they're getting bigger again.

So big, in fact, that some won't fit in jeans pockets anymore.

The Dell Streak, which is set to be released in the U.S. later this summer, is the biggest of the big-daddy phones so far, with a 5-inch screen. The screen of the iPhone 4, by comparison, measures only 3.5 inches diagonally.

When held up to a person's ear, the Dell phone looks like a book.

The Streak's mondo screen has become the focus of much debate on the internet, with tech bloggers arguing about what kinds of pants you'd have to wear to carry it around in your pocket; how big your hands have to be to hold it; whether or not people will stare at you when you're using it; and, perhaps most significantly, what exactly constitutes a phone these days.

Is a phone just any device that can make calls? Or does it have to be portable enough to carry with you, regardless of how baggy your pants are?

As mobile phone technology improved, "there definitely was a trend for smaller and there definitely was a trend for thinner," said Ramon Llamas, a senior research analyst who covers mobile technology for IDC. "But I think we're seeing the pendulum swinging back in favor of larger phones."

Mobile phone makers are trying to "push the boundaries of what is acceptable in a pocket," said Ross Rubin, executive director of industry analysis for consumer technology at the NPD Group.

Several Android phones -- which run on an operating system developed by Google, as opposed to those by Microsoft or Apple -- have come out with screens that are larger than 4 inches diagonally.

The HTC Evo and the Motoroloa Droid X, for example, both have 4.3-inch screens. Sony Ericsson is rumored, according to the blog Engadget, to be working on another 5-inch smartphone, the same size as the Dell Streak. (As a side note, the HTC Evo is so big that it comes with a kickstand).

In video reviews of these ever-larger phones, it seems almost to be a requirement these days for tech pundits to try to shove the things in their pockets as a way to determine whether the devices are truly portable.

In one such video, Veronica Belmont, co-host of a video show called Tekzilla, puts the Dell Streak in the front pocket of her pants only to find that about a third of the phone is still sticking out.

One YouTube video, titled "Dell Streak vs. Jeans," starts with a shot of a man's waist line, shown only from the thighs to mid-belly.

"The reason you're staring at my hips is that I'm going to show you what the Dell Streak is like, fitting in a jeans pocket," the host says. "Now, these jeans have got quite a deep pocket and, even still, it pokes out a little bit over the top. You can tuck it right in and there's still a corner coming out at the top there."

The man then proceeds to stuff the Streak into his back pocket, which he decides isn't such a good idea, either. 

It sticks out, which could make it easily accessible to pickpockets, he says. "And you're certainly not going to want to sit on it."

Dell did not return CNN's phone calls about this story.

The other potential issue with large phones is that it can be difficult to hold them up to your face, depending how big your hands are and if your arms are strong.

When Chris Hall tested the Dell Streak for the British website Pocket-lint, he said his hand literally became tired and stretched-out from holding the phone.

He said he also got some stares from strangers.

"People are going to look at you in a funny way" when you're holding such a large gadget up to your face, he said.

Hall still gave the phone -- which is sometimes referred to as a small "tablet" computer rather than a large phone -- a good rating: 8 of 10 stars.

In a video review for the blog Engadget, Richard Lai takes a bit of a contrarian view, saying the Dell Streak is still small enough to carry comfortably in a standard pant pocket.

"Obviously you see a bit of bulge here," he says after putting the phone in his jeans pocket, "but you get that with any phones these days, really, you know? Sliding it in and out is no problem, you see?"

Lai does note, however, that, if you want to walk up a flight of stairs with the 5-inch phone in your pocket, you should "shift your phone as far to the side [of your pocket] as possible" in order to maintain a normal range of movement.

"But other than that we've had no real issues with it," he says.

Despite some fuss about the bulk of these 4- and 5-inch phones, there are some clear advantages to screens with more real estate. 

As phones increasingly become internet portals, e-book readers and video players, having bigger screens makes them more useful, Llamas said.

Those functions are butting up against some long-held ideas about what a mobile phone is -- namely that it's a gadget that you can easily carry in a pocket and hold to your ear to make a call.

So maybe we need a new cell phone definition: 

One that can fit in your cargo shorts.

Comments :

scrumbugulus 7 inches in the pants isn't too uncomfortable, so 5 inches shouldn't be too bad. 
15 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
Kimanje 
There is a time when I craved for the smallest phones on the market. But that was when the phone was only about calls and SMS"es". Now our expectations from a mobile phone have become almost insatiable. We want the world at our finger tips wherever we are. And whichever way you look at it, the trade... more 
There is a time when I craved for the smallest phones on the market. But that was when the phone was only about calls and SMS"es". Now our expectations from a mobile phone have become almost insatiable. We want the world at our finger tips wherever we are. And whichever way you look at it, the trade off has to be size. For a little bigger size, you virtually have a portable, pocket friendly palm PC that can also make calls in your hands. Wih the current technology, we will stay with bigger phones for a while and there will not be many complaints. less 
15 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Bodatheyoda or you use your phone for texting and calls...maybe some music. And use your TV for movies. Juss saying... 
27 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
krotch 
The Dell Streak is meant to be inbetween a tablet and smartphone. Personally, a stupid idea to me, but whatever works for them. I would have much preferred the Streak as a dual core Atom system with 2 gig ram, 32 gig SSD, and a mini-SD slot, all running Win7. Oh well, guess just have to keep waiting... more 
The Dell Streak is meant to be inbetween a tablet and smartphone. Personally, a stupid idea to me, but whatever works for them. I would have much preferred the Streak as a dual core Atom system with 2 gig ram, 32 gig SSD, and a mini-SD slot, all running Win7. Oh well, guess just have to keep waiting for the Win7 slates to show up. less 
41 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Davidg55 
Um... if the phone is too big for you, try buying a different model. No one is forcing you to buy a superphone, but if i'm gonna plop down the money for a phone with an 8mp camera and a 1ghz processor and all the other bells and whistles available, i also want a good sized screen to be able to use i... more 
Um... if the phone is too big for you, try buying a different model. No one is forcing you to buy a superphone, but if i'm gonna plop down the money for a phone with an 8mp camera and a 1ghz processor and all the other bells and whistles available, i also want a good sized screen to be able to use it. its not as though they have stopped making smaller phones, they just offering bigger ones. Also the HTC Evo doesnt have a kickstand because its so big, it has a kickstand so you can stand it up and watch video on it. What a pointless article. 

And Veronica is the first woman over the age of 13 Ive seen who carries a phone in her pocket. then again from the look of the faded brown jeans and baggy grey t-shirt she is wearing, looking good clearly isnt a concern. Why not just go fully lumberjack and buy some cargo pants Veronica?
Women's wallets are too big for their pockets and I never see any key bulges in jean pockets either. Where is the article on keys and wallets being too big? Heck half the womens pants out their dont even have real pockets, so it seems a nonissue. If you are a man and your phone wont fit in your pocket, buy some looser jeans. less 
41 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Zooom @rohuezo: I definitely agree with you. And I think the computer manufactures will make their mobiles smaller as they are trying to grasp at on opportunity to compete with the mobiles phone manufactures. 
44 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Davidg55 
These companies arent stupid, they are giving the people what they want. I sell cellphones and the Evo and Droid X are by far the two most requested phones for the past month. People dont want small cell phones. Play around with an HTC evo and you will quickly find your concerns of "this is too big"... more 
These companies arent stupid, they are giving the people what they want. I sell cellphones and the Evo and Droid X are by far the two most requested phones for the past month. People dont want small cell phones. Play around with an HTC evo and you will quickly find your concerns of "this is too big" turning into "i want one." If you are going to make a phone powerful enough to run full out applications and record 720p hd video, you probably want a good sized screen to interact with it.

That said, I think 4.5in is about maximum you can go before your phone turns into a pda or tablet. less 
26 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
llapierre 
" (As a side note, the HTC Evo is so big that it comes with a kickstand)" As another side note, I would like to point out that CNN is biased toward almost any phone BUT the POS iPhone 4. If the Mr. Sutter did ANY research before writing, he would have seen that HTC puts kickstands on many of their p... more 
" (As a side note, the HTC Evo is so big that it comes with a kickstand)" As another side note, I would like to point out that CNN is biased toward almost any phone BUT the POS iPhone 4. If the Mr. Sutter did ANY research before writing, he would have seen that HTC puts kickstands on many of their phones. less 
50 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
deepwater805 When I get my new Dell Streak I'm gonna carry it inside my pants, but not in the back.... 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse  
rohuezo 
The only mobile phones getting bigger are the ones coming from computer manufacturers trying to grab a share at the mobile phone market and manufacturing such huge phones to accomodate the "hardware" they are familiar with. Real mobile phone manufacturers (Nokia, Sony Erickson, etc) use their experi... more 
The only mobile phones getting bigger are the ones coming from computer manufacturers trying to grab a share at the mobile phone market and manufacturing such huge phones to accomodate the "hardware" they are familiar with. 
Real mobile phone manufacturers (Nokia, Sony Erickson, etc) use their experience gained through out the years and have thin, small mobile phones. Their smartphones are certainly larger than their normal mobiles, but still at an acceptable size.

I think the computer manufacturers have to gather also the experience just as the mobile manufacturers did. less 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Davidg55 
How about the HTC evo and HD2 (HTC being a phone company,) the Motorolla Droid X (motorolla being a phone company,) the Samsung Galaxy s line, etc. The "Real" mobile phone manufacturers you refer to seem to be lagging behind in offering robust smartphones that can compete with android. Economics sug... more 
How about the HTC evo and HD2 (HTC being a phone company,) the Motorolla Droid X (motorolla being a phone company,) the Samsung Galaxy s line, etc. 

The "Real" mobile phone manufacturers you refer to seem to be lagging behind in offering robust smartphones that can compete with android. Economics suggests that if a product exists and is successful, its due to the market demanding it. Seeing as sprint and Verizon cant keep up with demand for their 4.3 inch screened smartphones (evo and droid x,) it would appear that a large phone is actually what most premium users want. less 
30 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Madibaman27 Get the dell out of my pants! 
1 hour ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
iflexs the phone is not big its just that the pockets of our pants are too small. solution: bigger pocket. then we can all jump to the river with weights in our pockets. 
3 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
juliotx well, thats why they invented the bluetooth headset. 
4 hours ago | Like (4) | Report abuse 
 
Keith1952 They invented the headset for old Star Trek fans, or for people with no children to make fun of you. 
3 hours ago | Like (3) | Report abuse 
 
ibook900 I think the problem is 2fold. One, phones are trying too much and failing at it by being too large in size. Also, what;s with the afterthought of a pocket most pants have today, especially on women's clothing? Pockets are needed, and should be practical in real life.

- A 
4 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
SwimTiger Well if the smartphones are getting larger....that only means one thing....The user start losing some fat...and you know who you are. 
4 hours ago | Like (5) | Report abuse  
Hoan Dell is Hell! 
4 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
MelDoug I love this article. CNN is Apple's lil lapdog 
6 hours ago | Like (5) | Report abuse 
 
llapierre That the word I was looking for! :D 
45 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
passerby55 the phones are not getting any bigger, is our pockets are getting smaller. 
6 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
KillerMike I can stuff a PSP in my pocket without any trouble. How can a phone possibly need to be any larger than that? 
7 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
freqengine smart phones = dumb computer 
7 hours ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
briank11 Once again, Dell is on the cutting edge of nothing. 
7 hours ago | Like (17) | Report abuse 
 
Davidg55 Im not a fan of dell computers, but they do make some pretty sick phones. Ever tried one? I'm guessing not. 
24 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse </content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="5f0ae0b91759437a9bd5beaaf2da9eb1">
<name>0803 - U.S. drawdown in Iraq proceeding as planned</name>
<content>Atlanta, Georgia (CNN) -- The Obama administration's planned drawdown of U.S. troops from Iraq is proceeding "as promised" and should lead to an end of America's combat mission there by the end of August, President Barack Obama said Monday.

Plans to reduce the number of U.S. troops in Iraq to 50,000 by the end of this month are on schedule, Obama told the national convention of Disabled American Veterans. At that point, the U.S. mission will shift to the training and support of Iraqi security forces.

A full withdrawal of American troops from Iraq is scheduled to occur by the end of next year.

The war in Iraq "is nearing an end," he said. "As a candidate for president, I pledged to bring the war in Iraq to a responsible end. And that is exactly what we are doing."

While the U.S. military commitment in Iraq is now nearing a conclusion, the president warned, there is still danger there for U.S. troops on the ground. 



Video: Obama to vets: Country needs you 
RELATED TOPICS 
Barack Obama 
Iraq 
Iraq War 
Disabled American Veterans 
"The hard truth is we have not seen the end of American sacrifice in Iraq," Obama said. "But make no mistake, our commitment in Iraq is changing -- from a military effort led by our troops to a civilian effort led by our diplomats."

Obama's update on the conflict in Iraq came in the context of a wide-ranging speech addressing several issues tied to national security and veterans' benefits.

Obama defended his decision to increase U.S. military commitment in Afghanistan -- a decision criticized by some of the more liberal members of his own party. He said the military has now gone on the offensive against extremist elements, and took issue with critics who claim the U.S. end game in Afghanistan remains poorly defined.

"We face huge challenges in Afghanistan," he said. "But it's important that the American people know that we are making progress and we're focused on goals that are clear and achievable."

"If Afghanistan were to be engulfed by an even wider insurgency, al Qaeda and its terrorist affiliates would have even more space to plan their next attack." 

"As president of the United States, I refuse to let that happen," he said.

The Pakistan government has begun to "take the fight to violent extremists within its borders. Major blows have been struck against al Qaeda and its leadership," Obama said.

On Iraq, the president provided a largely optimistic assessment of the U.S. effort, saying violence there is currently "near the lowest it's been in years."

But Iraqi officials released data Saturday that they said shows July was the deadliest month for civilians since May 2008, reporting that 396 civilians, 50 Iraqi soldiers and 89 police officers were killed. Iraqi officials also said 100 so-called "terrorists" were killed, and 955 others were detained.

The U.S. military has disputed the Iraqi figures, saying the actual numbers are less than half what Iraq's government reported.

The U.S. command in Baghdad, Iraq, "refutes that 535 people were killed in Iraq during the month of July," the military said in a statement Sunday. It put the total number of people killed by "enemy action" at 222, including 161 civilians, 55 Iraqi troops and six Americans -- the ninth-lowest civilian casualty count since January 2008, according to the U.S. military.

The U.S. military has said it believes Iraqi security forces can maintain current levels of relative stability, but that sentiment is not shared by many Iraqis.

Former Iraqi Prime Minister Ayad Allawi said in a recent interview with CNN that he is concerned that "the security is declining ... [and] that's why we need really good resolutions, we need to expedite the formation of a government and we need to create an understanding in the region, and we need the help of the United States to facilitate all of these issues through its good offices in Iraq and elsewhere in the region."

Starting in September, the number of U.S. troops in Iraq -- 50,000 -- will be almost a third of the total number there when Obama took office in January 2009, the White House has said. There will be 96,000 U.S. troops on the ground in Afghanistan -- more than three times the number there at the beginning of Obama's term.

In July, there were 81,000 U.S. troops in Iraq and 87,000 in Afghanistan.

While there is sharp public division over the U.S. effort in Afghanistan, Americans largely support the removal of U.S. forces from Iraq. Nearly two-thirds of all Americans back the administration's plan to remove most troops by the end of August, according to a May 21-23 CNN/Opinion Research Corporation poll. 

Only 36 percent of Americans favor the war in Iraq, the survey indicated.

Obama offered praise Monday for all the veterans of major U.S. military conflicts since World War II.

"In the life of our nation, not every generation has been summoned to defend our country in its hour of need. But every generation to answer that call has done so with honor and courage," he told the enthusiastic crowd.

The president ran through a litany of administration initiatives for military veterans, including "dramatically increased funding for veterans health care across the board."

Among the initiatives he highlighted: an increased use of electronic record-keeping that will allow veterans, for the first time, to go to the VA's website and download or print personal health records "so you have them when you need them and can share them with your doctors outside the VA." 

The new measure will take effect this fall, he said.

Comments :

parrotnsun I WONDER IF JOHN MC CAINS "COJONES" WERE LEFT IN VIETNAM? 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
jammies62 Mark Williams, Andrew Breibart, Sarah "Saint" Palin, Rand Paul, tea baggies all!
Love it!
Keep up the good work!
You are saving the dems millions in advertising! 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Woodstock1 O.k now what about all of those other campaign promises? What about the re-appeal of the Homlend Nazi Act. 
4 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
luvtigbittie 
You are foolish.. Arizona isn't having it's police officers round up illegals and throwing them into ovens dbag.. Illegals don't have any rights Americans do and what Arizona is enforcing is not inhumane.. Racial Profiling might be wrong but it isn't comparable to the genocide of Jews. How else are... more 
You are foolish.. Arizona isn't having it's police officers round up illegals and throwing them into ovens dbag.. Illegals don't have any rights Americans do and what Arizona is enforcing is not inhumane.. Racial Profiling might be wrong but it isn't comparable to the genocide of Jews. How else are we supposed to identify illegal immigrants living within the country that are wrongly protected by our Constitution? less 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
einna I would have liked him to repeal most parts of it, too, but he ran into issues with it. He extended them for a year, I think. Read politifact and see the number of promises he has kept, etc. 
2 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Bibico 
"...a civilian effort led by our diplomats..."Uh, don't forget the tens of thousands of "contractors" (mercenaries) who have been used in quasi-combat roles for years now, allowing us to appear to have a smaller military presence. They will still be there, killing and being killed, but not shown as ... more 
"...a civilian effort led by our diplomats..."

Uh, don't forget the tens of thousands of "contractors" (mercenaries) who have been used in quasi-combat roles for years now, allowing us to appear to have a smaller military presence. They will still be there, killing and being killed, but not shown as "combat" related casualties. When the funding for them is finally cut off, you can safely assume that anarchy and civil war are right around the corner, and a new generation of terrorists will have a safe haven. This "war" is reaching nothing like a successful conclusion.
Don't get me wrong, I'm glad we'll finally be done with it, and I'll be totally relieved when we conduct the same graceful abandonment...er....drawdown in Afghanistan. I hope this is the last time we make this sort of mistake, but since we heard there'd never be another Vietnam we can probably assume this is a mistake this country will continue to make. less 
8 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
flushlimbal quasi-combat roles? heck the men i know working there were rebuilding a palace , whats up with that , why not build hospitals there ? after all republicans are world socialist ( prefers building other countries instead of ours ) 
1 minute ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
luvtigbittie I guarantee G. Bush pays people to go on blog sites and have them spread B.S. about him to make him look better or to change the sore subjects he has manufactured 
9 minutes ago | Like (1) | Report abuse 
 
heathey2 Obama is the saint that we have all been searching for. Bush was such an evil man that I honestly don't understand how he can sleep at night being so guilt ridden and all that. 
2 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Notoj 
OK I'll post this again Bush did "NOT" start the withdrawl plan. It is just another Republican lie to make a bad party save some face. For you non researching brainwashed republicans here is the article from the New York Times, July 19th 2008, "Bush, in a Shift, Accepts Concept of Iraq Timeline" Sum... more 
OK I'll post this again Bush did "NOT" start the withdrawl plan. It is just another Republican lie to make a bad party save some face. For you non researching brainwashed republicans here is the article from the New York Times, July 19th 2008, "Bush, in a Shift, Accepts Concept of Iraq Timeline" Summary Senator Barack Obama, pushing a 16 month timeline if he was elected forced Bush into agreeing with setting a timeline was a good idea but was vague. less 
9 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
StanleyRW He was responsible for starting the bs war and was responsible for setting the stage for the oil spill.

You don't give someone credit for making a mess and then cleaning it up a little. 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Georges93 Bad party? That is you subjective opinion. You get to have your opinion, but you do seem pretty closed minded and generalizing of the majority of your American family and friends. 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Notoj 
@heathey2 Who was in power when these oil drilling contracts where signed with no safety plan required. I'll give you a hint his name rhymes with W. Do you think it was coincidence that Haliburton got the cementing contract. I know Obama is smart but can he invent technologies needed but non existen... more 
@heathey2 Who was in power when these oil drilling contracts where signed with no safety plan required. I'll give you a hint his name rhymes with W. Do you think it was coincidence that Haliburton got the cementing contract. I know Obama is smart but can he invent technologies needed but non existent or equipment that had to be made specialy for the spill. Your emotions have the best of you and facts seem to fly bye to fast for you to suck them in. One second your party is gouverment stay out of our way and the moment a problem happens it's where is the gouverment. less 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
einna heathy, may i suggest that you look up and learn the definitions of liberal, democrat, conservative and republican? you constantly misuse them, and therefore become increasingly uncredible. 
1 minute ago | Like | Report abuse  
Mike501 
16 months was last May. Obama missed big as there were still 90,000 troops there in May and 70,000 today. Bush negotiated the final withdrawal date of Dec 31 2011. These are all facts. Had Obama followed HIS plan, all troops would have been out 3 months ago, and the country would be in chaos. B... more 
16 months was last May. Obama missed big as there were still 90,000 troops there in May and 70,000 today. Bush negotiated the final withdrawal date of Dec 31 2011. These are all facts. Had Obama followed HIS plan, all troops would have been out 3 months ago, and the country would be in chaos. Bush DID start drawing down the surge troops before he left office. Another fact you ignore. less 
1 minute ago | Like | Report abuse  
heathey2 
You want to talk about saving face. It's been such a glorious year for the Liberals with the handling of the oil spill and the continuing debt that they feel the need to try and use this story as a personal victory. The invasion happened under Bush and he was responsible for most of the difficult mi... more 
You want to talk about saving face. It's been such a glorious year for the Liberals with the handling of the oil spill and the continuing debt that they feel the need to try and use this story as a personal victory. The invasion happened under Bush and he was responsible for most of the difficult missions. Liberals can't take credit for this. less 
5 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
jammies62 I see Tetuben is trolling as George93 again...
Tetuben must be a little bit red faced from his "hit the post button 25 times" the other night.
Step away from the scotch bottle Tetuben.... 
12 minutes ago | Like (1) | Report abuse 
 
Georges93 I think you must be a teenager. There are real people in this country who have something real to say and think every once in a while. 
7 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
IndianTrojan chuck norris will remain in Iraq though. 
14 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
jammies62 @heathey2-
Cough, cough...
Tea baggie covering up the racism with a very thin veneer of fiscal conservativism..
Cough, cough, spit...
Ahem... 
17 minutes ago | Like (4) | Report abuse 
 
StanleyRW Every country is bailing out the banks. It's a necessity. Letting the banks fail would have demolished our economy. 
2 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Georges93 Paulson and Pres. Bush were wrong with the bank bail outs and TARP. Nothing is too big to fail. Two wrongs don't make a right. 
8 minutes ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
itscion You sound like a skipping CD. I think you need to fire your writers or pay them more. 
12 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
StanleyRW Your association with the Teabaggers perhaps...

Much the same that I can infer that a fundementalist Muslim is a terrorist. 

Sure, they all aren't but they very well could be which usually is enough to label you.

Better to label you and be wrong than ignore you and let you wreak havoc. 
13 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Georges93 
Do you really truly believe that your neighbors are racists? You discredit our nation and the progress we have been over the many years. Why do you want to drag us back to the dark days before freedom? Each time you bandy about "racist" you diminish the real episodes of racism that are languishin... more 
Do you really truly believe that your neighbors are racists? You discredit our nation and the progress we have been over the many years. Why do you want to drag us back to the dark days before freedom? Each time you bandy about "racist" you diminish the real episodes of racism that are languishing out there and hurting real people. It may be fun for you and a joke, but there are real people whom it does really effect. less 
</content>
<bookmark>1386</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="765e79e5ca7349d29dd265b846c03877">
<name>0804 - Gunman suspected of killing 8 had just been forced to resign</name>
<content>Manchester, Connecticut (CNN) -- Omar Thornton, 34, walked into a room early Tuesday at the beverage distributorship where he worked in Manchester, Connecticut. 

Company and union officials played a video. He calmly watched images that purportedly showed him stealing from a truck.

An employee of Hartford Distributors for two years and a driver for one, Thornton was given a choice of resigning or being fired, union and company officials said.

He signed a resignation paper, was escorted out of the room and toward the door. He asked for a drink of water, company CEO Ross Hollander told CNN. That's when all hell broke loose. Thornton pulled out a handgun and began firing, officials said.

Within minutes, the gunman and eight other people were dead, and two others were wounded, according to Manchester police and a union official. Police swarmed to the scene, but never had a chance to talk with Thornton, who apparently shot himself to death in an office.

The shootings left the company, city and state in shock. Relatives and acquaintances said Thornton was known for his calm demeanor.

"My heart and prayers go out to the employees and families of the victims," Gov. M. Jodi Rell said in a statement. "In the wake of this tragedy, we are all left asking the same questions: How could someone do this? Why did they do this? It was a senseless act of violence that has left us all shaken. ..."



Video: Workplace shooting in Connecticut As police investigate the shootings and prepare to identify its victims, the company will meet with employees, some of whom have been with Hartford for 30-40 years.

A girlfriend of Thornton indicated he was a victim of racial harassment at the beverage center, the mother of the girlfriend told CNN.

Thornton told his girlfriend he had reported to a company supervisor and a union representative about the harassment but they did nothing about it, Joanne Hannah said Tuesday.

Teamsters officials deny allegations that Thornton, who was black, snapped because of racial harassment.

Eight people were killed in various parts of the facility, Police Chief Marc Montminy said, and one shot may have been fired outside. 

"There were clearly some performance issues," Montminy said.

Chris Roos, secretary and treasurer of Teamsters Local 1035, which represents the company's drivers, said Thornton had been accused of stealing "product" off a beer truck on two separate occasions.

Roos said Steve Hollander, a company vice president injured in the shooting spree, provided details of the 7 a.m. meeting.

"Omar asked if he could resign, and he signed a resignation paper. The meeting was over. They were walking out of the meeting, and that's when it all happened," Roos said.

Bryan Cirigliano, 51, the shop steward for the union and the union's president, was in the meeting. He was among those killed, Roos said. Other victims were found throughout the facility, police said.

"He was a great guy. Unbelievable family man, " Roos said of Cirigliano. "Very community-active. Loved his daughters, loved his wife."

Joanne Hannah said Thornton showed her daughter, Kristie, a cell phone photo of racial epithets and a stick figure with a noose around its neck drawn on a restroom stall. He was in a stall once and heard a co-worker say "they wanted that n----- out of there," she said.

She said Thornton was one of two black employees. "This poor guy got pushed to the limit."

Kristie Hannah and Thornton spent Monday night in Enfield together, Joanne Hannah said. "She said he acted his normal self."

Joanne Hannah said Thornton got a pistol permit about two years ago. She said she was unaware of the allegations of theft levied against Thornton, a truck driver, but she doubted he was guilty. "He was too honest."

Roos said Thornton never filed a racial complaint with the union or a government agency.

"This had nothing to do with racial stuff. This was a sick individual. He just snapped," Roos said.

James Battaglio, a spokesman for the family that owns the distributorship, said he had no information about the allegations of harassment. 

Hannah and relatives of Thornton said the suspected gunman called his mother Tuesday morning and said he had shot five people.

Thornton's uncle, Will Holliday, told CNN affiliate WFSB that in the call, the suspected shooter said, "'I killed the five racists that was there that was bothering me' and he said that's it, the cops are going to come in so I'm going to take care of myself."

Police would not release identities of the dead late Tuesday. Montminy said he did not know how many were specifically targeted.

Company receptionist Marissa Busiere told CNN affiliate WFSB she heard another co-worker screaming after shots rang out inside the business.

"'He's shooting! He's shooting! Call 911.' And everyone started running out of the building," Busiere said.

At the time, there were about 35 or 40 people in the office and warehouse, Brett Hollander, the director of marketing and a member of the family that owns the company, told the Hartford Courant. 

Three people were rushed to Hartford Hospital, and one of them later died, a doctor told reporters. Police declined to say how many people were wounded.

"Everyone is devastated by this tragic and senseless act," Battaglio, the spokesman for the Hollander family, told the Courant. He said the family intends to focus its attention on the families of the victims.

"[The family is] mourning. They're meeting tomorrow morning [Wednesday] with employees, away from the site," said Battaglio. "They want to meet in private, an opportunity for people to grieve and to come together and to address the remainder of their family members, meaning their employees."

"This is a tight-knit organization. This is tragic, this is senseless. In addition, they lost people with whom they've been extremely close to over the decades," Battaglio told CNN.

At least one nearby business was closed Tuesday afternoon.

"Pray for the families of the people at Hartford Distributors," a recorded phone message at Fluid Dynamics said.

Roos said employees are still reeling after the violence.

"I'm devastated. I'm trying to think how I'm going to get nine families' lives back in order again and help them cope with this. How can we help them cope with this situation? We're going to try to get employee-assistance people and union therapists to help and speak with these guys," he said.

Comments:

1termBHOBAMA 
America is a racist country, no matter how you put it. White convicts plea bargain with the state to avoid the death penalty, whites on death row get retrials and sentenced to life, etc., etc.. I think this man was pushed to the edge by the color of his skin. Thats the way this country works. As ... more 
America is a racist country, no matter how you put it. White convicts plea bargain with the state to avoid the death penalty, whites on death row get retrials and sentenced to life, etc., etc.. I think this man was pushed to the edge by the color of his skin. Thats the way this country works. As for the victims, they were at the wrong place at the wrong time. I'm not black. less 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
loyismyhonor 
You dumb liberals can't get it thru your thick heads can you?? Peole also kill people with knives, bats, razors, axes and rocks and fists--wanna ban all them too? Ok to start with take all your kitchen knives and you and a friend sever your hands, now you've killed two birds with one stone!!.....You... more 
You dumb liberals can't get it thru your thick heads can you?? Peole also kill people with knives, bats, razors, axes and rocks and fists--wanna ban all them too? Ok to start with take all your kitchen knives and you and a friend sever your hands, now you've killed two birds with one stone!!.....You're on a roll now, boys....Keep it up! less 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Marty7044 
It's sad, but this is what fosters the racism inside of me. It appears that most if not all the employees are white. So it just so happens that the guy that killed 9 people today is black? Wow, what are the odds! Sorry, but when I hear that a convenient store or bank was robbed or that someone w... more 
It's sad, but this is what fosters the racism inside of me. It appears that most if not all the employees are white. So it just so happens that the guy that killed 9 people today is black? Wow, what are the odds! Sorry, but when I hear that a convenient store or bank was robbed or that someone was mugged or stabbed (like today in California) I just don't assume the guy is white (even though there are WAY more white people). And sadly, I'm usually right. less 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
thabusiness Anyone claiming that race is no longer an issue should just read this comment board... 

for most people i think its not.... our media and pop culture keeps it alive 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Guest 
Wow, performance issues and stealing? This doesnt sound like the company was racist to me, just doing justice and firing his a$$. Looks like family is seeking settlement money, not a suprise and another slanderous racial card to damage the company. You get caught stealing and your performance isn't ... more 
Wow, performance issues and stealing? This doesnt sound like the company was racist to me, just doing justice and firing his a$$. Looks like family is seeking settlement money, not a suprise and another slanderous racial card to damage the company. You get caught stealing and your performance isn't up to standards, then you can get away with it because youre black? Thank God he killed himself less 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
jt35 
He was supposedly caught on video stealing. Okay, he's busted. But who asks to resign an hourly job instead of being fired? That does not pass the sniff test. Every houly employee and employer knows you can't file for unemployment if quit. Was he expecting them to give him a good letter of refe... more 
He was supposedly caught on video stealing. Okay, he's busted. But who asks to resign an hourly job instead of being fired? That does not pass the sniff test. Every houly employee and employer knows you can't file for unemployment if quit. Was he expecting them to give him a good letter of reference? I don't think so. less 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
biostockman This clown thought he was in a rap video this morning. 
1 minute ago | Like | Report abuse  
thabusiness if you dont get that you prolly never will 
1 minute ago | Like | Report abuse  
thabusiness its called critical thinking Dugowt ...... how about "there's a guy with a gun shooting".... but it was "hes got a gun" which implies the audience knows who it is. how would they know who it is .... i think you know 
2 minutes ago | Like (1) | Report abuse 
 
Deedee3000 Perhaps in the moment of being killed they didn't have time to make their semantics to your liking. Or maybe they meant "the guy who just got fired." 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Alan2 I love the title: "Gunman...forced to resign".....he was ALLOWED to resign because he was caught on video STEALING. And OF COURSE it was because of racial harrassment!! There has to be a reason why a Black Man would do something like this! 
2 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
subx He's black? NO WAY!

in b4 the mod truth deletion squad 
2 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
ItMakesSense More people died here today than of a terrorist attack in the US today. 
2 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
ItMakesSense Well Taliban terrorists that is... 
1 minute ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Guest 
I think he did steal otherwise both the company Reps and Union Reps have not asked him to resign. They know darn well that firing a black person is not a joke. They must have some concrete evidence. On the other hand, I also think he should have been discriminated against otherwise he has not los... more 
I think he did steal otherwise both the company Reps and Union Reps have not asked him to resign. They know darn well that firing a black person is not a joke. They must have some concrete evidence.
On the other hand, I also think he should have been discriminated against otherwise he has not lost it. The fact that he bought the gun with him on the meeting day shows that he intended to kill the people he was about to meet and then kill himself. I don't think being caught stealing some beer was not big of a deal that drove this guy to this horrible homicide and so shameful enough for him to kill himself.
I have no doubts there should be some degree of racial discrimination at play here. less 
2 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
doctormatt I think you're using the wrong verbs throughout this little description. "Should be" replaced by "was"? Work on your grammar, please. For yourself and the readers. 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Z1mm3r Happy Job Hunting !!!!! More jobs for you !!! 
2 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Z1mm3r My rights of FREE Speech and Religion....Omar was a proud Muslim 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
oldfromdc 
You people don't know how to be white and proud without bringing down every race around you. This makes you look fearful of everyone except whites. This is a sign of weakness on your part. If you fear or hate another race it's because you are weak. Yes, racism exist in the U.S. and yes we are st... more 
You people don't know how to be white and proud without bringing down every race around you. This makes you look fearful of everyone except whites. This is a sign of weakness on your part. If you fear or hate another race it's because you are weak. Yes, racism exist in the U.S. and yes we are still fighting this. Maybe we will never be one, but to fear or hate another man because of their skin color is nothing but a sign of weakness and insecurity. So, to all you kids posting hate..just sit back and think about that for a minute. Learn how to be proud without hate. less 
3 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
Jkers1986 
This polarizing spotlight on racism is being used as means for the US government to strip us of our liberties without anyone noticing because we are too engrossed with what "Tyrone" did to "Bob" and vice versa. The Media and our politicians are creating a shadow world in which trivial differences ar... more 
This polarizing spotlight on racism is being used as means for the US government to strip us of our liberties without anyone noticing because we are too engrossed with what "Tyrone" did to "Bob" and vice versa. The Media and our politicians are creating a shadow world in which trivial differences are blown way out of proportion and the truth remains hidden and protected......does no one else sense the elephant in the room? less 
3 minutes ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
flowerman I am going to go watch me some WET (White Entertainment Network).
See ya! 
4 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
parrotbay72 Hey, I'm going to the NAAWP meeting. Want to come with? 
1 minute ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
doctormatt It's humorous how taking pride in being "caucasian" is racist, but taking pride in being African-American is considered appropriate. 
2 minutes ago | Like (1) | Report abuse 
 
aeronautic1 Did everyone miss the rush of the news media today that said he pulled a .223 rifle (assault) as his instrument of death? I am suprised that some dim-ocrat didn't say is was Bush's fault. 
4 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
doctormatt 
All those who are African-American and playing the race card. Just remember what his girlfriend had to offer in terms of condolences to the families of 8 dead victims...rationalizing his behavior on the grounds of RACE. Take ownership of handing out that card first. Non African-Americans will take o... more
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="9211b211ab8643709c3d98ac909783f3">
<name>0805 - Everything to play for: Eyeing China's online games market</name>
<content>Aside from the hundreds of new games on display at ChinaJoy that ran from July 28 to Aug. 1 in Shanghai, there was also something else new -- more foreigners, specifically foreign gaming companies hoping to partner with Chinese companies to either import their games to China or export Chinas games abroad. 

They came from Australia, Russia, Germany, France, Japan, the United Arab Emirates and around 30 or so other countries, setting up booths at ChinaJoy, Chinas largest gaming and digital entertainment exhibition (the country's answer to E3), and speaking at several gaming conferences held in conjunction with the event. 

 
The [Chinese companies] want to do business ... It is the birth of a new market, really
 Martin Wilkes, sales and business manager for Firelight TechnologiesIt is a trend that many say will only grow in coming years as foreign game developers and publishers want a piece of Chinas lucrative gaming market, which was worth more than US$3 billion in 2009 according to Niko Partners, and as cash-rich Chinese companies like Tencent Holdings and Shanda Games try their luck in the West. 

Tencent recently invested US$300 million in Digital Sky Technologies, the Russian Internet holding company that acquired a stake in Facebook last year, and Shanda Games, a subsidiary of Shanda Interactive Entertainment Limited, purchased San Francisco-based Mochi Media for US$80 million in January. 

Meanwhile, Zynga, the San Francisco-based company known for its social networking game Farmville, acquired XPD Media, a social gaming company based in Beijing in May. 

There is a lot of stuff happening between the East and the West right now, says Ludovic Bodin, co-founder and CEO of Cmune, a Beijng-based company that builds 3D games for social networks. Everyone is trying to work with each other. 

Changing tides
Once considered mediocre at best, the increased quality and technological complexity of online games made in China is fueling interest from foreign publishers hoping to help domestic developers release their products overseas, says Carsten van Husen, CEO of the German-based online game publisher Gameforge.  

(Article continues after the photo)


 Chinese gamers pack into ChinaJoy alongside game developers for China's online gaming event of the year.During the conferences, which included sessions on the global development of Chinese games and global social games and their Chinese hopes, Gameforge signed its first deal to distribute Warrior King, a MMO (massively multi-player online) game produced by Beijing-based LineKong Entertainment Technology, in the West. 

Korea has always been leading the industry but the Chinese are obviously very clever, creative and massive, so they are coming on strong, van Husen says. 

Yet while Chinese gaming companies have been investing internationally and there are a few examples of Chinese social network games that have been successful abroad (Sunshine Ranch, a SNS game developed by Rekoo, has performed well in Japan and the United State, for example), some say it will be a while before Chinese developers can make any major inroads in the West largely due to cultural divides and lack of market expertise. 

 
There is a lot of stuff happening between the East and the West right now. Everyone is trying to work with each other.
 Ludovic Bodin, co-founder and CEO of CmuneIt will take another few years, Bodin says. For most of them, they are going to buy companies that are strong in [other] markets or can serve as a bridge between the East and the West. 

Technical interruptions
Cultural barriers as well as hard-to-navigate regulations, including a law passed last fall banning foreign investment in domestic online gaming operations, could also make it difficult for foreign game companies to enter China. 

Still, there are those who remain determined to take a share of the worlds largest Internet population entrenched in a lucrative culture of online games. 

The Chinese market has moved dramatically in terms of technology, says Martin Wilkes, sales and business manager for Firelight Technologies, a Melbourne-based company that provides audio solutions for video games. Games have become part of the Chinese culture and will only increase in potential because of the size of the population. 

Wilkes was accompanied by 10 other Australian companies on a Victorian Government ICT trade mission to Shanghai to explore business opportunities in China. 

The [Chinese companies] want to do business. They are really eager and very approachable and very keen to talk, he says. It is the birth of a new market, really. 



Read more: ChinaJoy, Chinas biggest gaming expo attracts foreign investors | CNNGo.com http://www.cnngo.com/shanghai/life/chinese-online-gaming-lures-more-foreign-faces-901300?hpt=Mid#ixzz0vh7dBthv
</content>
<bookmark>945</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="d06963dcb6ce455d80c5d7819607cc65">
<name>0809 - What does 'video game' mean, anyway?</name>
<content>Editor's note: Scott Steinberg is the head of technology and video game consulting firm TechSavvy Global as well as the founder of GameExec magazine and Game Industry TV. The creator and host of online video series Game Theory, he frequently appears as an on-air technology analyst for ABC, CBS, NBC, FOX and CNN. 

(CNN) -- From plummeting sales to a shift to social networks, critics love to endlessly debate what ails the gaming business. 

But ironically, the biggest problem of all may be that there is no singular "games industry" to speak of anymore, and that the term "video game" itself is hopelessly outdated. 

"I've never seen a period like this ... there's so much disruption," Electronic Arts founder Trip Hawkins recently said on the online video show "Game Theory." "The industry is really being turned inside out." 

Credit the rise of new technologies -- from downloadable games to smartphone apps -- streaming "cloud" games and social network titles. 

Free games playable in your Web browser, electronic amusements based around the sale of bite-sized virtual goods ("microtransactions") and massively multiplayer online worlds are also on the upswing. Simultaneously, tightened household spending is forcing players to look more toward episodic and downloadable content such as new maps, missions and story add-ons that extend the life of games they already own.

Unfortunately for industry titans like Activision and Electronic Arts, most modern forms of electronic entertainment have about as much to do with games like "Call of Duty" and "Mass Effect" as Apple does quilting. 

Digital diversions built for new platforms like Facebook and the iPhone aren't just designed to be played in completely different methods and manners. They're meant to be enjoyed in different context and timeframes, and constantly updated and refined based on player feedback, defining them more as services than products. 

"A lot of the established players [including] retailers and publishers are worried," said "Oddworld" creator Lorne Lanning. "They have good reason to be. People are finding experiences and products elsewhere, and different businesses are emerging that large infrastructure companies aren't used to adapting to, and a lot of them won't be able to adapt to. 

"Anyone who thinks that they're deeply entrenched ... is fooling themselves." 

As he explains, it's one thing to sell a copy of "Metroid: Other M," which costs a fixed price, offers everyone essentially the same experience and lasts a few hours before being put down. It's another to build a 3-D online universe such as "Free Realms" or social game such as "FrontierVille," which have to stay relevant for years and offer reasons to keep clicking day after day. 

The shift has made for many bleak months of retail software performance. Most recently, sales of games for PlayStation 3, Wii, Xbox 360 and popular handheld consoles slumped a whopping 15 percent to $531 million in June, according to market research firm NPD. 

"Everyone was caught figuratively with their pants down," said Epic Games design director Cliff Bleszinski of the shift to online, digital and social alternatives. "Everybody in the industry is still trying to figure out how to make blockbuster games in this day and age."

Independent game designer Clint Hocking, most recently responsible for "Far Cry 2," wholeheartedly agrees with these sentiments. "[Game industry insiders] stood around saying for so long that the game industry is immune to the recession," he said. "But we're not." 

Origin and Portalarium founder Richard "Lord British" Garriott predicts a radical shift for the business, citing that those who choose to accept it will flourish, while those who don't are doomed. 

But as insiders are all quick to point out, upsides are also plentiful for video game fans. 

More than 40,000 games are now available that speak to all ages and interests, and at a broader range of prices than ever, on the iPhone and iPad. Sales of PC digital downloads have either caught up to or surpassed retail purchases as of 2009 as well, depending on which analyst you ask. 

"The industry will be healthy, is not headed for doom, and we're entertaining more people in more ways than ever before," said Naughty Dog co-founder Jason Rubin. "But from a profitability standpoint, the [blockbuster] console stuff is not quite working."

At this point, it's a little premature to write the pastime off. 

Instead of debating what ails gaming as a whole, maybe we'd do better to take a deeper look at the fundamental changes responsible for these painful upheavals. 

Not to mention, that is, wake up and realize that "video games" can't all be lumped into the same single grouping any more, or viewed through the same myopic lens.

Comments:

Scott0604 
In this article they mention a shift in the market and how there are new medium for gaming i.e. browsers games and social networking site games (farmville) etc. I would argue that these aren't a shift but an expansion.The customer base of games is expanded rather than shifting and all it is doing is... more 
In this article they mention a shift in the market and how there are new medium for gaming i.e. browsers games and social networking site games (farmville) etc. I would argue that these aren't a shift but an expansion.

The customer base of games is expanded rather than shifting and all it is doing is creating different classes of gamer. My granny plays farmville and my mum plays the WII, this doesn't represent a shift away from traditional gaming because I'm pretty sure I never played Golden Eye on the N64 with either of them.

I also find the whole 'recession hitting hard' thing hard to believe when you consider Blizz just made $3.5 million selling a BTA mount. (A horse you can ride in the World of Warcraft game). less 
39 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Ryot 
I'm left wondering if CNN could have found a larger collection of douchebags to interview. Seriously, I laughed out loud at the laundry list of "luminaries" quoted here -- washed up, left the industry, attention white hacks. Of course the guys you interviewed were caught with their pants down! They'... more 
I'm left wondering if CNN could have found a larger collection of douchebags to interview. Seriously, I laughed out loud at the laundry list of "luminaries" quoted here -- washed up, left the industry, attention white hacks. Of course the guys you interviewed were caught with their pants down! They're idiots! How about interviewing those who *did* see thus coming -- Blizzard, Zynga, hell even EA's own Maxis. 

Look, I'm a video game designer by profession. I come up with the user interactions in digital interactive entertainment. I've worked on MMORPGs, single player RPGs, mobile games, and social network games. Any game designer worth his or her salt can move across game genres and platforms and design an experience hat will be entertaining and valuable to the target audience. Everyone else should get out of the game industry asap. As an "insider" myself, I welcome these changes, and hope they signal the death of dinosaurs such as the men quoted in this article. less 
2 hours ago | Like (6) | Report abuse  
highfive Sometimes I miss my one button joystick! 
5 hours ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
eplatypus 
I am not exactly sure of how the business works exactly, but I believe Steam has a pretty good system going. There are several games I never would have thought purchasing but I have because of Steam's midweek madness sales. At $50 dollars I had no intention of buying some of the games, but when ha... more 
I am not exactly sure of how the business works exactly, but I believe Steam has a pretty good system going. There are several games I never would have thought purchasing but I have because of Steam's midweek madness sales. At $50 dollars I had no intention of buying some of the games, but when half price or down to $20 it enticed me to look into them, read some reviews and then purchase them. Hell, it may be half off but I would think a sale is a sale. less 
8 hours ago | Like (3) | Report abuse 
 
Scott0604 I agree. Big steam fan and I purchased all of the Civ games because they were on offer. Didn't play them much tbh but Steam made their money off me whether I play them or not. 
37 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
phatkhat 
Steam is good. I love their system for downloading games - so you can play anywhere. I think they are developing "Steam Cloud" for multiplayer gaming, too, but I don't follow that. I will say that twice a year, July and December, they have the mother of all sales. Everything from FPS to old classics... more 
Steam is good. I love their system for downloading games - so you can play anywhere. I think they are developing "Steam Cloud" for multiplayer gaming, too, but I don't follow that. I will say that twice a year, July and December, they have the mother of all sales. Everything from FPS to old classics like Monkey Island and what ever falls between. less 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
bannedchad 
I use to buy games when they first came out. My wife and I have tripled our income in the last 5 years and now, I spend even LESS on games. Why? It's easy, I'm not giving 60.00 for a game that gets boring after a couple of days tops. I'm not paying 60.00 to get a game that takes a monthly fee to pla... more 
I use to buy games when they first came out. My wife and I have tripled our income in the last 5 years and now, I spend even LESS on games. Why? It's easy, I'm not giving 60.00 for a game that gets boring after a couple of days tops. I'm not paying 60.00 to get a game that takes a monthly fee to play. I'm not paying 60.00 to buy a game that makes no sense. Why would I? I can wait 3-4 months and buy it for 20.00 off craigslist after I read if it's even worth playing. The game industry needs to learn the real lesson here. Start putting more effort into games, make them enjoyable and stop trying to sell us games that are not worth playing. The industry will die if they don't figure this out soon. less 
8 hours ago | Like (4) | Report abuse 
 
Scott0604 
Something that you glance on is something that has started irritating me recently. Many console games released today are small and/or short. I understand that the level of work it takes to produce the high end graphics means that they can't make huge games like they used to (See metal gear solid on ... more 
Something that you glance on is something that has started irritating me recently. Many console games released today are small and/or short. I understand that the level of work it takes to produce the high end graphics means that they can't make huge games like they used to (See metal gear solid on ps1 and FF8 on ps1) but I would gladly substitute a better/longer gameplay for less graphics. less 
33 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Serinanth 
I agree for the most part but the montly fee to pay argument is invalid. Do you own a motor vehicle which requires a montly intake of fuel? Do you not pay monthly for your internet? I guess its in the eye of the beholder on what you wish to spend your money on though =) Also some modern games surpas... more 
I agree for the most part but the montly fee to pay argument is invalid. Do you own a motor vehicle which requires a montly intake of fuel? Do you not pay monthly for your internet? I guess its in the eye of the beholder on what you wish to spend your money on though =) Also some modern games surpass hollywood blockbusters in terms of what it takes to produce them. less 
3 hours ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
canwegetreal I hate it when I don't have internet and can't play the games I payed for 
9 hours ago | Like (8) | Report abuse  
Smoothe 
Video games? Where has this guy been? They are called by their genres....Most of the games in the article are called shooters( 1st person )......I prefer MMORPG's or just RPG's ( role playing games ) I'm a console snob and prefer more depth in my games so I prefer computer titles..... Some people... more 
Video games? Where has this guy been? They are called by their genres....Most of the games in the article are called shooters( 1st person )......I prefer MMORPG's or just RPG's ( role playing games ) I'm a console snob and prefer more depth in my games so I prefer computer titles..... Some people are satisfied with a joystick, pad or whatever.....They are all an escape and a lot cheaper than most entertainment....As for game apps for your phone.....whatever Wearing out the buttons on my tiny screen phone does not sound smart or fun.... less 
9 hours ago | Like (6) | Report abuse 
 
LPPP I guess he's been out from under his rock and not playing video games so often that gaming nomenclature angers him. 
8 hours ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
canwegetreal You all can say what ever you all want, But the reason I don't pay sh it games or any games is becuase they all net the internet to play or activate. PERIOD!!! 
9 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
mdsteil While its been said already, if this guy is the head of your gaming division, you need to look harder 
9 hours ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
Godstar All you could ever want to know about gaming you can learn on Kotaku, and not from this guy. 
10 hours ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
bookfaces The only people struggling to understand the game market is the boomer generation; the same people who still yell into their cell phones. 
10 hours ago | Like (6) | Report abuse 
 
Scott0604 
Calm down FreeMan56 (I really hope that's a half life reference because that would kinda prove your point).The idea that the younger generation are less intelligent isn't new, you parents probably thought it and their parents etc, but unfortunately it is false. The average IQ increases by 1 every 3 ... more 
Calm down FreeMan56 (I really hope that's a half life reference because that would kinda prove your point).

The idea that the younger generation are less intelligent isn't new, you parents probably thought it and their parents etc, but unfortunately it is false. The average IQ increases by 1 every 3 years. The Dr, whose name eludes me, who discovered this now attends trials in America to ensure some people don't get the death sentence, as I believe it is US law that you cannot give the death sentence to people declared mentally retarded. less 
25 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
phatkhat Oh, yeah. And some of us do have hearing loss. Maybe it was too many Who concerts in the front rows? ROFL. 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse  
phatkhat I think some of us boomers have a pretty damn good grasp of the game market. I can tell you that if we all suddenly "croaked", the gaming industry would really have a slump, because there are a lot of serious gamers in the boomer set. :oP 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse  
FreeMan56 Some facts for you imbeciles: Who invented the cell phone? Dr Martin Cooper, born Dec 26, 1928. Who invented the internet? Vint Cerf, born June 23, 1943. I could go on and on for days, and would find few, if any, major developments produced by the f-wit generation that you're a part of. 
3 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
FreeMan56 "Can't wait for them all to croak."

Once we're gone, you're screwed, because you're all a bunch of nitwits. 
3 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
dablakpantha I work with a few of them. I told him, 'You don't have to yell into the phone, they can hear you." He cocked his head to the side and asked me to repeat my self. I said never mind... 
8 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
Bahbkc Can't wait for them all to croak. 
9 hours ago | Like (3) | Report abuse 
 
JLS639 
Obviously there are quite a few gamers who know a lot not put into this article (special kudos to Langkard). However... You would do well to cut out the cussing if you want people to take what you write seriously. Dropping assorted cuss bombs do not help you make your point. Try writing in a specifi... more 
Obviously there are quite a few gamers who know a lot not put into this article (special kudos to Langkard). However... You would do well to cut out the cussing if you want people to take what you write seriously. Dropping assorted cuss bombs do not help you make your point. Try writing in a specific example of what is wrong with, for example, Warhammer online or Farmville or Civilization part four instead of dropping a cuss bomb. less 
10 hours ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
Bearish 
The article fails to mention that most of these "light" games target totally different audiences than the traditional blockbuster game audience. If the games industry is struggling, which it really isn't, it would probably be because every game is a sequel of a sequel of a sequel. Most of them wit... more 
The article fails to mention that most of these "light" games target totally different audiences than the traditional blockbuster game audience. If the games industry is struggling, which it really isn't, it would probably be because every game is a sequel of a sequel of a sequel. Most of them with little change between sequels too. While Nintendo keeps remaking the same 5 games, at least they actually make relatively different games and then cram Mario into them. You can't say the same for most WOW clones or First Person Shooters with 1 minor gimmick attempting to carry the entire game. less 
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="dc52b05f3f8d4f968dd6403290f3ab89">
<name>0817 - Pentagon report: China extending military reach</name>
<content>Washington (CNN) -- The Chinese military continues to expand its reach and capabilities beyond its immediate geographical area, a new report from the U.S. Department of Defense concludes.

The report, an annual assessment sent to Congress, notes that some of those capabilities have been positive, like humanitarian and anti-piracy efforts, but others are meant to give China "extended-range power projection."

While China's continued effort to be able to sustain military operations far from its shore are concerning to the U.S. military, "China's ability to sustain military power at a distance, today, remains limited," the report says.

As in the past, the U.S. program to sell military equipment to Taiwan continues to create tension with China and has led to cessation at times of military relations between the two countries.

The assessment notes that China has the most active ballistic and cruise missile program in the world, including developing anti-missile technology. Also of concern are Chinese efforts to develop a long-range anti-ship ballistic missile with a reach of more than 900 miles, which would include areas in which the U.S. Navy is active. Such a measure would give the Chinese military "the capability to attack ships, including aircraft carriers, in the Western Pacific Ocean," according to the report.

The Chinese could start building their first aircraft carrier this year, and China has started to train pilots to operate off such carriers. It already has a Russian carrier that it is refurbishing.

Its naval muscle is also being flexed with additional nuclear powered submarines, and it has nearly completed a navy base on Hainan Island, "with direct access to vital international sea lanes," which will allow for "stealthy deployment of submarines," the report says.


Comments :

BforG 
The gall of the US: US has current military campaigns in Afghanistan and Iraq, they are still obsessed with 60 year old history tryiing to move their military in Korea up to the Chinese border and providing weaponry for Taiwan. Vietnam, central America, Grenada ......The US would reduce military te... more 
The gall of the US: 
US has current military campaigns in Afghanistan and Iraq, they are still obsessed with 60 year old history tryiing to move their military in Korea up to the Chinese border and providing weaponry for Taiwan. Vietnam, central America, Grenada ......
The US would reduce military tension around the world by first of all setting an example maybe reduce their per capita military spending to maybe only double anyone elses. 

I would like to see an independant assessment of the US military intentions and the risks they pose to the world. less 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
SamQ 
well i see how people talk about democracy &amp; China being a threat..but come on guys..you cant become the 2nd largest economy in the world if you enslave your people..so am sure the system works..maybe better than others..some how China doesnt have any debts like US has..a damn trillion dollar..&amp; wha... more 
well i see how people talk about democracy &amp; China being a threat..but come on guys..you cant become the 2nd largest economy in the world if you enslave your people..so am sure the system works..maybe better than others..some how China doesnt have any debts like US has..a damn trillion dollar..&amp; what gives US the right to have military presence everywhere in the world..if they can have it so can the Chinese less 
6 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Bilfar 
The United States will have some very interesting technology to unleash against this miscreant regime someday. My hope is that the Chinese continue to misread their tea leaves to the point of testing America's true might and unwavering resolve. Those bright, blood red flags will serve as excellent t... more 
The United States will have some very interesting technology to unleash against this miscreant regime someday. My hope is that the Chinese continue to misread their tea leaves to the point of testing America's true might and unwavering resolve. Those bright, blood red flags will serve as excellent targets. less 
11 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
lightroom 
The US is the most dangerous country in the world today, it imposes threats to human lives/wellbeings in every corner of this planet. The US is losing influence on political and diplomacy grounds fast, and with trillion dollar debt which probably will never be honored, however, military spending is ... more 
The US is the most dangerous country in the world today, it imposes threats to human lives/wellbeings in every corner of this planet. The US is losing influence on political and diplomacy grounds fast, and with trillion dollar debt which probably will never be honored, however, military spending is increasing year on year, where does this all go? The US military spending accounts for 47% of the worlds total, and yet, at the same time, brainless reports produced still point fingers to others. When will the US ever learn to stop blaming the others and focusing on its own problem, it's on the path of no return, and when all of these reach the breaking point, the US fall will be a pretty nasty and yet spectacular one. less 
14 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
stoneman07 
If the world will let China dominate over the far east, it will be like the expansion of Japan way back in the 30's. And many democracies over here will fall under communism. Just look how China aggressively claims spratley islands. That should belong to Philippines, I mean it's even far from the Ex... more 
If the world will let China dominate over the far east, it will be like the expansion of Japan way back in the 30's. And many democracies over here will fall under communism. Just look how China aggressively claims spratley islands. That should belong to Philippines, I mean it's even far from the Exclusive Economic Zone of China that is 200 nautical miles from its shores. They are a threat to every democratic nation here in Asia. less 
23 minutes ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
Marty777 See that flag? A hammer and sickle in everyone of our hands is their goal. Freedom not fought for will be freedom taken away. 
36 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
NapoleonIII Stephen Hawking gives the planet 200 years. I say that's a conservative estimate. We're done for. 

We just don't get it - we cannot keep up with war, rape and destruction. You don't need to be a Nostradamus or Tiresias to see that we're all doomed if we don't stop now. 
56 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
chl84 Don't worry, dude, 200 years is beyond our concern, I really doubt I can even live for 100 years. Cheerish what you have now, those knucklehead politicians can do whatever they want, just don't take our freedom away. 
32 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
bluebells If the American can send their army to the Chinese border in places like Japan &amp; Korea then the Chinese have every right to send its own army to any place on earth including Cuba. 
56 minutes ago | Like (16) | Report abuse 
 
zinktink 
@machioveliHave you even been to China? Dude I guarantee you most young Chinese people in the cities and even those that are currently serving in the Jiafangjun(People's Liberation Army) probably live a much better life than you ever will.It's incredible how ignorant people are these days. By the wa... more 
@machioveli

Have you even been to China? Dude I guarantee you most young Chinese people in the cities and even those that are currently serving in the Jiafangjun(People's Liberation Army) probably live a much better life than you ever will.

It's incredible how ignorant people are these days. By the way, learn how to spell Machiavelli properly. less 
16 minutes ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
machioveli @hayashi exactly, just pointing out that if they put troops in Cuba you might as well open up a little China in Miami for all the defectors 
34 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
hayashi machioveli, the Chinese know everything about outside world, they want to live their life like Americans, well, maybe not today's broke Americans, but certainly in terms of wealth and many other aspects. 
37 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
machioveli 
Problem is that nations like China stay in power from keeping people in contact with outside worlds. If China puts troops in Cuba even the lifestyle they see Cubans leading will look like luxury compared to the way their families lives in China. So that probably will be a good thing for the US. Even... more 
Problem is that nations like China stay in power from keeping people in contact with outside worlds. If China puts troops in Cuba even the lifestyle they see Cubans leading will look like luxury compared to the way their families lives in China. So that probably will be a good thing for the US. Even as a threat they will still be wiped out within seconds if anything happened. China only has missles and submarines as global reach options. less 
42 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
vintel7 Bush and the republicans gave our manufacturing base to China and sold our national debt to China who are now our bankers and owners. It does not surprise me that China is ascendant. We helped them. 
57 minutes ago | Like (6) | Report abuse 
 
lightroom 
Bush did a lot stupid things but it doesn't matter who is in charge in the US, the situation won't change. Labour cost is the biggest issue, because you guys are just too expensive to feed, $20 per hour vs chinese $5 per day, you do the maths. You've lived on borrowed money for too long, it's the be... more 
Bush did a lot stupid things but it doesn't matter who is in charge in the US, the situation won't change. Labour cost is the biggest issue, because you guys are just too expensive to feed, $20 per hour vs chinese $5 per day, you do the maths. You've lived on borrowed money for too long, it's the beginning of the end of it. less 
34 minutes ago | Like (1) | Report abuse 
 
samyl We dont need to worry about chinese military power. coz its all made in china. We all know about chinese product quality. it wont last long...haha... 
1 hour ago | Like (4) | Report abuse 
 
AutosPak Americans are addicted to Chinese products. 
11 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
lightroom Americans have better weaponary, so what, they still can't win a single war...lol 
44 minutes ago | Like (4) | Report abuse 
 
akleos So, the dog would bare its teeth. 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse  
BarryC16 
Will America ever learn? Who gives a hoot if China wants to waste its money the way we did, and continue to do although they are spending far less per capita than we do. It seems that feeding our people and giving healthcare to everyone (as in Europe) is just too easy for us. We need to have yet ano... more 
Will America ever learn? Who gives a hoot if China wants to waste its money the way we did, and continue to do although they are spending far less per capita than we do. It seems that feeding our people and giving healthcare to everyone (as in Europe) is just too easy for us. We need to have yet another phony reason to continue to build OUR military. Such a joke. less 
1 hour ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
pkfops That's great.China should be a fantastic military partner to work with. 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse  
HelionGann Every country deserves the ability to Defend itself. We shall see how China uses these new armaments. Will it be for peace? Or War? 
2 hours ago | Like (14) | Report abuse 
 
NapoleonIII We saw how they treated the Tibetans and they're mum on North Korea. I say we're in for a great ride. 
54 minutes ago | Like (4) | Report abuse  
scope213 
Every country? Let's get real here. If that would be the case then human civilization would be wiped from the face of this planet. You seem insinuate that all nations have the ability to do exactly what we've been doing for the majority half of the 20th century. I think not.However, China at thi... more 
Every country? Let's get real here. If that would be the case then human civilization would be wiped from the face of this planet. You seem insinuate that all nations have the ability to do exactly what we've been doing for the majority half of the 20th century. I think not.
However, China at this juncture is not a threat due to the bountiful progress of growth they are experiencing and the party hardliners reaping the rewards of embracing semi-capitalism. Eventually, all good things will come to an end and when that happens hopefully China hasn't "reached to far out". less 
1 hour ago | Like (6) | Report abuse 
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="126bc89d0d0b4cfdb7ca5519937dd562">
<name>0818 - Colombia survivors: A normal flight, then a crash on the runway</name>
<content>(CNN) -- Aires Airlines Flight 8250 was seconds away from landing at San Andres airport on a small island off the coast of Colombia. The pilot had turned on the seat belt sign and told passengers to stay in their seats. Passengers could see rain and lightning outside their small cabin windows, but nothing was amiss. Everything seemed calm. Normal. Routine.

Then a hard, violent crash as the Boeing 737-700 smacked into the runway. The plane started to break apart, and sparks flew as metal ground against concrete. Seats came loose from their moorings and tumbled about the cabin. Passengers could see the runway and the rainy predawn sky through the gaping holes left in the sheared fuselage. Some of them fell to the ground, still strapped into their seats.

Survivors of Monday's plane crash that left one person dead and more than 120 injured describe nearly two hours of normalcy followed by minutes of sheer terror.

"Everything was going well," Heriberto Rua told Radio Caracol. "When I felt something, it was the crash."

Another passenger, Juan Carlos Hurtado, said everything was fine until the moment of landing about 1:49 a.m. (2:49 a.m. ET).



Video: Closer look at plane crash 

Video: Pilot: Crash cause unlikely lightning 
RELATED TOPICS 
Colombia 
Air Disasters 
"No sooner had the rear wheels touched down when it started to break apart," he told Radio Caracol. "It broke apart, and the seats were torn loose. We ended up seeing the road, and it started to catch on fire. There were many people wounded, screaming."

Industrial engineer Jose Ricardo Ramirez said he was ejected from the ruptured plane.

"The truth is that I can't say whether the plane got to roll down the runway," Ramirez told Radio Caracol. "Simply, when we fell down, we ended up on the pavement, chairs and all."

Ramirez said his first inclination was to unbuckle his seat belt and then undo his wife's restraint.

A couple and their three children were traveling behind him, Ramirez said. He noticed that a plane seat was lying on top of the man. He lifted the seat off him and then noticed that his own wife's face was covered in blood.

"I immediately grabbed her and tried to get her away because flames were coming from the plane," Ramirez said. "We tried to get away, but because my wife had a broken knee, I had to help remove her.

"A police patrol arrived minutes later, and they helped us and brought us to the clinic, where we were tended to as soon as possible."

Two residents of the metro Atlanta, Georgia, area were among those seriously injured.

Carolina Bellino said she and her husband, David, suffered fractured backs. She cannot move, Bellino said.

"He is worse than mine," she told ABC's "Good Morning America" on Tuesday.

Bellino, who said she is seven or eight weeks pregnant, recalled that she prayed until rescuers arrived.

"It's just like a nightmare, but I'm thankful because I'm alive," she said.

"It's a new beginning for us. You know you realize you can lose your life in just 20 seconds."

Colombian authorities say they are investigating whether the plane may have been hit by lightning or been buffeted by a severe downdraft.

One of the two pilots stood outside the wrecked plane shortly after the crash and described to a police videographer the flight's final moments. CNN affiliate Caracol TV played the recording Tuesday.

"We were caught in a great sinking as we reached the runway, as our wheels touched down," said the unnamed pilot, his face bloodied. "It threw us out. It threw us out. Nature is very strong."

The pilot paced back and forth before the camera, recounting his ordeal as crews worked on the plane just a few yards away.

"It grabbed us with everything it had," the pilot said. "I said, 'Landing' and cut, and when I was cutting, I started to level off, and I felt that the plane was going straight (down).

"I pulled [on the stick]. I pulled. I pulled. And the plane kept on going, kept on going. It was when we said, 'Landing.' When there's nothing left to do."

Survivors said they were unaware that anything had happened to the aircraft until the violent impact.

Ramirez, the industrial engineer, said he had seen lightning outside his window as the plane approached the airport.

"[But] I didn't feel any explosion," he told Caracol. "It's a miracle from God. Thanks to God we are all alive."

Hurtado also said he was unaware of any lightning striking the plane, as reported by some officials on the ground.

"That's what people say," Hurtado said. "Others [say] that the landing gear did not go down. But I don't know what happened. Only that it was horrible."

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="26aae0abca0c417fb236b1ef8e173748">
<name>0819 - Last U.S. combat convoy has left Iraq</name>
<content>Mosul, Iraq (CNN) -- The last U.S. brigade combat team has left Iraq, leaving about 56,000 U.S. troops in the country, according to the U.S. military.

Capt. Christopher Ophardt, spokesman for the 4th Stryker Brigade, 2nd Infantry Division, said the last of the 4,000 members of the unit were in armored vehicles crossing the border into Kuwait early Thursday.

A few hundred members stayed behind to finish administrative and logistical duties but will fly out of Baghdad later Thursday, Ophardt said.

Much of the brigade departed more than a day ago, but the announcement was delayed for security reasons.

Their departure comes more than seven years after U.S. combat forces entered, though their departure does not signify the end of all U.S. combat forces in the country.

Another 6,000 U.S. troops must leave Iraq to meet President Barack Obama's September 1 deadline for the end of U.S. combat operations in the country and the beginning of Operation New Dawn, in which U.S. forces are expected to play an advise-and-assist role.

A public information officer at Fort Lewis, Washington, said it will take a few weeks for all of the 4-2's members to return home. "It is one flight at a time," she said. "We are expecting most of them to be home by mid-September."

As they prepared to depart, some soldiers laughed and some expressed relief at having survived multiple deployments. A few reminisced about having endured firefights and helping carry the bodies of buddies off the field of battle. Many said they would never forget the war.

"The first time you get shot at, it's just, I mean, it wakes you up," said Sgt. Terry Wetzel, the company's senior sniper. "You think, before you come here, that you're an adult, that you're a grown man. But this place will change you."

Wetzel said he was ready to go home. "I feel like we have done as much as we can do here now. It's pretty much up to the Iraqi army and Iraqi police and their government," he said. "We have helped them out as much as we can."

"We put our blood, sweat and tears since we've been here for 12 months and we know we did our job and we know it's not going to be in vain, but there's a lot of excitement right now," said Spc. Don Lanpher as he prepared to depart.

"We're keeping the promise that we've made when I began my campaign for the presidency," U.S. President Barack Obama said Wednesday in Columbus, Ohio, where he was attending a Democratic fundraiser. "By the end of this month ... our combat mission will be over in Iraq."

Obama said that more than 90,000 U.S. troops have left Iraq in the past 18 months.

"And, consistent with our agreement with the Iraqi government, all of our troops will be out of Iraq by the end of next year," he said.

According to the Pentagon, 4,419 U.S. troops have died in Iraq.

Comments:

JTJONES It does not matter if you agree with the politicians or the reasons they were sent there the men and women of our armed forces deserve all of our utmost respect. 
1 minute ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
FOne 
Another lost war....Why was it lost?....because whoever started the freakin war didn't have a clue about the objectives....what was the definition of success in this "accomplished mission"?...I bet bush was fantasizing that the future Basrah would look like a small town in texas...and the whole coun... more 
Another lost war....Why was it lost?....because whoever started the freakin war didn't have a clue about the objectives....what was the definition of success in this "accomplished mission"?...I bet bush was fantasizing that the future Basrah would look like a small town in texas...and the whole country would turn into a pure democracy with democrats and republicans clashing to win the vote of anything that moves... less 
1 minute ago | Like | Report abuse  
kevin49 The Iraqi army is weak and will be overrun by the insurgents. 
1 minute ago | Like | Report abuse  
Cindy1234 Hurray to our troups coming home! I hope Afghanistan's war ends soon too. And I hope our leaders never ever get us involved in any more dumb wars! 
1 minute ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
gravey804 
You know, our reasons for going to Iraq are unjustified and at the same time unchangeable but I am proud to say that I served there. May all the families, friends, and my fellow comrades that have been injured or KIA, my prayers and blessings are with you. I am overwhelmed that this lie is finally c... more 
You know, our reasons for going to Iraq are unjustified and at the same time unchangeable but I am proud to say that I served there. May all the families, friends, and my fellow comrades that have been injured or KIA, my prayers and blessings are with you. I am overwhelmed that this lie is finally coming to a close. It doesn't matter what Congress or the President says because they've never fought there, they've only taken trips to stable grounds but I'm in Germany now and as the troops from Iraq return to the US, I ask of you all to welcome them with open arms, love, care, and patriotism. For many of them have been back and forth to Iraq since it started, some 6, 7, and 8 times. Now that we're almost done there, which all of our troops should be out by next August, it's time to get my comrades out of Afghanistan. Mr. President, if you want to continue nation building in countries, why not start with our own. We need the help! We can send food, water, etc. to other countries during crisis but we can't end our own homelessness in America. It's time to rebuild America for all people, black, white, latino, asian, KKK, Black Panthers, Bloods, Crypts, etc. If there is not changes being made by our leaders, how can we expect the different cultures, regions, gangs, supremacist, and others to change? God Bless America and God Bless You less 
2 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
Badger705 "...our reasons for going to Iraq are unjustified"

too bad you're parroting the slop the liberals are saying. 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Badger705 I'll never forget the day Saddam's sons got killed. That was a highlight for me. 
2 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
HockeyTime Captured... 0, Killed...2. 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Richardgwm Remind me, how many weapons of mass destruction did the US capture that day? 
1 minute ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Retspool Why did we attack Iraq again? 
3 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
Richardgwm Remember the Maine, Gulf of Tonkin, Weapons of Mass Destruction. Whenever they ask you to go to war, they are lying to you.

Never let them do it to you again. 
3 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
Mouldavi War and lies are always getting along. 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
Xchange Remember Pear Harbor. Slavery in the South and Boston tea party. Yes there are some reasons for war. 
1 minute ago | Like (1) | Report abuse 
 
Slag 
There are actually liberals on here that don't remember what Obama promised with respect to this war. Were any of you actually listening to his promises or were you just hearing what you wanted to hear. Or just maybe, you were so fed up with Bush, anything sounded better. Hey, but don't blame me for... more 
There are actually liberals on here that don't remember what Obama promised with respect to this war. Were any of you actually listening to his promises or were you just hearing what you wanted to hear. Or just maybe, you were so fed up with Bush, anything sounded better. Hey, but don't blame me for you failure to listen. less 
4 minutes ago | Like (6) | Report abuse 
 
TSAHfromVA Do you remember? If you did you will post it instead of EMPTY rhetoric! 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
permink 
Well so ends a mission we could have avoided. None the less, I applaud the troops for their service, we should all be very proud of them. Despite questionable motivation and leadership from Washington for years, the US military slugged it through and enabled the iraqi people to stand apart from tyra... more 
Well so ends a mission we could have avoided. None the less, I applaud the troops for their service, we should all be very proud of them. Despite questionable motivation and leadership from Washington for years, the US military slugged it through and enabled the iraqi people to stand apart from tyranny and despotism and let them taste freedom and democracy they never had. It has come at a price for our country and my hope is that what the american army has done in iraq will endure. less 
4 minutes ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
TSAHfromVA KUDOS for our troops!!! Most bloggers here forgot about that!! Their main concern is to continue to bash President Obama and/or try to take credit for the accomplishment (surge). Our brave men should be the only ones rewarded now and the Commander in Chief who is bringing them home!! 
4 minutes ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
Dan586 I forgot what day did Iraq attack the U.S. ? 
5 minutes ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
enelsprmo Well, at least Obama did not lie about pulling troops out... 
5 minutes ago | Like (2) | Report abuse 
 
Timothius Yes he did. You don't remember his campaigning??? What about the escalation in Afghanistan???? Well??? 
3 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
JonesBones End the War in Iraq, Wallstreet reform, Health-care reform, Stop oil leak, Make BP pay up, Get GM back on track, Extended Unemployment (which helped me A LOT now I have job again), Equal pay for women, diversified the Supreme Court, but I'm suppose to vote the Dems out? I don't think so. 
5 minutes ago | Like (9) | Report abuse 
 
JustaGuest Yes because Obama and the dems personally fixed the oil leak. I actually saw Nancy Pelosi down at the leak putting the cap on while Joe Biden was cleaning up the beach. 
4 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Davidji What I find creepy is how all of this is reminiscent of the footage of the last Soviet combat troops pulling out of Afghanistan a couple of decades ago. 
6 minutes ago | Like (3) | Report abuse 
 
TexasB yea, and look how well that worked out for everyone...right 
0 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse 
Load next 25 | View all comments </content>
<bookmark>2352</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="3f7a80ba619b4e908a1fc6c2ad2ae8fc">
<name>0820 - China: Mechanical failures to blame for North Korean plane crash</name>
<content>Beijing, China (CNN) -- Mechanical failures caused a North Korean air force plane to lose direction before crashing in northeastern China earlier this week, state media quoted Chinese authorities as saying Thursday.

China's official Xinhua news agency said that Pyongyang has apologized to Beijing for the incident and the two sides have "reached a consensus on dealing with the aftermath."

The plane went down Tuesday at Lagu township in Fushun county, killing the pilot and destroying one home on the ground. The crash site in Liaoning province is about 200 kilometers (120 miles) away from a North Korean air base in the border town of Sinuiju, according to South Korea's Yonhap news agency.

An employee at Songgang Iron Mine, a company near the crash site, told CNN Wednesday that armed police officers and special forces agents immediately cordoned off the area after the plane went down.

Photographs of the wreckage purportedly taken by an eyewitness have been circulating on Chinese websites, showing the North Korean air force emblem on the fuselage beneath the tail of the aircraft. Military enthusiasts online have identified it as a Russian-built MiG jet but differed on the specific model, with some calling it a MiG-21 fighter and others claiming it to be a MiG-15 trainer.

Xinhua's latest report did not give details on the plane.

Yonhap had earlier quoted unnamed sources in South Korea as saying the plane's pilot may have been trying to defect from North Korea to Russia. Chinese commentators had speculated that the plane may have run out of fuel.

Comments:

KLMIT To Zhongnanhai old men: Time to order N Korea to change its political system--let people choose their leader. Don't continue to use it as a chip to deal with US, Japan &amp; the West. You should begin to think about change too! 
47 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
KillCanadian 
U.S. and NATO officially lost the war in Iraq yesterday. Looks like they are going to lose the war in Afghanistan too. The U.S. and their useless NATO garbage still can't find that weak old man riding on a donkey up the mountains of Afghanistan after 9 years. And now Amadinejad and Kim Jong IL are... more 
U.S. and NATO officially lost the war in Iraq yesterday. Looks like they are going to lose the war in Afghanistan too. The U.S. and their useless NATO garbage still can't find that weak old man riding on a donkey up the mountains of Afghanistan after 9 years. And now Amadinejad and Kim Jong IL are toying around with U.S. and their NATO cowards and no one can do anything about it (other than doing some jumping jacks on board of a carrier which they called exercise). less 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Eatingbugs I guess Saddam Hussein is back in power then? 
35 minutes ago | Like | Report abuse  
MickOreilly he can waste* 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse  
MickOreilly he can waste* 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse  
MickOreilly 
The U.S. didn't lose any war. There was never going to be a winner. There's no winning or losing with change. There's only a different future with it. Only time will tell what the effects of the war are. Maybe Iraq will turn out well in 20 to 50 years. Ahmadinejad's own people hate him. He won't be ... more 
The U.S. didn't lose any war. There was never going to be a winner. There's no winning or losing with change. There's only a different future with it. Only time will tell what the effects of the war are. Maybe Iraq will turn out well in 20 to 50 years. 

Ahmadinejad's own people hate him. He won't be re-elected. He was waste all the time he wants "toying" with us. He knows he's powerless against the rest of the world and so does the dying Jong-Il. Why do you think South Korea and Israel are still in one piece? The world will never be content. Get used to it. less 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
UNIVERSALDOC North Korean fighters have the ejection seat rigged to kill the pilot if he tries to eject or if he deviates from the flight plan. lol Prove it isnt true. 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
CamaroRS In NK you eject plane 
1 hour ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
Eklipso Act of God? Lololol
No debris field and an alleged defection towards countries that'll send em back to N. Korea. and a newsfeed originating from??? So when does it move from an act to an omen then to a will. Lolololololol You will lose 
2 hours ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
CamaroRS Hahaha, act of God :-) 
2 hours ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
CamaroRS I wonder if he was planning to rendezvous with the tricycle bomber, you know, for a quick get away on landing. The knife wielding kindergarten killer was probably waiting to guard them. 
2 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
hayashi The pilot tried to defect to China, his flight path was almost a straight line from Sinuiju Korea to Shenyang China, and the plane crashed 27 km away from Shenyang International Airport. Russia is at completely opposite direction. 
2 hours ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
EvilWorm Spin control in overdrive. 

Defection attempt NOT mechanical problems. 
3 hours ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
mumblesj Wow. Happy to know that the North Koreans didn't automatically blame the imperialist West for this crash. Maybe they're coming around? NOT. 
3 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
pkfops Mechanical failures? The pilot would have ejected. He was either shot down by NK or the Chinese. The pilot was dead before the plane hit the ground. 
3 hours ago | Like (4) | Report abuse  
Guest8810 Funny - if any jet crashed within NK borders, they would consider it an act of war. 
4 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse 
 
Marty777 They shot down a South Korean airlines passendger jet! 
3 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
CamaroRS You can hardly consider a Mig-21 crashing an act of war. It's more like an act of God it got into the air in the first place. 
3 hours ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
Jake106 Mainly because North Korean airspace is declared off-limits to almost the entire world, so any plane flying over it would either be severely lost, or it actually WOULD be an act of war. 
3 hours ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
JackLumber So the defector lost directions did he? 
4 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
esmith512 
The plane in the picture is an older MiG-21. North Korea's military is deeply underfunded, the equipment old, safety equipment missing, broken, or intentionally disabled, and often the fuel loads too small to fly very far due to low funds and fears of pilot defections. A North Korean MiG-21 in Chi... more 
The plane in the picture is an older MiG-21. North Korea's military is deeply underfunded, the equipment old, safety equipment missing, broken, or intentionally disabled, and often the fuel loads too small to fly very far due to low funds and fears of pilot defections. A North Korean MiG-21 in China near North Korea is very probably a defecting pilot who ran out of fuel and tried to crash land the unglidable MiG. less 
4 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
JackLumber Yeah you can't build them with bamboo shoots and donkey dung anymore.
Well you can but they don't work very well. 
4 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  
Guest 
From the photo's it's clearly the back side of a MiG 21, possibly a BiS model from the dorsal hump. It has delta wings covered in bricks and debris, MiG 15's have sharply angled conventional wings.As to the reason??? Who knows, but if other posters are any indication, if you have a way to get out ... more 
From the photo's it's clearly the back side of a MiG 21, possibly a BiS model from the dorsal hump. It has delta wings covered in bricks and debris, MiG 15's have sharply angled conventional wings.

As to the reason??? Who knows, but if other posters are any indication, if you have a way to get out of there, you try. less 
4 hours ago | Like | Report abuse  

Barry77 The guy with the 1956 AAA road guide probably got something in his eye. 
</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="cbe6876612b54af49a6bd76eaa512628">
<name>0823 - How 12 dog breeds got their names</name>
<content>(Mental Floss) -- Every dog owner knows why they gave their dog its name, but how well do you know the story behind their breed names? Let's take a look at where a handful of common breeds found their monikers.

1. Jack Russell Terrier

Yep, Jack Russell was a real guy. 

John Russell was born in Dartmouth, England in 1795, and over the years he became quite a hunting enthusiast. While he was studying to become a clergyman at Oxford, he met a milkman who had a white terrier bitch named Trump who seemed to be the perfect dog for fox hunting. 

After convincing the milkman to sell him the dog, Russell began breeding Trump to develop a line of terriers with the stamina to hunt foxes all day and the courage to go after game that had slipped into holes.

Russell actually has two dogs named after him. We're all familiar with the Jack Russell terrier, but the Parson Russell terrier, a similar breed with longer legs, also takes its name from Russell and is recognized as a separate breed.

Acts of Good Sportsmanship

2. Lhasa Apso

The little dog's name sounds funny, but its origins are pretty straightforward. The Lhasa Apso was originally bred as a watchdog for Tibetan palaces and monasteries; it was hard for an intruder to sneak in past the watchful, yipping pooches. 

The "Lhasa" in the name comes from the city of Lhasa, Tibet's longtime capital. Apso is a Tibetan word meaning "bearded," so the breed's name signifies that it's a longhaired dog that originated in Tibet.

10 Unexpected Secret Service Duties

3. Basset Hound

The lovable big-eared hounds don't get their name from a person named Basset. Rather, "Basset" comes from the French word bas for "low" and refers to the dogs' low-slung statures.

4. Cairn Terrier

These feisty little terriers originated in the Scottish Highlands, where they were renowned for their abilities as hunters of rats and other small prey like rabbits. 

The dogs were particularly adept at hunting in the cairns, manmade piles of stones that dot the region as navigational markers. Thus, the breed became known as the Cairn terrier.

Mental Floss: 6 Utterly Loyal Dogs

5. Dalmatian

The spotted breed takes its name from Dalmatia, an Adriatic region that lies mostly within modern-day Croatia. Dalmatians have long been used as sentinels and guard dogs in the region, but it's not entirely clear that they originated there. 

Paintings and writings show Dalmatian-like dogs in various regions of Europe as far back as the 14th century, and the dogs have been used in Dalmatia since at least the 18th century. Since the dog was most commonly associated with the region, it became widely known as the Dalmatian.

6. Poodle

The poodle may be thought of as a fancy, snooty dog today, but it actually had fairly rough-and-tumble origins as a gun dog. Their name reflects their early work as retrievers who would swim out after fallen waterfowl. 

Pudeln was a Low German word that meant "to splash," so these brave retrievers were known as pudelhund, or "water dogs." The word eventually evolved into the English "poodle."

7. Weimaraner

The beautiful grey dogs with the expressive eyes have probably only been around since the 19th century. According to tradition, that's when Grand Duke Karl August of Weimar began to selectively breed hunting dogs that were fast, had strong noses, wouldn't back down from large game like wolves or wildcats, and were smart. 

Karl August's breed allegedly became fashionable among his fellow Weimar noblemen, and the breed gained popularity as a bird-hunting dog as well.

Oh, the Places Your Ashes Will Go!

8. Cocker Spaniel

Spaniels have been around as far back as the 14th century, and these popular pets also got their starts as gun dogs. English hunters prized the dogs' particularly skilled tracking of woodcocks, so the dogs became known as "cockers."

Mental Floss: Other Animals Dogs Will Adopt

9. Bouvier des Flandres

This herding dog's name is pretty straightforward if you know a bit of French. The breed originated in Flanders, and French farmers who prized their working spirits named the Bouvier des Flandres, which translates into "Cow herder of Flanders."

10. Dachshund

The dachshund is another breed with an unexpectedly ferocious origin. When the breed was first created in the early 17th century, hunters were attempting to create a fearless, elongated dog that could dig its way into a badger's hole and do battle with the tenacious little mammals. 

Their name reflects this early purpose; "dachshund" means "badger dog" in German.

11. Cavalier King Charles Spaniel

This spaniel takes its name from King Charles II of Britain, who was often depicted in paintings and tapestries in the company of a small spaniel and was reportedly "seldom seen without his little dogs."

Mental Floss: Dogs Welcoming Home Soldiers

12. Beagle

The exact origins of the word "beagle" are a bit mysterious, but anybody who has spent much time with the breed will believe the most commonly accepted story. The American Kennel Club traces the name back to the 16th century, when the hounds became associated with the French word becguele ("noisy person") thanks to the din of their howls during hunts.

Comments

holajohnson We have 3 retired greyhounds. We love the breed! So beautiful and interesting. They look so elegant when they run , but OMG they are soooo lazy :) 
8 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
1hippychick I have a pug....greatest dog and companion in the world! She always makes me laugh! Her name is Maggie.... 
11 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
Bj00000000 We have 2 Dachshund's. They are without a doubt the greatest friends you could every have. Oscar and Maggie, great pets, loyal companions, wonderful animals. Small in stature but hearts of a lion. 
12 hours ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
mrjude I love my badger dogs. 
13 hours ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
eddiew81 beagles are the best dogs in the world.i love my maybelle ( moo for her nick name) soooo much. 
20 hours ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
carter84262 
Although a cairn, or ca'rn, can be just a marker for any of several purposes in Scottland it is normally a group barial tomb and it is that use for which Cairn Terriers were generally used to guard. At least that is how I have heard it both from dog show people (I was involved with dog shows as a yo... more 
Although a cairn, or ca'rn, can be just a marker for any of several purposes in Scottland it is normally a group barial tomb and it is that use for which Cairn Terriers were generally used to guard. At least that is how I have heard it both from dog show people (I was involved with dog shows as a youngster but with other breeds such as Old English Sheepdogs...1 of my family's dogs was the top winner OES of all time from the late 60's until maybe 10 years or so after that) and from Scotts when I visited there 18 or so years ago. less 
22 hours ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
JoseCuerdo 
While its initial origins are unknown, "spaynels" are mentioned in 14th century writings.[1] It is commonly assumed that they originated in Spain and Edward of Norwich, 2nd Duke of York in his 15th century work The Master of Game introduces them as "Another kind of hound there is that be called houn... more 
While its initial origins are unknown, "spaynels" are mentioned in 14th century writings.[1] It is commonly assumed that they originated in Spain and Edward of Norwich, 2nd Duke of York in his 15th century work The Master of Game introduces them as "Another kind of hound there is that be called hounds for the hawk and spaniels, for their kind cometh from Spain, notwithstanding that there are many in other countries."[2] The Master of Game was mostly an English translation of an earlier 14th century Old French work by Gaston III of Foix-Barn entitled Livre de Chasse.[3] less 
1 day ago | Like (1) | Report abuse 
 
JoseCuerdo 
hey, how about that! According to Wikipedia, Cocker Spaniels were originally from Spain! Not bad! I wonder whether they were considered illegal alien dogs back in 14th Century England. And in case you're going to say not everything in Wikipedia is true..... yeah, right, that's what you say when it s... more 
hey, how about that! According to Wikipedia, Cocker Spaniels were originally from Spain! Not bad! I wonder whether they were considered illegal alien dogs back in 14th Century England.
And in case you're going to say not everything in Wikipedia is true..... yeah, right, that's what you say when it states something you don't like or believe in! less 
1 day ago | Like (1) | Report abuse 
 
yahute My dachshund really dislikes her breed to be placed inside a bun and have mustard and ketchup squirted on top. 
1 day ago | Like (5) | Report abuse  
goberdeen isnt the following statement inappropriate?

"he met a milkman who had a white bich named Tramp" 
1 day ago | Like (6) | Report abuse 
 
beelzel No, though funny in its structure. It is the proper use of a dog descriptive. Some think dating as far back as old Norse. 
1 day ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
SCY385 I was kind of hoping that someone would explain where my dog gets his breed name from. He's a Bichon Frise which sounds really snooty especially for the type of personality he has. He's more like the Labrador from the movie Marley &amp; Me. 
1 day ago | Like | Report abuse  
chedar Tell you what, if you can not afford a Lhasa Apso, find a breeder that have two breed. One Pekingese and another Bichon. Their offspring will be 99% Lhasa Apso look alike. It's when you can't not afford a Lhasa Apso that you try to breed them kind of a fake Lhasa Apso at half the price. 
1 day ago | Like | Report abuse 
 
tifoso 
Hold on a moment. You are telling someone who cannot afford one dog to get two dogs, breed them, then get, oh, say, five puppies to get something that looks like a Lhasa. Then what do you do with the other four? Have you ever worked out the actual costs of breeding a litter? Only the puppy mills... more 
Hold on a moment. You are telling someone who cannot afford one dog to get two dogs, breed them, then get, oh, say, five puppies to get something that looks like a Lhasa. Then what do you do with the other four? Have you ever worked out the actual costs of breeding a litter? Only the puppy mills and pet stores make a profit and that is because they cut every corner possible and breed every dog no matter how unsound. Besides, no matter what breed you get or even a mutt, you will have roughly the same expenses raising the dog. It has been shown time and again that buying quality is far cheaper than buying backyard bred dogs because the poorer quality dogs run up vet bills that dwarf the difference in purchase price. Bottom line is that if you want a Lhasa and cannot afford quality, you probably should not have a dog. This comes from over 35 years dog experience. less 
23 hours ago | Like (14) | Report abuse 
 
tifoso 
The myth persists that there is something called "hybrid vigor", that crossbreds are inherently healthier than purebreds. Those who favor crossbreds are often subject to what is called "selection bias", that is, they select the data the fits their theory. If someone breeds a poodle with a recessiv... more 
The myth persists that there is something called "hybrid vigor", that crossbreds are inherently healthier than purebreds. Those who favor crossbreds are often subject to what is called "selection bias", that is, they select the data the fits their theory. If someone breeds a poodle with a recessive gene for hip and elbow dysplasia to a Labrador with the same recessive genes, the fact that the dog is an outcross does not cancel the recessives. If the recessives pair up, the dog will be dysplastic. We are noticing that many Labradoodles have more problems than their PB ancestors. One of the reasons to avoid puppy mills and pet shops is that responsible breeders will do everything they can to reduce the chances of occurrence of genetic problems. Go to a pet shop and ask for the OFA or PennHip certificate of the parents. Pet shops get these puppies from wholesalers who buy from mills. The wholesalers often have no idea who the parents are. The mills are run on a profit motive so they do not pay to have the parents checked for hereditary problems. Now if you get one of these mill dogs and breed it to a dog of a different breed also from a mill, why does anyone believe the problems will magically disappear? less 
1 day ago | Like (5) | Report abuse  
CowboyVamp Funny story - true story - the Weimaraner originally bred to hunt down vampires. The place was lousy with them at the time. 
1 day ago | Like (1) | Report abuse  
aorist How about the Ann Coulter Beech. How did that dog get its name? 
1 day ago | Like (11) | Report abuse 
 
tifoso Don't call her a beech. That is an insult to beeches. 
23 hours ago | Like (7) | Report abuse 
 
cheetahsloth Rhodesian ridgeback- one of the coolest names for one of the most interesting breeds. Originally used for keeping lions at bey, and in some African cultures still are. They're like the Navy seals of the dog world... 
1 day ago | Like (3) | Report abuse 
 
tifoso Now called Zimbabwe Zipperbacks. OK. Not really. 
1 day ago | Like (4) | Report abuse 
 
BioHzrd420 Oh Basset Hounds. They are the sweetest dogs ever. And those eyes and ears :) 
1 day ago | Like (3) | Report abuse  
Marnie12 My friend's dog is a Schnoodle - half Schnauzer and half Poodle. That's all I got. 
1 day ago | Like (2) | Report abuse  
abueloloco3 
as current owner of 2 Jack Russell Terriers, my understanding is that when the AKC decided to recognize the breed the JR club (which apparently owns the name) expressed their displeasure because they feared the AKC would fit the JR into a rigid "box" (size, weight, coat, etc., etc.), so they said th... more 
as current owner of 2 Jack Russell Terriers, my understanding is that when the AKC decided to recognize the breed the JR club (which apparently owns the name) expressed their displeasure because they feared the AKC would fit the JR into a rigid "box" (size, weight, coat, etc., etc.), so they said the AKC could not use the name, hence the new term Parson Russell Terrier. same bloodlines, same genes, same dog. fantastic companions. less 
1 day ago | Like (4) | Report abuse 
 
tifoso 
Many of the so-called "recognized breeds" have varieties - Cockers, Dachshunds, Beagles, for example. Many breeds once split into multiples who now maintain independent stud books - Cairns and West Highland White Terriers. There are breeds divided by size and which compete in different variety gro... more 
Many of the so-called "recognized breeds" have varieties - Cockers, Dachshunds, Beagles, for example. Many breeds once split into multiples who now maintain independent stud books - Cairns and West Highland White Terriers. There are breeds divided by size and which compete in different variety groups - Toy, Mini, and Standard Poodles - one stud book. On the Russell Terriers - If the short-legged JRT's compete directly against the longer-legged PRT's, one or the other type will begin to disappear. There was a reason for the two types. less 
1 day ago | Like | Report abuse  
Microbial 
@abueloco3That's my understanding as well. I always find it amusing when JRT's are separated into "breeds"- the AKC is also introducing the "Russell Terrier" which are JRT's in the 10 to 12 inch height range. JRT's have always been more of a "type" then a "breed". There is such variation in size (10... more 
@abueloco3
That's my understanding as well. I always find it amusing when JRT's are separated into "breeds"- the AKC is also introducing the "Russell Terrier" which are JRT's in the 10 to 12 inch height range. 

JRT's have always been more of a "type" then a "breed". There is such variation in size (10 to 15 inches) due to changes in their hunting style. Initially long-legged fox hunters and then as fox hunting declined more shorter legged dogs were bred for badger/rodent hunting. 

Personally I prefer having one type of Jack Russell Terrier that encompasses all these varieties that retain their keen hunting instincts. Rather then divide up the type into breeds for the purposes of showing. 

I also agree they are wonderful companions. I currently have 2 tall JRT's and one shorty. :) less 
1 day ago | Like (3) | Report abuse 
Load next 25 | View all comments </content>
<bookmark>945</bookmark>
</TextBean></TextList>