<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TextList>
<TextTemplate>
<name/>
<content/>
<bookmark/>
</TextTemplate>
<TextBean UUID="a89a6c6d878141cfbd1b2885400dc632">
<name>Lesson 1:欢迎来到资讯王</name>
<content>SCENE① A 加州的资讯王达康办公室

【欢迎来到资讯王】

Dave: Welcome to InfoKing. I’m Dave. Looks like you’ve 1) inherited Bob’s 2) cubicle.

戴夫： 欢迎来到资讯王。我是戴夫。看来你已经接管了鲍伯的办公室隔间。

Zina: I’m Zina Romero. Sales. Who was Bob?

吉娜： 我是吉娜萝美洛。业务员。谁是鲍伯？

Dave: Bob was a totally 3) studly 4) programmer.

戴夫： 鲍伯是个彻头彻尾的壮男程序设计师。

Zina: Studly?

吉娜： 壮男?

Dave: You know. Big brain.

戴夫： 你知道嘛，就是头好壮壮。

Zina: His stuff is still 5) tacked up on the walls. Did he leave in a hurry?

吉娜： 他的东西还钉在墙上。他走得很匆忙吗？

Dave: The pressure got to him. Plus he wanted to get paid.

戴夫： 压力让他崩溃了。加上他又想拿到薪水。

语言详解

A: Sitting in a cubicle all day.

整天坐在隔间里。

B: What do you hate most about working in an office?

你最恨在办公室工作的哪一点。

【get to 影响，左右】

get to在对话中是指“影响，左右”，多半是指负面的情况：

A:The pressure has been really getting to me lately.

我最近真的被压力压得喘不过气来。

B:Maybe you should take a vacation.

或许你该去度个假。

get to的另一个常见用法是“抵达”，这个短语在问路时很好用，相信大家也都不陌生：

A:How can I get to the train station?

我要怎么才能到火车站？

B:It’s around the corner and to the left.

它就在转角那边靠左侧。

get to还有一个常见用法，意思是“得以，才能够”：

A:How did you get to be a politician?

你是如何才得以当政治人物的？

B:Many years of hard work.

多年的苦功。

1) inherit (v.) 继承

2) cubicle (n.) （办公室）隔间

3) studly 健壮帅气的，“猛男”是stud。

4) programmer (n.) 程序设计师

5) tack (v.) （用大头针）钉上

</content>
<bookmark>822</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="8f72c3c0b79642e197740052f2238548">
<name>Lesson 2:此话怎讲</name>
<content>SCENE① B 加州的资讯王达康办公室

【此话怎讲？】

Zina: What do you mean? If he was a good programmer, he should have been 1) raking it in.

吉娜： 此话怎讲？若他是个好的程序设计师，他应该早就发了。

Dave: The boss wanted to pay Bob with 2) stock options. But Bob didn’t want to play that game again.

戴夫： 老板想用认股权当作薪水付给鲍伯。可是鲍伯不想再次玩那种游戏了。

Zina: Again?

吉娜： 再次？

Dave: At his last 3) start-up, Bob worked for stock and no salary. They 4) folded and he made 5) zip.

戴夫： 鲍伯上回参与的创业公司，他工作的酬劳是股票，不拿薪水。他们的公司倒闭，他半毛也没拿到。

Zina: Ouch.

吉娜： 真惨。

Dave: Now he only works 6) freelance. Hundred 7) bucks an hour.

戴夫： 现在他只接个案做。时薪一百美元。

语言详解

A: Their business folded last week.

他们的店上星期倒了。

B: No, I can’t believe it! That was my favorite bookshop.

不，我不敢相信！那是我最爱的书店。

【What do you mean?这话怎讲？】

这是谈话时较随便的讲法，照说应该是What do you mean by that? 另一个类似句型是What does the word mean?”这个字作何解释？”mean 在这两个句型的“意思、意表”解。

mean 也作“打算”解，须要注意的是后面只能接不定词，不可接-ing式，例如:

Paul means to go to Taipei next week.

保罗打算下星期到台北去。

A: What do you mean by saying”Judy is leaving the country.”?

你说茱迪要出国是什么意思？

B: Well, she means to accept a job offer in Singapore.

她打算要接受新加坡的一个工作机会。

1) rake in 发财，大捞一笔

2) stock option 股票选择权，认股权

3) start-up (n.) 开始（创业，工作，动工等）

4) fold (v.) 关店，倒闭

5) zip (n.) 零，乌有

6) freelance (a.) 无约、自由工作的

7) buck美元

</content>
<bookmark>1114</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="b8b1d965113b4cb59bf06a763f976d0d">
<name>Lesson 3:你是怎么算薪水的</name>
<content>SCENE① C

Zina: How do you get paid? 1) If you don’t mind my asking.

吉娜： 你是怎么算薪水的？若你不介意我问的话。

Dave: Not cash. But if our 2) launch goes well, my stock options will pay off, big time.

戴夫： 不是现金。但要是我们上市的情况很好，我的股票期权可就值大钱了。

Zina: And in the meantime, how do you pay the rent?

吉娜： 那这段期间你要怎么付房租？

Dave: I don’t have to worry about rent. I live right here.

戴夫： 我不用担心房租。我就住在这里。

Zina: What? In your cubicle?

吉娜： 什么？在你的隔间里？

Dave: Right here. Me and my PC. Home sweet home.

戴夫： 就在这。我和我的个人电脑。甜蜜的家庭。

语言详解

A: We’re launched a new website.

我们推出了一个新网站。

B: That’s great. What’s the address?

太棒了。网址是什么？

【big time 超级，非常】

big time是在口语中常常可以听到的短语，用来强调句中程度的高，意即“超级，非常”，可以当做副词用：

A:I need to go to the bathroom, big time!

我得要上厕所，超急的！

B:There’s a toilet over there. Why don’t you go?

那里就有厕所。你为什么不去？

也可以当做形容词，写做big-time：

A:She is a big-time movie producer!

她是个大牌的电影制片！

B:Really? Why haven’t I heard of her before then?

真的？那怎么我以前从没听说过她？

1) If you don’t mind my asking. 若你不介意我问起的话。这是客气的询问句。要注意的是，mind 的后面要接动名词；而若提到是谁问的，则要用所有格。

2) launch (n., v.) 事业登场，投入市场

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="1da941c0dc6a4e339bb6a455af4f9120">
<name>Lesson 4:我会让你发财</name>
<content>SCENE② A 隔周，吉娜到老板的隔间去看他

【我会让你发财】

Zina: Hi, boss. You wanted to see me?

吉娜： 嗨，老板。你说要见我？

Vince: Zina. Look, I know when I 1) hired you, I told you I’d pay you a salary. But I just can’t.

文斯： 吉娜。听着，我知道当我雇用你之时，我说过会付你薪水。可是我没办法。

Zina: Excuse me? I hope I didn’t just hear what I think I just heard.

吉娜： 你说什么？我希望我不是真的听到我以为我听到的。

Vince: I know it’s 2) awkward, but you’re going to be thanking me later. I’m going to make you rich.

文斯： 我知道这说来尴尬，不过你以后会感谢我的。我会让你发财。

Zina: You’re going to make me rich by not paying me?

吉娜： 你要用不给我薪水的方法让我发财？

语言详解

A: How many people did the company hire this year?

公司在今年雇用了多少人？

B: Over two hundred.

超过两百个。

【look听着】

很奇怪，怎么英文的look会翻译成中文的“听着”？其实这正说明文化的差异。在英、美社会里，要对方在意你即将说的话，最普遍的语词是look，而我们在同样情况下却说“听着”。

A:Look, I’ll give you ten dollars if you sweep the room for me.

听着，如果你帮我扫房间，我就给你十块钱。

B:Sounds reasonable.

听起来蛮合理的。

1) hire (v.) 雇用

2) awkward (a.) 令人尴尬的的，感到尴尬的

</content>
<bookmark>504</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="37ca8416abbd4cd0945e1c0828650ec0">
<name>Lesson 5:我要提供你认股权</name>
<content>SCENE② B 隔周，吉娜到老板的隔间去看他

【我要提供你认股权】

Vince: I want to 1) offer you more InfoKing stock options.

文斯： 我要提供你资讯王的认股权。

Zina: When you hired me, you knew you were going to be low on cash, didn’t you?

吉娜： 你在雇用我的当时，就知道你会缺现金，对吧？

Vince: Let me explain. To get more cash, I’ll have to borrow more from Vikam, the 2) venture 3) capitalists.

文斯： 容我解释。为了要有更多现金，我就得跟投资我们的维康创投借更多的钱。

Zina: I know how it works. You don’t want to give away any more of your future 4) profits than you have to.

吉娜： 我知道这种运作方式。除非万不得已，你不会想把更多未来的利润拱手让人。

Vince: Exactly. Instead of 5) increasing their 6) position, I want to increase yours.

文斯： 正是。我不增加他们的股权，反倒要增加你的。

语言详解

A: I’m going to offer you a position in our sales department.

我要提供我们业务部的一个职位给你。

B: Thank you.

谢谢您。

【I know how it works. 我知道规矩。】

这里的work不是指“工作”，而是指“事物运作的道理与规范”，类似于行规的概念：

A:I am afraid we are going to have to fire you.

我恐怕我们得要开除你了。

B:It’s OK, I know how it works. You just don’t like me.

没关系，我知道行规。你就是看不惯我。

【give away 送掉】

give away 这个短语看起来很简单，不过有许多常用的意思，对话中所用到的give away 是指“赠送”。

A: Why did you give your bicycle away?

你为何把你的脚踏车送掉了？

B: It’s too old. I want to get a new one anyway.

那台太老了。反正我要换新的。

1) offer (v.) 提供

2) venture (n.) 具冒险性的事业

3) capitalist (n.) 出资者，金主，capital 是“资金”。

4) profit (n.) 利润

5) increase (v.) 增加

6) position (n.) 地位，此指“股权”。

</content>
<bookmark>1114</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="b621a90515b44faa9562e134b2bcfe99">
<name>Lesson 6:我可不便宜</name>
<content>SCENE② C 隔周，吉娜到老板的隔间去看他

　　【我可不便宜】

　　Zina: I’m not cheap.

　　吉娜：我可不便宜。

　　Vince: I’m prepared to increase your 1) stake to three percent.

　　文斯：我准备把你的股份增加至百分之三。

　　Zina: I’ve sold more 2) subscriptions to InfoKing in one week than you 3) expected me to sell in a month.

　　吉娜： 我一星期内所卖出资讯王的订阅数，就比你期望的月业绩要高了。

　　Vince: I know you’re good, Zina. You know how much three percent could be 4) worth, don’t you?

　　文斯： 我知道你很厉害，吉娜。你知道百分之三值多少钱，对吧？

　　Zina: Vince, I’m better than good. I’m the best. I want four percent.

　　吉娜： 文斯，我比厉害还要厉害。我是最棒的。我要百分之四。

　　Vince: Three-and-a-half.

　　文斯： 百分之三点五。

　　Zina: Done.

　　吉娜： 成交。

　　语言详解

　　A: I expect you to follow all the rules.

　　我希望你遵所有的规则。

　　B: Yes, ma’am!

　　遵命，夫人！

　　【subscription to 订阅】

　　subscription 或其动词subscribe 后面都要用介系词to才等于中文的订阅，例如：

　　I renew my subscription to Time Express.

　　我续订《时代杂志中文版》。

　　A:Many of my friends subscribe to the evening newspaper.

　　我的许多朋友订了那家晚报。

　　B:Why?

　　为什么？

　　A:Only because they want the free Teddy Bear.

　　只因为他们想要免费的熊宝宝。

　　1) stake (n.) 股份

　　2) subscription (n.) 订阅

　　3) expect (v.) 期待

　　4) worth (a.) 值得的

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="464654c701d14c3fb4d7a4fe06489307">
<name>Lesson 7:我开了一整晚夜车</name>
<content>SCENE③ A 吉娜一早进公司

　　Zina: Dave, 1) wake up.

　　吉娜： 戴夫，醒醒。

　　Dave: Whaah? Zina? What time is it?

　　戴夫： 啊？吉娜？现在几点了？

　　Zina: It’s seven-thirty. I want to know who left this note on my desk.

　　吉娜： 七点半。我要知道是谁在我桌上留了这张纸条。

　　Dave: What note? I can’t see. I just 2) pulled an all-nighter.

　　戴夫： 什么纸条？我看不到。我开了一整晚夜车。

　　Zina: It’s a little green 3) post-it note, 4) stuck right in the middle of my computer screen.

　　吉娜： 是小张的绿色便利贴，就粘在我电脑屏幕的中间。

　　Dave: And? What does it say? Isn’t there a name?

　　戴夫： 然后呢？上面写着什么？没有名字吗？

　　Zina: It says, “Zina, I like how you 5) rhumba. An 6) admirer.”

　　吉娜： 上面写着：“吉娜，我喜欢你跳伦巴的样子。仰慕者。”

　　语言详解

　　A: Where should I put this picture of Fiona?

　　我该把费欧娜这张照片摆哪儿？

　　B: Just stick it on your front door.

　　把它贴在你的前门就好了。

　　【It’s seven-thirty. 七点半。】

　　在这个句型中，it指时间。虽然这句话也可以简化为Seven-thirty.但还是用原句型较为适当。

　　it除了指时间以外，也用于指天气或距离，例如：

　　It’s very hot today.

　　今天天气很热。

　　It’s about 400 kilometers from Taipei to Kenting.

　　从台北到垦丁大约400公里。

　　A:How far is it from here to Hualien?

　　从这里到花莲有多远？

　　B:It’s about 150 kilometers.

　　大约150公里。

　　A:How is the weather like down there?

　　那里天气怎么样？

　　B:It’s raining at the moment.

　　此刻正在下雨。

　　1) wake up 醒来；awake是“醒着的”。

　　2) pull an all-nighter 开夜车，熬夜

　　3) post-it note 可贴的便条纸，系3M公司出品的办公用具，现已成为同类产品的代名词。

　　4) stick (v.) 粘贴

　　5) rhumba (n.) 伦巴舞

　　6) admirer (n.) 仰慕者，secret admirer 是“暗恋者”。

</content>
<bookmark>1261</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="3d4ea40542784124b0a838023564e17c">
<name>Lesson 8:我受不了电脑怪胎</name>
<content>SCENE③ B 吉娜一早进公司

　　【我受不了电脑怪胎】

　　Dave: Whoa. Now I’m awake! Zina has a secret admirer.

　　戴夫： 哇。这会我可醒了！吉娜有暗恋者了。

　　Zina: I really do not have time to deal with some 1) lovesick computer 2) geek.

　　吉娜： 我真的没时间去应付爱昏了头的电脑怪胎。

　　Dave: I know what you mean. I can’t stand computer geeks.

　　戴夫： 我知道你的意思。我也受不了电脑怪胎。

　　Zina: Sorry, Dave, I didn’t mean you. I am just not 3) in the mood for this. I have work to do.

　　吉娜： 抱歉，戴夫，我不是说你。我只是没心情搞这玩意儿。我还有工作要做。

　　Dave: Who do you think it is?

　　戴夫： 你觉得是谁？

　　语言详解

　　A: Your friend seems to be in a better mood.

　　你朋友的心情看起来好多了。

　　B: I gave her a pep talk.

　　我给她来了段精神讲话。

　　【I can’t stand… 我无法忍受……】

　　stand这个字大家一定都知道，但它除了“站”这个意思之外，最常用的就是指“忍受”，可以用在人身上：

　　A: Allison is my best friend.

　　爱丽森是我最好的朋友。

　　B: I can’t stand her. She is so fake!

　　我受不了她。她好假喔！

　　也可以用在事物身上：

　　A: It must be 45 degrees in here.

　　这里一定有四十五度。

　　B: I can’t stand it anymore. It’s too hot!

　　我再也受不了了。有够热的！

　　用来表示动作也行：

　　A: Let’s go have a beer at Tom’s.

　　我们去”汤姆的店”喝啤酒。

　　B: I can’t stand to go there. It reminds me of my ex-girlfriend.

　　我不能忍受去那里。那会让我想起我的前女友。

　　1) lovesick (a.) 因爱而分神迷乱的

　　2) geek (n.) 怪胎

　　3) be in the mood for有心情去…

</content>
<bookmark>411</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="82cbfcaf2d67444cb1833587bec08770">
<name>Lesson 9:你今天早来了</name>
<content>SCENE④ A 文斯顺道来吉娜的隔间看他

　　【你今天早来了】

　　Vince: Hey, Zina. You’re here early today.

　　文斯： 嗨，吉娜，你今天早来了。

　　Zina: Yeah, I’m going to be making phone calls all day. What a 1) blast.

　　吉娜： 对啊，我今天要打一整天的电话。真够好玩的。

　　Vince: I just wanted to say thanks for putting us on the map so fast. I 2) appreciate it.

　　文斯： 我只是想谢谢你那么快就让我们站上柜面了。我很感激。

　　Zina: Save it, Vince. After I put my first million in the bank, I’ll say you’re welcome.

　　吉娜： 省省吧，文斯。等我在银行存了第一个一百万，我会跟你说不客气的。

　　Vince: Fair enough. 3) Keep up the good work.

　　文斯： 很公平。再接再励。

　　语言详解

　　A: Here are those tools you wanted to borrow.

　　这些是你想要借的工具。

　　B: Thanks a million. I really appreciate it.

　　千恩万谢。我真的很感激。

　　【Save it. 你省省吧。】

　　save是“存，省下”的意思，而Save it.在对话中用做短句，意思是“省省吧。”，告诉对方多说无益。而save it for的句型也很常用，意思是“替……预留”，请看以下的实际例子：

　　A:I wasn’t drinking, officer; I just didn’t see the red light.

　　警官，我没有喝酒；我只是没看到红灯。

　　B:Save it for the judge.

　　这些话你留着去跟法官说吧。

　　A:I love this movie! I want to watch it, too.

　　我好爱这部电影！我也要去看。

　　B:OK. I’ll save it for tonight when you get home from work.

　　好。我就把这部电影留到今晚，等你下班回家一起看。

　　1) blast (n.) 尽兴，玩得愉快

　　2) appreciate (v.) 感激

　　3) Keep up the good work. 再接再励

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="066aa35a382b4b979e9e203dc2b573d4">
<name>Lesson 10:万一他就是你那伦巴男孩呢</name>
<content>SCENE⑤ A 戴夫由上方探头，进吉娜的隔间

　　【万一他就是你那伦巴男孩呢？】

　　Dave: Hey, Zina. You shouldn’t act so tough with Vince. 1) What if he’s your rhumba boy?

　　戴夫： 嘿，吉娜。你不该故意对文斯那么凶巴巴的。万一他就是你那伦巴男孩呢？

　　Zina: Please. He’s only nice to me because I’m making him a ton of money.

　　吉娜： 拜托喔。他对我好只是因为我在帮他赚大钱。

　　Dave: He was definitely happy. You must be making a lot of sales.

　　戴夫： 他真是高兴得很。你一定做成了很多买卖。

　　Zina: It isn’t hard. All the 2) online businesses need a way to 3) keep track of the 4) traffic to their 5) sites.

　　吉娜： 这不难。所有的线上商务都需要设法掌握他们网站的流量。

　　Dave: That’s InfoKing. Tracks every visitor. Or at least it will, if we can get it to work.

　　戴夫： 这就是资讯王。掌握每一位访客。或者至少以后会是这样，若我们能让做出来的东西管用。

　　语言详解

　　A: I can’t get online.

　　我连不上线。

　　B: There must be too many other people using the Internet.

　　一定是有太多人上网了。

　　【act tough with… 故作强硬】

　　tough 这个字，指的是“强悍的”，若要说“对……很强悍、强硬”就是be tough with…，对话中用了act这个字，act tough with听来的感觉倾向于“故意装得很强硬”。

　　A: I’m so angry. I could hit you in the face.

　　我好生气。我真想揍你的脸。

　　B: Don’t you act so tough with me. I know you couldn’t hurt a fly.

　　你别跟我故作强硬。我知道你连只苍蝇都舍不得杀。

　　【get it to work 让它运作】

　　get…to work这个句型，若是用在事物身上，是指“让……能够运作”，可能是指草创的新东西，或是某个窒碍难行的制度，也可以单纯指东西坏了：

　　A: My car broke down again.

　　我的车又坏了。

　　B: I bet I can get it to work. Where is it?

　　我打赌能让它上路。车子在哪里？

　　1) what if… 万一，要是……

　　2) online (a.) 连上电脑网路的，线上的

　　3) keep track of… 随时掌握……

　　4) traffic (n.) 此指“网站的流量”

　　5) site (n.)“网站”，即website

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="91a3f9488b5a440b8ef845bb187becf7">
<name>Lesson 11:你要知道动机何在吗</name>
<content>SCENE⑤ B 戴夫由上方探头，进吉娜的隔间

　　【你要知道动机何在吗？】

　　Zina: Do you want to know what really 1) motivates Vince to be nice to me?

　　吉娜： 你要知道文斯对我好的动机何在吗？

　　Dave: OK. What?

　　戴夫： 好啊。是什么？

　　Zina: It isn’t 2) gratitude. It’s fear. Vince is afraid I’ll 3) jump to a 4) competitor.

　　吉娜： 那不是感激。是恐惧。文斯怕我会跳出去帮竞争对手。

　　Dave: You wouldn’t do that. Would you?

　　戴夫： 你不会这么做，对吧？

　　Zina: I might. Vince knows he needs to keep me happy.

　　吉娜： 我或许会喔。文斯知道他得让我保持快乐。

　　Dave: What about your 5) accounts?

　　戴夫： 那你的客户呢？

　　语言详解

　　A: Man, that guy was a really good boxer.

　　天啊，那家伙真是个好拳手。

　　B: You fought a good fight. But your next competitor will be even tougher.

　　你打了场好拳。但是你的下个对手将会更强。

　　【nice to me 对我好】

　　nice to 后面接“人”时，表示“友善、随和”的意思，例如：

　　Grandma was nice to me when I visited her.

　　我去探望祖母时她对我很友善。

　　We should all be nice to the new-comer.

　　我们应该对那位新来的人客气些。

　　【I might. 我可能会】

　　在英文中谈论”可能”的情态助动词（modals）有好几个，包括might, could, may, must。大致上，might表示的”可能”是最低，而must最高。

　　Tina might be sick.（少于50%可能）

　　Tina could be sick.（约50%可能）

　　Tina may be sick. （约50%可能）

　　Tina must be sick. （约90%可能）

　　1) motivate (v.) 给……动机

　　2) gratitude (n.) 感激

　　3) jump to… 换（公司），尤指违反合约的情况。

　　4) competitor (n.)竞争者

　　5) account (n.) 客户，尤指生意上往来的客户。

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="194b63b314d74d7c8fbe09131d559dd5">
<name>Lesson 12:这是生意经 </name>
<content>SCENE⑤ C 戴夫由上方探头，进吉娜的隔间

　　【这是生意经】

　　Zina: My accounts go where I go. Vince knows that.

　　吉娜： 我到哪里，客户就跟到哪。文斯知道的。

　　Dave: Wow. You are a real snake.

　　戴夫： 哇。你真狡猾。

　　Zina: It’s business, Dave.

　　吉娜： 这是生意经，戴夫。

　　Dave: I know, I know. Kill, or die, right?

　　戴夫： 我知道，我知道。不是杀人就是被杀，对吧？

　　Zina: Right. The 1) faint of heart should not 2) apply.

　　吉娜： 没错。绝对不可以显得胆小。

　　Dave: I really feel sorry for that rhumba boy if he ever 3) identifies himself.

　　戴夫： 若那个伦巴男孩现身，我还真会替他感到难过。

　　Zina: So do I.

　　吉娜： 我也是。

　　语言详解

　　A: She applied so much make-up to her face that I don’t recognize her anymore.

　　她在脸上用了好多化妆品，我都认不出她来了。

　　B: I thought she was wearing a mask.

　　我还以为她戴了面具呢。

　　【So do I. 我也是。】

　　谈话中对方提到某种想法或动作，而你要表示同感时常会用到这个句型，要注意助动词do要置于主词 I 之前。类似的句型还有So am I.也表示“我也是”。

　　使用So do I 或So am I 取决于对方是否使用be动词，使用be 动词则用So am I，其他动词则用So do I. 。

　　A: I want to find out where John is.

　　我想要找出约翰到底在哪里。

　　B: So do I.

　　我也是。

　　A: I’m anxious to know if I’m admitted to the college.

　　我急于想知道我是否被那所大学录取了。

　　B: So am I.

　　我也是。

　　1) faint of heart 心生畏惧

　　2) apply (v.) 适用，运用

　　3) identify oneself 表明身分

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="9477c0dbaac2471ca8c944023a0e0d60">
<name>Lesson 13:另一张绿色便条纸</name>
<content>SCENE① A 加州的资讯王办公室

　　【另一张绿色便条纸】

　　Zina: Dave! Look at this!

　　吉娜： 戴夫！你看这个！

　　Dave: You don’t have to yell, Zina. I’m just one 1) cubicle away.

　　戴夫： 你不必用喊的，吉娜。我才离你一个隔间而已。

　　Zina: Somebody left another green post-it note.

　　吉娜： 有人留了另一张绿色便条纸。

　　Dave: Was it your “humba boy” again?

　　戴夫： 又是你那个“伦巴男孩”啊？

　　Zina: It says, “You look so 2) frail, / but I know you’re tough like a nail. / To me, you are more beautiful than free e-mail.”

　　吉娜： 上面写着：“你看来娇柔，但我知道你如钢铁般强韧。对我来说，你比免费的伊妹儿还要讨人喜欢。”

　　Dave: Wow. He really likes you, doesn’t he?

　　戴夫： 哇，他还真喜欢你，不是吗

　　语言详解

　　A: Brian went off in class and yelled at the teacher.

　　布莱恩在课堂上情绪失控还对老师大喊。

　　B: That guy is totally out of control.

　　那家伙真是 完全失去控制了。

　　【doesn’t he? 不是吗？】

　　这是所谓附加疑问句，是添加在句末的问句，是为了确定自己讯息正确或为了得到对方的赞同。肯定附加疑问句希望得到否定回答，否定附加疑问句希望获得肯定回答。

　　A: This is the book that you want,isn’t it?

　　这是你要的那本书，不是吗？

　　B: Yes, it is.

　　正是。

　　A: You don’t like coffee, do you?

　　你不喜欢咖啡，是吗？

　　B: No, I don’t.

　　对，我不喜欢。

　　1）cubicle (n.) (办公室) 隔间

　　2) frail (a.) 柔弱的

</content>
<bookmark>331</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="5c6c76ea0abf44c289684c7b30d368f4">
<name>Lesson 14:有谁一早就在这里了 </name>
<content>SCENE① B 加州的资讯王办公室

　　【有谁一早就在这里了？】

　　Zina: Who has been here already this morning?

　　吉娜： 今天有谁一早就在这里了？

　　Dave: Well, Vince dropped off some sales reports for you. Said you signed a big deal with HomeSupplies.com.

　　戴夫： 呃，文斯丢了一些销售报告给你。说你签下了HomeSupplies.com这个大客户。

　　Zina: They’re 1) small fry. Tonight I’m going to LA to 2) negotiate with Stars.com. That’ll be big.

　　吉娜： 小菜一碟。我今晚要飞去洛杉矶跟Stars.com协商。那可大了。

　　Dave: You’re right. All the 3) entertainment web sites follow Stars.com.

　　戴夫： 没错。所有的娱乐网站都以Stars.com马首是瞻。

　　Zina: Who else has been here?

　　吉娜： 还有谁到过这里来？

　　Dave: Elvin stopped by to see me.

　　戴夫： 艾文顺道过来找了我一会儿。

　　Zina: Elvin? Which one is he?

　　吉娜： 艾文？他是哪一个啊？

　　语言详解

　　A: Did you sign a contract before agreeing to work for him?

　　在你同意为他工作前先签合约了吗？

　　B: He told me we would do it later.

　　他说那个晚点儿 再签。

　　【stop by 顺道拜访】

　　stop by是指你在要去一个地方的途中，因为顺路而到某人家拜访：

　　A:I was going to the store and thought I would stop by.

　　我正要去店里，就想可以顺道过来。

　　B:I’m so glad you did!

　　我真高兴你来了！

　　stop by也可以用来表达“稍作停留，不会久留”的意思：

　　A: I just stopped by to see if you needed anything.

　　我只是过来看一下你是否需要什么。

　　B: I need some more cough medicine.

　　我还需要多一些咳嗽药。

　　1) small fry 微不足道的事

　　2) negotiate (v.) 协商，协调

　　3) entertainment (n.) 娱乐

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="b7bce426172b40f6987492f1168743c3">
<name>Lesson 15:集怪胎与朋克于一身 </name>
<content>SCENE① C 加州的资讯王办公室

　　【集怪胎与朋克于一身】

　　Dave: You don’t know Elvin? 1) Studly programmer 2) numero uno? With the 3) ponytail and nose ring?

　　戴夫： 你不认识艾文？那个头好壮壮，叫我第一名的程序设计师？绑马尾穿鼻环的那个？

　　Zina: Great. A 4) geek and a 5) punk all rolled into one. Just my type.

　　吉娜： 好极了。集怪胎与朋克于一身。正合我意。

　　Dave: You think he’s the one?

　　戴夫： 你觉得那个人就是他？

　　Zina: Could be. He sounds like a 6) prime suspect.

　　吉娜： 有可能。他听起来很像头号嫌疑犯。

　　Dave: What about your 7) assistant? She was here looking for you just now.

　　戴夫： 那你的助理呢？她刚刚才来找过你。

　　Zina: Mary? Please, Dave. Anyway, I know it couldn’t be her. She has a boyfriend.

　　吉娜： 玛莉？帮帮忙，戴夫。反正我知道不可能是她。她有男朋友了。

　　Dave: Yeah, but I bet he’s nothing like you.

　　戴夫： 是啊，但我敢说他跟你可不一样。

　　语言详解:

　　A: What’s your job title?

　　你的职称是什么？

　　B: I’m an assistant professor of chemistry.

　　我是化学系的助理教授。

　　【be nothing like… 可不像……】

　　be nothing like…这个句型可以用来比较两个人的不同：

　　A: Your sister is nothing like you.

　　你的姐姐跟你完全不像。

　　B: I know, she’s much more independent than I am.

　　我知道。她比我独立多了。

　　除了比较人以外，你也可以用这个句型来对事物或是地方做比较，可以是好，可以是坏：

　　A: This job is nothing like the one I used to have.

　　这个工作跟我以前的是两个样。

　　B: Hang in there. Maybe it will get better.

　　撑着点。或许情况会好转的。

　　1) studly (a.) (俚) 健壮帅气的

　　2) numero uno（意，西）即 number one “第一名，头号人物”。

　　3) ponytail (n.)（发饰）马尾

　　4) geek (n.) 怪胎

　　5) punk (n.) 朋克，指发型服饰怪异新潮的族群，指源于美国70年代因摇滚乐兴起的运动。

　　6) prime suspect 头号嫌疑犯

　　7) assistant (n.) 助手

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="71dc87a1fe9d4ec4a96ab3543bd8e22a">
<name>Lesson 16:我不敢居功 </name>
<content>SCENE② A 艾文与玛莉在意式浓缩咖啡前出现

　　【我不敢居功】

　　Mary: Are you Elvin?

　　玛莉： 你是艾文吗？

　　Elvin: Elvin Dixon. Who are you?

　　艾文： 艾文迪克森。你是谁？

　　Mary: I’m Mary. I want to say I really 1) admire the software you’re designed.

　　玛莉： 我是玛莉。我真的很欣赏你设计的软件。

　　Elvin: Easy stuff. But thanks. And the 1)admiration is 2) mutual.

　　艾文： 简单的玩意。不过还是谢了。这份欣赏是彼此彼此。

　　Mary: It is?

　　玛莉： 真的？

　　Elvin: You’re selling InfoKing 3) subscriptions like nobody’s business. And we don’t even have a working 4) demo yet.

　　艾文： 你把“资讯王”的订阅卖得如入无人之境。 而我们甚至连能用的样品都还没着落呢。

　　Mary: I can’t take the credit for that. I’m just Zina’s assistant. She’s the 5) pro.

　　玛莉： 我不敢居功。我只是吉娜的助手。她才是高手。

　　语言详解

　　A: Here’s a demo of our product.

　　这是我们产品的样品。

　　B: Thank you. I’ll take a look at it and get back in touch with you.

　　谢谢。我看过之后再联络你。

　　【like nobody’s business 如入无人之境】

　　like nobody’s business可以用来表达“无人能出其右”，形容此人相当有一手：

　　A: They play the blues like nobody’s business.

　　他们演奏蓝调的技巧无人能敌。

　　B: I have to go and see them.

　　我一定要去看看他们。

　　【take the credit居功】

　　credit是“功劳，赞扬”的意思，take the credit就是指“因为功劳而接受赞扬”，可以用在正面的“居功”。

　　A: Josh, you are amazing!

　　乔许，你真是令人不可思议！

　　B: I can’t take the credit for this job. We all worked hard on it.

　　这工作我不能居功。大家都很努力。

　　1) admire (v.) 仰慕，钦羡；名词是admiration

　　2) mutual (a.) 互相的

　　3) subscription (n.) 订阅

　　4) demo (n.) （商品的）样品，demonstration的略缩。

　　5) pro (n.) 专家，系professional 的略缩

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="921c1e6b3c3646ef96002b7b6131cdf7">
<name>Lesson 17:她整个人热力四射 </name>
<content>SCENE② B 艾文与玛莉在意式浓缩咖啡前出现

【她整个人热力四射】

Elvin: She is, like, 1) mega-intense, isn’t she?

艾文： 她整个人热力四射，对吧？

Mary: Ha, she is unstoppable. I’m learning so much from her.

玛莉： 没有事情能挡得住她。我跟她学了好多。

Elvin: What’s it like to work with her?

艾文： 跟她共事是啥感觉？

Mary: She’s 2) demanding. But I like that. I mean, I know our timeline is tight.

玛莉： 她的要求很高。但我喜欢那样。我是说，我知道我们的时间很紧。

Elvin: Tell me about it.

艾文： 这还用说。

Mary: You guys are working around the clock, I know. That guy Dave next to Zina never leaves.

玛莉： 我知道你们都在二十四小时赶工。那个坐在吉娜隔壁叫戴夫的人从没离开过。

Elvin: Vince wants us to have everything 3) debugged and ready to go by the end of the month.

艾文： 文斯要我们把程序错误全部修正，准备在月底前上线。

语言详解

A: Your mother is so demanding!

你妈妈的要求真高！

B: That’s what my dad always says.

我爸爸也总是这么说。

【around the clock 日以继夜】

由clock 组成的成语除了around the clock 之外，另有一个against the clock“赶时间”。

A: Frank, why does your factory have to work around the clock this month?

佛兰克，为什么你们工厂这个月要日以继夜地赶货？

B: Well, we have got quite a lot of orders for shipment this quarter.

我们最近收到相当多订单，都要这一季出货。

A: In other words, you are all working against the clock now.

换句话说，你们现在全都在赶时间。

B: You’re right.

你说对了。

1) mega-intense intense是指“紧张的、一触即发的”，字首(prefix) mega是“非常，相当多”的意思，亦指 “百万的”，如 megabyte“百万位元组”。

2) demanding (a.) 要求很高的

3) debug (v.) （电脑）除虫，指修正电脑程序中的错误。

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="7490a988f3694217925e0a32ada125f7">
<name>Lesson 18:我们得要抢先完成 </name>
<content>SCENE② C 艾文与玛莉在意式浓缩咖啡前出现

　　【我们得要抢先完成】

　　Mary: Is it true that one of our 1) competitors is planning to 2) launch their 3) tracking service next month?

　　玛莉： 听说我们有个竞争对手打算下个月推出监测流量的服务，这是真的还是假的？

　　Elvin: That would be “WebTracker”. We’re heard they’re almost ready. That’s why we have to finish first.

　　艾文： 你说的是“网路搜寻家”。听说他们几乎准备好了。所以我们得要抢先完成。

　　Mary: Or they’ll take over the market before we even get started.

　　玛莉： 否则在我们还没来得及开始之前，他们就会占去整个市场。

　　Elvin: Right. And that would be a total 4) giga-bummer.

　　艾文： 没错。到时就一败涂地了。

　　Mary: I guess we’d better get back to work.

　　玛莉： 我猜我们最好赶快回去工作吧

　　语言详解

　　A: You have such a strange accent. Where are you from?

　　你的口音奇怪。你是哪里人？

　　B: Take a guess.

　　猜猜看。

　　【take over 接掌、占据】

　　take over 表达商务上或军事上的“接掌、占据”。

　　A: Once again, the military has taken over the African country.

　　又一次军方接管了那个非洲国家。

　　B: Do you think that’ll interrupt your plan of taking over the market there?

　　你想这会干扰到你要掌控该地市场的计划吗？

　　A: Maybe and maybe not. I just have to wait and see.

　　或许会，或许不会。我只有等着瞧了。

　　1) competitor (n.) 竞争者

　　2) launch (v.) 事业登场，投入市场

　　3) tracking service 监控服务，此指“监控网站流量的服务”。

　　4) giga-bummer bummer是指“倒霉、不幸的遭遇”， giga这个“字首” 是指“十亿”，意即“非常巨大，非常多”。

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="6168d5151a5b4946bec074cec0938970">
<name>Lesson 19:我就不拐弯抹角了</name>
<content>SCENE③ A 吉娜去她老板的隔间看他

　　【我就不拐弯抹角了】

　　Zina: Vince. We’re both busy, so I’m not going to beat around the bush. I need a 1) raise.

　　吉娜： 文斯。大家都很忙，我就不拐弯抹角了。我要加薪。

　　Vince: I can’t do that, Zina. You know I can’t.

　　文斯： 办不到，吉娜。你知道我无能为力的。

　　Zina: 2) Bull. I’re done my 3) research. I know you still 4) control more than 65 percent of InfoKing 5) options.

　　吉娜： 胡扯。我做了研究。我知道你仍掌握了“资讯王”百分之六十五以上的股权。

　　Vince: Who told you that?

　　文斯： 谁跟你说的？

　　Zina: That doesn’t matter. I want 6) at least 4 percent.

　　吉娜： 那不重要。我少说要百分之四。

　　语言详解

　　A: I have done extensive research on the French Revolution.

　　我对法国大革命做过广泛的研究。

　　B: Then you must have been to Paris.

　　那你一定去过巴黎。

　　【beat around the bush拐弯抹角】

　　beat around the bush原意是指猎人在打猎时，先在草丛附近拍打，以让鸟类猎物受惊而现出踪迹，引申出藉由迂回的方式，不针对问题回答，犹如中文里的“拐弯抹角”：

　　A: Stop beating around the bush, and tell me what you want.

　　别拐弯抹角，告诉我你要什么。

　　B: I want a divorce.

　　我要离婚。

　　A: What did Tom want to tell you?

　　汤姆那时想要跟你说什么？

　　B: I’m not sure. He kept beating around the bush.

　　我不确定。他一直在拐弯抹角。

　　1）raise (n.) 加薪

　　2) bull 原意是“公牛”，这里是用作 bullshit 委婉说法。

　　3) research (n.) 研究

　　4) control (v.) 控制

　　5) option (n.) 选择，此指“股票选择权”

　　6) at least 至少，起码

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="5f1f80ef7d614642a79436234d7e17f4">
<name>Lesson 20:我得要有动力</name>
<content>SCENE③ B 吉娜去她老板的隔间看他

　　【我得要有动力】

　　Vince: Your 3.5 percent 1) share is going to be worth at least a million.

　　文斯： 你那百分之三·五的股权，将会值个百万以上。

　　Zina: I need to be 2) motivated, Vince. 3) Multi-motivated. As in multi-million.

　　吉娜： 我得要有动力，文斯。多重动力，多重百万的多重。

　　Vince: What if I said no?

　　文斯： 要是我说不呢？

　　Zina: Ever hear of WebTracker?

　　吉娜： 有听过“网路搜寻家”吗？

　　Vince: You wouldn’t! If you leave, you’ll make nothing.

　　文斯： 你不会那样吧！你若是离开，连半毛都赚不到。

　　Zina: I might make nothing even if I stay. For that kind of risk, I want to get rich.

　　吉娜： 我留下搞不好也赚不到半毛。 基于这种风险，我要发财。

　　Vince: OK. If you sign the Stars.com 4) account before WebTracker does, we’ll talk next week.

　　文斯： 好吧。若是你早“网路搜寻家”一步签下Stars.com这个客户，我们就等下星期再谈。

　　语言详解

　　A: Don’t you want to go and exercise?

　　你不想在运动吗？

　　B: Yes, but I can’t seem to get motivated.

　　想，可是我没有动力。

　　【用 as in… 做补述】

　　as in这个短语是用来补述，好让意思能让人更明白，常用在解释拼字的时候：

　　A: My name is Meg.

　　我叫做梅格。

　　B: Is that M as in Mary, E as in elephant, and G as in girl?

　　那是Mary的m、elephant的e，girl的g吗？

　　as in可以用来进一步解释情况，犹如中文里的“像……那种”：

　　A: I just ate a Chinese buffet for only 2.99 dollars.

　　我刚只花了2.99美元吃了份中式自助餐。

　　B: As in the all-you-can-eat kind? That’s so cheap!

　　是吃到饱的那种吗？还真便宜！

　　你也可以用as in来提问，以确定自己没有误会对方的意思:

　　A: I made a million last year.

　　我去年赚了一百万。

　　B: Is that as in dollars?

　　你说的一百万是美元吗？

　　1) share (n.) 股份

　　2) motivate (v.) 给予……动力

　　3) multi “多重的”字首

　　4) account (n.) 客户，尤指生意上往来的客

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="3724e57d226b4c66b3815849cb0d7b13">
<name> Lesson 21:你真是心狠手辣</name>
<content>SCENE③ C 吉娜去她老板的隔间看他

　　【你真是心狠手辣】

　　Zina: No, Vince, not next week. Now. You need to 1) guarantee me 5 percent.

　　吉娜： 不，文斯，下星期不成。我要你现在就保证我能拿百分之五。

　　Vince: But you just said 4 percent!

　　文斯： 但你才刚说过百分之四的！

　　Zina: If the next word out of your mouth isn’t “Yes” it’s going up to 6 percent.

　　吉娜： 若是下一个从你嘴中冒出来的字不是“好”，就会涨到百分之六了。

　　Vince: Yes! OK, yes. Stop it! You are just 2) ruthless.

　　文斯： 好！好就好吧。别再来了。你真是心狠手辣。

　　Zina: That’s why you love me. One other thing. Did you leave me a note this morning on a green post-it?

　　吉娜： 所以你才爱我啊。还有件事。你今天有留张绿色便利贴在我桌上吗？

　　Vince: I don’t think so. Mine are yellow. Why?

　　文斯： 我想没有吧。我的是黄色的。怎么？

　　Zina: 3) Never mind. I’m looking for somebody who uses green.

　　吉娜： 别放在心上。我在找用绿色的人。

　　语言详解

　　A: Can you guarantee me that I will like this product?

　　你能跟我保证我会喜欢这个产品吗？

　　B: Oh, yes. Otherwise we will give you back your money.

　　能。否则我们就会退还你的钱。

　　【I don’t think so. 我想没有吧】

　　这个句型是柔性的”No”，潇洒地否定对方刚提到的事或说过的话。

　　A: Is there anything else you want to tell me about?

　　还有其他什么事要告诉我的吗？

　　B: I don’t think so.

　　我想没有吧。

　　A: It looks like rain.

　　好像下雨了。

　　B: I don’t think so.

　　我想没有吧。

　　1）guarantee (v.) 保证

　　2) ruthless (a.) 冷血无情的

　　3) Never mind. 别在意，别放在心上

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="bd2501dd8a0d49669f3ba45d4e69c319">
<name>Lesson 22:你打算回应他吗? </name>
<content>SCENE④ A 吉娜和戴夫在隔间里

　　【你打算回应他吗？】

　　Zina: He’s been here again.

　　吉娜： 他又到过这里了。

　　Dave: Rhumba Boy? What did he write this time?

　　戴夫： 伦巴男孩？他这次写了什么？

　　Zina: I am not mean. / Actually, I am quite clean. / Will you be my queen? / Answer me in green, / on your computer screen./

　　吉娜： “我不卑鄙。 其实我很干净。汝愿当吾手中玉？用绿色的纸回答我，在你的电脑屏幕上。”

　　Dave: Are you going to answer him?

　　戴夫： 你打算回应他吗？

　　Zina: Yes.” don’t like your green notes. / They make me see red. / Show your head, / and you’ll 1) end up dead.”

　　吉娜： 对。“我不爱你的绿纸条。它们让我气得脸通红。若敢露脸，就要你死。”

　　语言详解

　　A: Isn’t Lisa your girlfriend?.

　　莉莎不是你的女朋友吗？

　　B: Actually, we broke up. Now I’m dating Jane.

　　其实我们分手了。我现在跟阿珍在约会。

　　【He’s been here. 他到过这里。】

　　have/has been here隐含“现在已经离开这里”的意思，要是have/has come here即是表示“现在人在这里”。同理have/has been there意味着“已经离开那里”，而have/has gone there说明“尚在那里”。

　　A: Where have you been? I haven’t seen you and Peter for a long time.

　　你这一向在哪里？我很久没有见到你和彼德。

　　B: I have been in Bangkok for a while, and Peter has gone to the U.S.

　　我曾一度到曼谷，彼德去了美国。

　　1) end up 落得……的下场

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="4c1bf0942ea5497c8bfbd0eb7f62ae55">
<name>Lesson 23:你才不要分心 </name>
<content>SCENE④ B 吉娜和戴夫在隔间里

　　【我才不要分心】

　　Dave: Do you think maybe it would be better to just talk to Vince? Explain the situation?

　　戴夫： 你觉得去跟文斯说会不会好一点？解释这整个情况？

　　Zina: No way. I want the satisfaction of 1) squishing this bug myself. Plus, what if it’s Vince?

　　吉娜： 门都没有。我要自己享受压扁这只虫子的满足感。而且若文斯就是那小子怎么办？

　　Dave: I don’t think so. Your admirer seems kind of sweet. Aren’t you even a little 2) curious about him?

　　戴夫： 不会吧。你那仰慕者似乎还蛮贴心的。难道你对他一点都不好奇？

　　Zina: He’s just a 3) distraction, like a mosquito buzzing in my ear. I want no distractions.

　　吉娜： 他只会让人分心，就像耳边蚊子嗡嗡叫。我才不要分心。

　　Dave: A little distraction might 4) do you some good, Zina.

　　戴夫： 稍微分点心或许对你有好处，吉娜。

　　语言详解

　　A: Our two-year-old baby is always getting into trouble.

　　我们家那个两岁的小鬼老是出状况。

　　B: Two is the age when they start to get curious.

　　孩子就是从两岁会开始好奇。

　　【a little curious 一点儿好奇】

　　a little 意思是“不多，但仍有一点”，如果是little，意思是“很少”，隐含否定之意。

　　A: There’s still a little time. We can have another drink.

　　还有一点时间，我们可以再来一杯。

　　B: But there is little money with us.

　　但是我们没有什么钱了。

　　A: I think they would accept my credit card.

　　我想他们会接受我的信用卡。

　　1）quish (v.) 挤扁，压扁

　　2) curious (a.) 感到好奇的

　　3) distraction (n.) 分心

　　4) do someone good 对某人有好处

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="17b5a97185f2474ba6d900a8cc228bb2">
<name>Lesson 24:我们会熬过去的 </name>
<content>SCENE④ C 吉娜和戴夫在隔间里

　　【我们会熬过去的】

　　Zina: Talk about distractions. Vince wants to see us all again this afternoon.

　　吉娜： 说到分心。文斯今天下午又要召见大家了。

　　Dave: Another 1) pep talk? That’ll make three this week.

　　戴夫： 又要来精神讲话吗？那就会是这个星期的第三次了。

　　Zina: He’s worried that our team is going to 2) tire out and that WebTracker is going to beat us.

　　吉娜： 他担心我们团队会气力放尽，而“网路搜寻家”会打败我们。

　　Dave: I don’t 3) blame him. People are starting to 4) grumble about working 5) twenty-four seven.

　　戴夫： 我不怪他。大家都在抱怨日夜无休地上班。

　　Zina: They need to suck it up. We’re going to pull this off. I’ll make sure of that.

　　吉娜： 他们得要含辛茹苦。我们会熬过去的。我一定会确保战果。

　　语言详解

　　A: You always blame me for everything!

　　你总把每件事都怪在我头上！

　　B: That’s because it’s your fault!

　　因为那是你的错！

　　【That’ll make three times this week. 那就会是这星期的第三次了。】

　　make在这里的意思是“加总起来”，可以用来表达沮丧或是失望的负面情绪：

　　A: The computer has crashed again.

　　电脑又死机了。

　　B: That makes the fifth time tonight.

　　这是今晚第五次了。

　　【pull something off 完成难题】

　　pull something off 可以用来表示“完成一份艰难的工作”。

　　A: This project has to be finished next week.

　　这个企划案在下星期之前得要完成。

　　B: If we pull this off, we’ll all get promotions.

　　若我们闯过这一关，我们就升官了。

　　1) pep talk 精神讲话。用以提振士气，凝聚共识的谈话。

　　2) tire out 精疲力竭

　　3) blame (v.) 责怪

　　4) grumble (v.) 抱怨

　　5) twenty-four seven 意指“一周七天，一天二十四小时”。

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="dfa219b8ae774d63af316d8c2579c5f0">
<name>Lesson 25:这是难关,对吧 </name>
<content>SCENE⑤ A 会议结束后

　　【这是难关，对吧？】

　　Dave: It’s 1) crunch time, isn’t it? I wasn’t 2) nervous before the meeting, but now I am.

　　戴夫： 这是难关，对吧？ 我开会前还不紧张的，但现在我紧张了。

　　Elvin: No kidding. Time is running out.

　　艾文： 一点不假。时间越来越紧迫了。

　　Dave: It would help to bring in a couple more 3) troubleshooters.

　　戴夫： 若是再找几个难题顾问来解决问题，可能会有帮助。

　　Elvin: Vince says he can’t 4) afford anybody else. We’re got to 5) come through.

　　艾文： 文斯说他请不起人了。我们得要自己撑过。

　　Dave: Do you think we’ll make it?

　　戴夫： 你觉得我们会成功吗？

　　Elvin: I guess we’ll either make it, or we won’t.

　　艾文： 我猜我们要么就搞定，否则就完蛋了。

　　语言详解

　　A: Dad! I love that car.

　　爸！我好爱那辆车。

　　B: Me too. But we can’t afford it.

　　我也是。不过我们买不起。

　　【Time is running out. 时间越来越紧迫了。】

　　run out 表示“耗尽、到期、届满”，而 run out of 是“将……用光、缺乏”，前者不能接名词，而后者一定接名词或动名词。

　　A: We’d better hurry. Time is running out.

　　我们最好快一点。时间快到了。

　　B: But we have to find a gas station first. We are running out of gas.

　　但是我们必须先找个加油站。汽油快用光了。

　　A: Why didn’t we use the other car?

　　为什么我们没有用另外那部车子呢？

　　1) crunch time (n.) （俚）关键时刻，危机困境。

　　2) nervous (a.) 感到紧张的

　　3) troubleshooter (n.) 解决麻烦问题的能手。

　　4) afford (v.) 负担得起

　　5) come through 度过难关

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="481c71472e2c4cb38500e04286078518">
<name>Lesson 26:她还真像个女超人 </name>
<content>SCENE⑤ B 会议结束后

　　【她还真像个女超人】

　　Dave: Either we’ll be millionaires, or we won’t… won’t have a dime.

　　戴夫： 当不成百万富翁，就当……身无分文。

　　Elvin: And it’s all coming down to the next three weeks.

　　艾文： 接下来的三个星期就会见真相。

　　Dave: The only person who seems confident the software will be done on time is Zina.

　　戴夫： 只有吉娜有信心，软件会准时完成。

　　Elvin: Yeah, she is some kind of Superwoman, isn’t she?

　　艾文： 对啊，她还真像个女超人，你说是不是？

　　Dave: 1) Failure just isn’t an 2) option for her. I’m glad she’s on our team.

　　戴夫： 失败这两个字不在她的字典里。我很高兴她跟我们是同一伙的。

　　语言详解

　　A: Do I have any other options?

　　我有其他选择吗？

　　B: You have to pick them up at six A.M.

　　你得在早上六点的时候来拿。

　　【It’s all coming down to…成败攸关于……】

　　come down to是指情况到了最后成败的关头，短期内就要见真相：

　　A: It’s all coming down to these last two days.

　　成败就看这最后两天了。

　　B: We can do it!

　　我们做得到的！

　　也可以指彼此的关系每况愈下，到达谷底：

　　A: I need more money. Give me some.

　　我还要钱。给我一点。

　　B: Has our relationship just come down to this-money?

　　我们的关系已走到了这样，钱钱钱？

　　你也可以说It came down to the point where…以表示情势的发展已至最后的临界点：

　　A: It came down to the point where I had to make a decision.

　　事已至此，我得做出决定。

　　B: So you decided to quit your job and come here?

　　所以你决定辞职到这里来？

　　1) failure (n.) 失败

　　2) option (n.) 选择

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="4593c585d22c4e7a800e630204b5b3c2">
<name>Lesson 27:她可都是玩真的</name>
<content>SCENE⑤ C 会议结束后

　　【她可都是玩真的】

　　Elvin: I used to 1) be down on the sales people until I saw her 2) in action.

　　艾文： 我以前对业务员都很失望，直到我见识到吉娜的能耐。

　　Dave: She means business, for sure.

　　戴夫： 她可都是玩真的。

　　Elvin: Most salespeople seem like 3) half-brains. Zina’s definitely an 4) exception.

　　艾文： 大部分的业务看起来都没大脑。吉娜绝对是个例外。

　　Dave: We’d better get back to work.

　　戴夫： 我们最好回去工作了。

　　Elvin: Yeah, I’m not too worried about Vince, but I’d hate to face Zina if we don’t 5) deliver…

　　艾文： 是啊，我还不太担心文斯，但若我们搞不定，我可是打死不想面对吉娜……

　　语言详解

　　A: It’s definitely time you got a haircut.

　　你绝对该去剪头发了。

　　B: I know. My hair is always in my eyes.

　　我知道。我的头发老是跑进眼睛。

　　【mean business 玩真的】

　　mean business是表示“当真，玩真的”，没有儿戏的成份在内，一心一意地去达成某件事，未必和“生意”business有关：

　　A: I still can’t believe Mary got into college.

　　我还是不敢相信玛莉考进大学了。

　　B: Well, she meant business this time.

　　呃，她这次是玩真的。

　　mean business也可以表示为了某种目的而来：

　　A: Why are the police outside?

　　警察怎么会在这儿？

　　B: They mean business. Otherwise, they wouldn’t have come here.

　　他们来办事。要不然没事他们不会来的。

　　1) be down on… 对……感到失望，看不起。

　　2) in action 在行动中，在动作中

　　3) half-brain (n.) 只有半个脑，意即“没大脑，白痴”。

　　4) exception (n.) 例外

　　5) deliver (v.) 成功达成交付任务

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="6eb131c516f1499f921b27b315fe8528">
<name>Lesson 28:我能跟你说些私事吗? </name>
<content>SCENE① A 吉娜与玛莉同坐在飞往洛城的班机上

　　【我能跟你说些私事吗？】

　　Mary: Zina, can I talk to you about something 1) personal?

　　玛莉： 吉娜，我能跟你说些私事吗？

　　Zina: As long as it doesn’t take too long.

　　吉娜： 只要不太花时间就可以。

　　Mary: My boyfriend says I work too much. That I spend more time with you than with him.

　　玛莉： 我男朋友说我工作太拼命了。说我跟你相处的时间都比跟他多。

　　Zina: Was he 2) upset when you told him you had to leave this weekend?

　　吉娜： 你跟他说这周末你得去外地时，他有不爽吗？

　　Mary: He said not to 3) bother coming back. And I said, “fine, I won’t.”

　　玛莉： 他说不劳我再回去了。我就说：“好，我就不回来。”

　　Zina: So what’s the problem?

　　吉娜： 那这有什么问题？

　　语言详解

　　A: Don’t bother buying me a present. I hate birthdays.

　　不用费心帮我买礼物了。我讨厌生日。

　　B: Too late. I already bought you one.

　　来不及了。我已经帮你买了。

　　【don’t bother 别费事，不劳】

　　don’t bother后面可以接四种不同的结构：

　　1. -ing: Don’t bother coming back.

　　2. 不定词:Don’t bother to come back.

　　3. yourself + -ing: Don’t bother yourself coming back.

　　4. yorself + 不定词:Don’t bother yourself to come back.

　　以上四句都正确，但以(1)及(2)两句较普遍。

　　A: When is your plane tomorrow? I would like to see you off at the airport.

　　你明天班机是几时？我想要到机场给你送行。

　　B: Thanks. But don’t bother to come to the airport.

　　谢了。但请不要麻烦跑一趟机场。

　　1) ersonal (a.) 私人的

　　2) upset (a.) 感到不爽的，生气的

　　3) bother (v.) 费心，麻烦

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="4889c77c2bf541c0922c99b50da277a1">
<name>Lesson 29:我猜我只是有点紧张 </name>
<content>SCENE① B 吉娜与玛莉同坐在飞往洛城的班机上

　　【我猜我只是有点紧张】

　　Mary: I guess I’m just a little nervous. I’m giving everything I have to InfoKing, and…

　　玛莉： 我猜我只是有点紧张。 我把所有都给了“资讯王”，而且……

　　Zina: …and what if it doesn’t 1) work out, right?

　　吉娜： ……而且要是行不通怎么办，对不对？

　　Mary: 2) Exactly.

　　玛莉： 完全正确。

　　Zina: You need to 3) quit thinking like a loser. InfoKing is going to 4) kick butt. You know how I know?

　　吉娜： 你别那么没志气了。“资讯王”会所向披靡的。你知道我怎么知道吗？

　　Mary: How?

　　玛莉： 怎么知道？

　　Zina: Because I won’t let it fail.

　　吉娜： 因为我不会让它失败。

　　Mary: But what about tomorrow? What if Stars.com decides to go with WebTracker, and not us?

　　玛莉： 可是明天呢？要是Stars.com决定跟“网路搜寻家”走，而非我们？

　　语言详解

　　A: You’re saying that you didn’t steal the loaf of bread?

　　你是说那条面包不是你偷的？

　　B: That’s exactly right. I’m an honest man.

　　完全正确。我是个诚实的人。

　　【quit thinking 停止……想法】

　　quit跟stop一样，后面跟着-ing 表示 “停止某种动作”，后面跟着不定词时意思是 “停下来做某项动作”，例如：quit smoking“戒烟”，stop to smoke“停下来抽烟”。

　　A: We have been running for an hour. Let’s stop to take a rest.

　　我们已经跑了一个钟头了。让我们停下来休息。

　　B: But be sure you don’t smoke.

　　但是你可不能抽烟。

　　A: I promised you to quit smoking, I honor my word.

　　我答应过你要戒烟。我遵守诺言。

　　1) work out 行得通

　　2) exactly (adv.) 的确，正是

　　3) quit (v.) 停止

　　4) kick butt (俚) 踢屁股，意即“大胜，击溃”

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean><TextBean UUID="30ed50a99acf42fbaafd1deddc31a11e">
<name>Lesson 30:你的便利贴是什么颜色? </name>
<content>SCENE① C 吉娜与玛莉同坐在飞往洛城的班机上

　　【你的便利贴是什么颜色？】

　　Zina: We’re going to blow WebTracker out of the water. Trust me.

　　吉娜： 我们会让“网路搜寻家”出局的。相信我。

　　Mary: I believe you, Zina.

　　玛莉： 我相信你，吉娜。

　　Zina: Mary, can I ask you something? What color are your post-it notes?

　　吉娜： 玛莉，我能问你个问题吗？你的便利贴是什么颜色？

　　Mary: My post-it notes? Pink, I think. Why?

　　玛莉： 我的便利贴？我想是粉红的吧，怎么？

　　Zina: Are you sure they aren’t green? It’s OK if they are. Just be 1) honest.

　　吉娜： 你确定不是绿色？是也无妨。老实说就好。

　　Mary: I’m pretty sure they’re pink. Did I do something wrong?

　　玛莉： 我很确定是粉红色的。我做错了什么吗？

　　Zina: No. Pink is OK. Stick with pink.

　　吉娜： 没有。粉红很好。不要换。

　　语言详解

　　A: Why is he so upset?

　　他怎么那么难过？

　　B: I told him he’s getting fat. I was just being honest.

　　我跟他说他变胖了。我只是说实话而已。

　　【blow…out of the water 击溃……】

　　blow…out of the water是指“把……打得落花流水”，意即让对方溃不成军：

　　A: How was the basketball game last night?

　　昨晚的篮球赛如何？

　　B: The Lakers blew the Pistons out of the water.

　　湖人队把活塞队打得溃不成军。

　　【stick with… 坚持……】

　　stick with something 是指“坚持（某事）”，也就是不轻言放弃，不轻易更换：

　　A: What’s the best way to learn English?

　　学英文最好的方法是什么？

　　B: Stick with the basics until you know them really well.

　　坚守住基本原理，直到你了然于心。

　　1) honest (a.) 诚实的

</content>
<bookmark>0</bookmark>
</TextBean></TextList>